[♪]
[BLOWING]
[SIGHS]
- MOM: I'm just gonna go tell her.
- MILLS: No. No, I...
I wanna tell her myself.
MOM:
She knows what it's like
for you to be away.
You've led
explorations before.
Not for this long.
Six weeks at most.
She's a resilient kid.
- But this isn't supply transport.
- She'll be fine.
Or a jump to Cyllene and back.
- It's a two-year run.
- I know. I know how long.
Just go.[LAUGHING] It's hard.
MILLS:
I'll go. I'm just thinking
about what to say.
Say they're tripling
your salary,
which is how we can afford
to treat her.
To cure her.[COUGHING]
You okay?
[EXHALES]
I'm fine.
It's two years...
I won't be here.
I know, but when you get back,
she will.
Dad! I can't do it.
[COUGHING, CLEARS THROAT]
You okay?
Yeah, yeah.
Are you sure?
Dad, I just want you
to help me with this.
Here. Don't blow so hard.
- Just easy. A little gentle.
- I think my thumbs are too small.
Your thumbs are perfect.
You're just blowing too hard.
Here, watch me. Watch me.
[WHISTLES THROUGH HANDS]
Why are you so good
at everything?
- You make it look so easy.
- It is easy.
You just have to know
how to do it.
- Don't blow in, blow down.
- Okay.
[WHISTLING]
[BLOWING]
This is you.
[SPITTING][LAUGHING]
It isn't.
- Just blow a little gently.
- Okay.
Don't get frustrated.
Try again.
[WHISTLING SOFTLY]
[BOTH LAUGHING]
- It's okay. I know.
- What do you know?
I know that you're leaving.
And I know it's 'cause of me.
No, it's not because of you,
it's for you.
So how long
will you be gone this time?
[♪]
COMPUTER:
Zoic Exploratory Charter 3703.
Unexpected meteor activity detected.
Running risk assessment.
Checking passenger vitals.
Cryostasis, normal.
[BOOMING THUD]
[ALARM SOUNDING]
Warning.
Unexpected meteor activity.
Manual override required.
[GRUNTS]
[♪]
COMPUTER:
Emergency landing.
Cryochamber compromised.
Emergency transpondence,
this is Charter 3703!
Our ship has been hit
and is going down!
NEVINE:
Are you scared?
COMPUTER [MUFFLED]:
Trajectory off-course.
Location unknown.
[CLEARLY]
Trajectory off-course.
[ALARM SOUNDING]
[METALLIC CREAKING, GROANING]
[WINCES SOFTLY]
[GRUNTS]
[BREATHING HEAVILY]
[CRIES OUT]
COMPUTER:
Cryogenic failure.
[THUD]
[WEAPON POWERING UP]
[GRUNTING]
[♪]
[WHIRRING]
COMPUTER:
Accessing emergency landing database.
Flight path trajectory interrupted.
Current location unknown.
MILLS:
This is theZoic Charter 3703.
If anyone receives this,
I'm the only survivor
of a long-range
exploratory mission.
My ship was struck
by an undocumented
asteroid belt.
I believe the debris
to be a small cluster
from a much larger
asteroid system.
But I can't be sure.
We've crash-landed
on an uncharted celestial body.
My ship
has been severed in half.
Confirmed nine escape pods
have been destroyed
and two are missing.
The atmosphere is breathable.
[COUGHING, GASPING]
All passengers are dead.
[♪]
Send help.
COMPUTER: Deleted. This is Charter 3703,
long-range exploratory mission.
Asteroid debris field
hit my ship.
All passengers are dead.
No reason for recovery.
COMPUTER:
Message sent.
Three...
two...
one.
[GASPS, SIGHS]
COMPUTER:
Accessing archive.
NEVINE [ON MONITOR]:
Remember when we went
to the beach a while ago?
And do you remember how,
like--?
Just cold it was?
What does it feel like
out there?
[BEEPING]
[THUNDER BOOMING]
[CHITTERING NEARBY]
[♪]
[POD BEEPING]
[TONE SOUNDING]
[GRUNTING]
[PANTING]
[♪]
[ROARING IN DISTANCE]
[SNARLING NEARBY]
[♪]
Where are you?
[CRUNCHING UNDERFOOT]
[♪]
COMPUTER:
Scanning for escape vessel location.
Location unknown.
Where are you?
[GURGLING]
[CRUNCHING UNDERFOOT]
[STEAM WHISTLING, HISSING]
[♪]
COMPUTER:
Section of the Zoic located.
Distance to escape vessel,
15 kilometers.
[SQUEALING]
[GRUNTING]
[SQUEALS]
[PANTING]
[CHUCKLES WEAKLY]
[CLATTERING SOFTLY]
[RUSTLING]
[♪]
MILLS:
Hey! Hey!
Hey!
Stop!
[INSECTS BUZZING]
[ROARING IN DISTANCE]
[HEAVY FOOTSTEPS NEARING]
MILLS:
What's your name?
Your name?
Okay. Let's find out
who you are.
Passenger number 35.
Your name must be Koa.
[STAMMERS]
It's okay.
Here, let's look
at this burn.
Koa, my name is Mills.
I was the pilot of the ship.
I was transporting you home
before we crashed.
And you've been in cryostasis for...
a long time.
The navigation system
is gone.
I don't know where we are.
It's uncharted.
There is an escape vessel.
But it's high above
in the mountains.
That's our only chance
to get you off the planet.
[SIGHS]
There's something alien
out there...
that, uh... is dangerous.
You understand me, Koa?
I mean, it's Koa?
[SPEAKS IN FOREIGN LANGUAGE]
What'd you say?
What language is that?
[REPEATS PHRASE]
Well, I can't, um...
I can't translate.
I don't understand.
No, I don't understand.
I can't translate it.
My translator's broken.
Like everything else
on this damn ship.
What is that, Kuu'ri?
Pris'ka?
Mountain.
Um... We--
We must climb all the way
to the top of the mountain.
That's where the other half
of our ship is.
Ship. Mountain?
Do you understand mountain?
Escape vessel.
Here's an escape vessel.
That's where we...
[IMITATES WHOOSHING]
Over here.
That's how you leave.
That's how you get home.[IN ENGLISH] Home.
What?
- Home.
- Yes.
[♪]
Home.
[REPEATS PHRASE
IN FOREIGN LANGUAGE]
What is it, your parents?
Family?
[IN ENGLISH]
Family.
On the top of the mountain.
[CHUCKLES]
That's what I'm trying
to tell you.
They're on top of the mountain.
- Family.
- Yeah.
They're here.
Charter 3703.
The daughter of the Ona family
is alive.
A child, maybe 9 years old
and in good health.
Her name is Koa,
from the upper territories,
so we are unable
to communicate.
Her parents were passengers.
Both deceased.
I'm taking her
to an escape vessel
I've located
some distance away.
Send help.
COMPUTER:
Sending distress signal.
Yeah, that's a ship.
Just like the one
you're driving for work.
[IMITATES WHOOSHING]
Blast off!
I made it. Can you believe it?
School's been pretty fun.
I've been getting good grades,
and everything's
been going well.
I miss seeing you
'cause I love you.
Hello. We have gotten
some amazing news.
It's made me very happy
'cause you have made it halfway.
Here is your halfway celebration.
I'm very proud on you--
Proud of you.
For making it halfway.
[COUGHING]
[RECORDING WHIRRING]
I think Mom told you,
but there's just a little
minor problem going on
with me, so...
But it's actually
really fun here
and I've met some nice people.
And they remind me of you
because you are
my greatest friend,
and, uh...
Hurry back, please.
Speed it up.
[CRYING]
I really hate you right now.
You don't even care about me.
Just want you to know I, um...
I love you.
I'm so tired, Dad.
I'm tired.
I'm try--
All right, let's go.
Let's go.
[♪]
MILLS:
Stay with me.
We need to be quiet
and move to the mountain.
Quiet.
And move.
Move.
[♪]
[HONKING]
[SCREECHES]
Keep moving.
[ROARING IN DISTANCE]
COMPUTER:
Distance to escape vessel,
12 kilometers.
MILLS:
Here, take my hand.
[GROANS]
You okay?
[SPEAKING IN FOREIGN LANGUAGE]
All right, let's go.
[♪]
[KOA SPEAKING
IN FOREIGN LANGUAGE]
[♪]
[WHIRS, BEEPS]
Don't eat.
In your mouth
down to your stomach.
[GROWLING]
[CHIRRING]
Shit.
[LAUGHS]
[GASPS]
[CHITTERING]
[SPEAKING IN FOREIGN LANGUAGE]
Hey!
[CREATURE GROANING]
No, no, no.
No. Hey! Hey!
Koa.
[KOA GRUNTING]
Leave it. Leave it!
[♪]
[SIGHS]
Shit.
[SCREECHING]
[SQUEALING]
[SCREAMS]
[SOBBING]
[CHITTERING]
[SQUEALS LOUDLY]
[♪]
[SIGHS]
[CRYING SOFTLY]
You have to listen to me.
You're gonna
get yourself killed.
[♪]
I'm tired!
I'm just tired!
I'm just tired.
No. I'm...
I'm saying I'm just tired.
I'm just tired.
Want some water?
Water. It's okay.
Well, fill it up.
Fill it with water.
- Water.
Here, go to the other side
where it's flat.
Water.
[♪]
It's a flower.
Flower.
Yeah.
No, that's okay.
Flower.
[♪]
COMPUTER:
Signal disruption.
Destination lost.
Scanning.
"Don't eat."
[BRANCH CRACKS]
[♪]
[WHIRRING, BEEPING]
[GASPS, GROANING]
No, no! No, no!
[CHITTERING]
[SNARLING]
Give me your foot.
Push. Push.
[GROANS]
[SCREAMS]
[ROARS]
Run.
[♪]
[PANTING]
[PULSING GUNSHOTS CONTINUE]
[CHITTERING]
[SNARLING]
[WHIMPERS]
[SCREAMS]
[PANTING]
[ROARS][SCREAMS]
[SCREAMING]
[♪]
It's okay.
Are you hurt?
You all right?
[CRYING]
Koa, we gotta go.
Move.
All right.
We'll wait.
[WHISTLES]
[♪]
Move?
Move.
[SPEAKING
IN FOREIGN LANGUAGE]
[♪]
[GROANING]
All right, we're safe now.
You can sleep.
Sleep.
[IN ENGLISH]
Home.
[WHIRRING]
MILLS:
Home is out there.
COMPUTER:
Irregularity detected.
[BEEPING]
Scanning to identify.
Unable to identify irregularity
at this time.
Could be more
of the asteroid shower.
What are you doing?
Why'd you take this?
Go to sleep.
NEVINE:
And then I'll stick it...
here...
So now it kind of
looks like it's--
The wire makes it
look pretty nice.
But I'm just gonna add
this touch of red also.
[♪]
MOM:
She loved you so much.
She didn't suffer, she just...
She just slipped away.
[PULSING]
[ALARM SOUNDING]
[CHITTERING]
Koa. Koa.
Koa!
[GASPS]
[VOMITING]
[COUGHING]
[SPITS]
[ALARM BLARING]
[SNARLING]
[THUNDER BOOMING]
[♪]
[ROARS]
[SCREAMS]
[ROARING]
[THUDDING FOOTSTEPS OVERHEAD]
You okay?
COMPUTER:
Scanning for alternate path.
Directional air current detected.
[CHITTERING]
[GRUNTING]
[WIND WHISTLING]
[HAMMERING]
Family.
Yeah, that's where
we're headed.
To see your family.
[SPEAKING
IN FOREIGN LANGUAGE]
No, it's not enough.
[IN ENGLISH]
Mountain.
Move? Move! Koa.
I can't move a mountain.
[SHOUTS
IN FOREIGN LANGUAGE]
Look, I can't.
It's blocked.
I can't go any further.
I can't get past this rock.
That's it.
[IN ENGLISH]
Mountain!
[SPEAKING IN FOREIGN LANGUAGE]
[IN ENGLISH]
Koa. Koa. Mountain.
Move. Koa,
mountain, move!
Move!
[SPEAKING
IN FOREIGN LANGUAGE]
There's no one
on that mountain.
I lied to you, and I'm sorry.
They're gone.
[SPEAKS
IN FOREIGN LANGUAGE]
And you don't understand me.
No, I'm sorry.
I can't go any further.
I don't have
any more tools!
[♪]
[EXPLOSION]
You all right?
Just in case.
[COUGHING]
[RUMBLING]
Stay.
[GRUNTING]
[KOA SHOUTING
IN FOREIGN LANGUAGE]
[GROANS]
[PANTING]
No!
No. No!
God!
Koa, no!
Koa!
[WHISTLING IN DISTANCE]
[♪]
[SCREECHES]
[WEAPON POWERING UP]
[SNARLING]
COMPUTER:
Proximity scan initiated.
[COMPUTER PULSING]
[SNARLING]
[SCREECHES]
Get off me!
[BEEPS]
[COMPUTER EMITTING
HIGH-PITCHED TONE]
[CREATURE CALLING IN DISTANCE]
[♪]
COMPUTER:
Scanning irregularity.
Catastrophic asteroid detected.
Assessing proximity risk.
Collision imminent.
[♪]
Koa.
Koa!
[GASPS]
[SCREECHES][SCREAMING]
[♪]
Koa!
[CHITTERS]
[SCREAMS]
MILLS [IN DISTANCE]:
Koa!
Oh, God.
[BREATHING SHALLOWLY]
[GRUNTS]
[GASPS]
[COUGHING]
[♪]
Thank you.
The asteroid that hit our ship?
COMPUTER:
Updating trajectory.
There. Asteroid impact: 12 hours.
It was just a small part
of a much bigger one. See this?
This?
It's coming here.
[RUMBLING]
[GRUNTS]
[♪]
Koa.
Okay.
Tie it around something safe.
Right here.
[ROARING IN DISTANCE]
Koa!
Ko--
Good job.
[♪]
[SPEAKING IN FOREIGN LANGUAGE]
[GRUNTS]
[POWERING UP]
COMPUTER:
Distress signal received.
Interception point
coordinates: 012016.
The rescue vessel's coming.
The vessel's coming.
Life support is working.
Navigational system's good.
If this is working, which it...
I think may--
[SPEAKS IN FOREIGN LANGUAGE]
[EXHALES SHARPLY]
Koa.
[IN ENGLISH]
Family.
[WHIMPERING]
Family!
I'm sorry.
Family! Family!
[SHOUTING IN FOREIGN LANGUAGE]
[IN ENGLISH]
No. No.
[SOBBING]
[BOOMING IN DISTANCE]
[SPEAKS IN FOREIGN LANGUAGE]
Koa.
[MILLS SPEAKS
IN FOREIGN LANGUAGE]
[IN ENGLISH]
This is my daughter.
You understand?
The last time I saw her,
she was mad at me.
Because my job
took me away from her.
And when I was gone,
she got very sick.
She died
and I wasn't there for her.
I need to get you home.
Koa?
I'm sorry.
[SNIFFLING]
[CRACKLING IN DISTANCE]
[♪]
Ready?
Okay, checking
launch sequence.
- That's the launch button.
- Launch.
[WHIMPERING]
[♪]
[GASPING]
[GRUNTING]
Mills.
COMPUTER:
Launch sequence failure.
Vessel orientation inoperable.
[ALARM BLARING]
[ASTEROIDS BOOMING]
[PANTING]
[SNARLING]
[ROARING]
[SCREAMING]
[GRUNTS]
[ROARING]
[GROANS]
[♪]
[BEEPS]
Shit.
[ROARING]
Shit, shit, shit.
[BUTTONS BEEPING]
[ROARS]
[GRUNTING]
NEVINE:
It just took me some time.
I was able to get it right.
[NEVINE WHISTLING
THROUGH HANDS]
[LAUGHS]
I got it.
How's it sound?
[SNARLING]
[♪]
NEVINE:
I love you.
[NEVINE WHISTLING
THROUGH HANDS]
[ROARING]
[KOA SCREAMING]
COMPUTER:
Vessel orientation restored.
Repair cycle initiated.
[♪]
[SNARLING]
Launch the ship!
[SCREAMS]
[GROANS]
God!
[ROARING]
[SNARLING]
[SCREAMING]
[SQUEALING]
[♪]
COMPUTER:
Impact imminent.
[♪]
COMPUTER:
Interception point
coordinates: 012016.
[♪]
[INHALES DEEPLY]