[tranquil music]
LIBYA
SABHA DISTRICT
[indistinct chatter]
[thunder rumbling]
[man speaking Arabic]
[indistinct shouting in distance]
[objects clanking]
[man speaking Arabic]
[indistinct chatter]
[speaking Arabic]
[groans, pants]
[men speaking Arabic]
[chatter fading]
[grunts]
[breathes heavily]
[clanking]
[breathing shakily]
[grunts]
[sighs]
Sonia?
Sonia Gautier?
[muffled groan]
[shushes]
Stay still and you'll be home soon.
[distant chatter]
[man speaking Arabic]
[lighter clanks]
[continues speaking Arabic]
[Adam grunts]
[background chatter]
[man speaking Arabic]
[groans]
- [man shouting in Arabic]
- [gunshots]
[man 1 shouts]
[man 2 shouting in Arabic]
[man 2 speaking Arabic]
- [men groan]
- [bullets clank]
- [clamoring in distance]
- [alarm blaring]
[man shouting]
[explosion]
[gunshot]
[men yelling]
- [gunfire in distance]
- [men yelling]
[grunting]
- [distant shouting]
- [gunfire in distance]
- [Adam mutters]
- [Sonia sobs]
[distant chatter]
[explosion]
- [gunshot]
- [man speaking Arabic]
- [man shouting]
- [gunshots]
[man speaking Arabic]
[man 1] Drop gun! Or she dead!
- [gunshot]
- [groans]
[Sonia whimpering]
Oh, my god. Thank you.
[breathing heavily]
- [gunshot]
- [body thuds]
[panting]
[soft dramatic music]
[cell phone buzzing]
[soft groan]
- [Marconnet] Yes?
- [Kruger] Mr. Secretary, this is Kruger.
You should turn on the television.
I'll be there in ten minutes.
[Marconnet sighs]
[reporter 1] What we know is the explosion
took place around 11 p.m.,
in a room at the Star Hotel,
in the heart of the 8th arrondissement.
According to initial reports,
the explosion seems to be linked
to an intervention by RAID forces
who are attempting to neutralize
a terrorist cell on the verge
- of committing an attack.
- He's upstairs.
[reporter 1] Investigators have yet
to confirm whether the explosion occurred
before or during the assault,
but there are reports
of multiple casualties.
Earlier, we saw first responders
removing victims from the scene.
[reporter 2] Matthieu, we will come back
to you at the scene in just a few moments,
as we've just received the first statement
from the Ministry of the Interior.
He includes this picture
of the presumed orchestrator
of the attack, Moktar Al Tayeb.
If you see this individual,
you are encouraged
to report the information.
However, beware, he is armed
and extremely dangerous.
[Kruger] You need to run
a different picture.
Yes, exactly.
Less focus, less friendly.
[Marconnet] Of course,
we'll take care of this immediately.
[reporter 2] He has close ties
to Islamist movement.
[Marconnet] I should have told you sooner.
I apologize once again, Mr. President.
[TV chatter continues]
What the hell happened?
- [reporter 2] Thank you, Hervé.
- He wasn't alone.
[reporter 2] Three of Al Tayeb's
accomplices died in the assault.
His wife, Imane Al Tayeb, is one of them.
[Marconnet] Isn't information your job?
[Marconnet sighs]
Do you realize the situation
you've put me in?
No one knew he was in the country.
I'll have every department on my ass.
You need to find him and fast.
He's in contact with Victor.
- Pastore?
- Mm-hm.
[scoffs]
They'll call or see each other.
I can have someone in place
when it happens.
Hold on.
[inhales deeply]
I tell you act fast,
and you propose
we infiltrate Victor Pastore's mob?
We're not talking about
some small time player.
[Marconnet breathes deeply]
Narcotics tried it three years ago.
Took them months,
and they lost a guy doing it.
I have my resources.
I'll have my guy in there in no time.
You remember that kid Adam Franco?
He's been working for us for 20 years.
[sighs]
All right.
I need my sleep.
[cell phone beeps]
[line rings]
ATTACK AT THE STAR HOTEL
[Kruger] It's me. Bring him in.
[tense music]
TUNISIA
SFAX
- [overlapping chatter]
- [bell clinks]
[reporter 3] All police forces
from Île-de-France have been mobilized
to track down the presumed mastermind
of the attack.
The head of the National Police Forces
declared a state of emergency
in the capital
to facilitate search for the suspect.
And finally, we turn towards Libya,
we are still without word
concerning our colleague, Sonia Gautier.
International correspondent
and whistleblower.
She was taken hostage several weeks ago.
by an armed militia
in the upper Fezzan region.
The terrorists demanded
the liberation of 15 of their members
detained by French government,
and negotiations were about to be settled
before coming to an abrupt halt
several days ago.
Ms. Gautier, as you may recall,
is scheduled to speak
to the UN a month from now,
with regards to her investigation
on the Western states' interference
in that area of the world.
[dog whines, barks]
SOLEIL1990 JUST LOGGED IN
SOLEIL1990 CREATED
A GAME CHAT WITH YOU
[dog barks]
[dog whining]
JOIN
[game console thuds]
[Soleil] Hey, buddy, what's up?
Not much, you?
[Soleil] So, you're online,
but I can't talk, too busy.
Tomorrow, after I get off work,
you're free? Around four?
Yeah, sure.
You know what? Let's meet at my place.
It's more relaxed.
At your house?
[Soleil] Yeah.
- Okay, I'll be there.
- [dog whines]
SURNAME: HAMON
[lock clicking]
[kids shouting in distance]
[doorbell rings]
Mochaccino with cream
and chocolate shavings.
- [door closes]
- Thought you gave up caffeine?
[Kruger scoffs]
I made herbal tea. You'll like it.
You heard about the Star Hotel?
[Adam] A little. Who's the guy?
Moktar Al Tayeb, a Sudanese warlord.
He was a longtime French ally
until he switched allegiance
about ten years ago.
- He's become radicalized.
- [thuds]
Now, he's in contact
with the Islamic State in Eastern Africa.
We found out he was here.
We busted up one of his operations,
but he got away from us.
We're betting he will strike again soon.
- [siren wailing in distance]
- [spoon clanks]
Since when do you set up
operations in France?
Since when do you ask questions?
[Adam scoffs]
[glass thuds]
Good. You understand
who your next target is.
All the details are in here.
It's not going to be easy.
Moktar knows how to lie low.
We've been in Sudan five years
looking for him, and he's a slippery one.
[Kruger] He has a loyal network
throughout Europe.
He recently contacted
one of his old friends,
Victor Pastore.
[Kruger] They were partners
in a drug ring for 15 years.
They became very close.
Victor is his daughter's godfather.
[Kruger] We know he's helping him hide.
You'll infiltrate Pastore's clan.
I want you to get close to Victor,
get him to trust you.
That's how you'll find Al Tayeb.
Victor has a crew of about ten guys,
not really soldiers.
Except for an Albanian former ops guy,
who ensures security.
He's the one you have to take on
if you want to get noticed.
That's the last guy who tried
to infiltrate his crew. Be careful.
[Kruger] Everything else is in the file.
I just want to point him out.
One of Victor's right-hand men.
He supplies the hired help.
He's your way in.
After that, it's your call.
Do I get backup?
A small surveillance team.
Just Cisko and Mona to cover you.
Same MO we used in Chad.
What's my cover on this one?
There's nothing here.
[chuckles]
This is where it gets interesting.
[soft tense music]
You need a foolproof identity
in order to infiltrate rapidly.
Victor will be playing it safe.
[Kruger] Can you think of a better cover?
Dijon, then jail,
the Legion, a few years in Africa,
and now you've come home.
No need to start it too much.
You know it all by heart.
When you say "infiltrate rapidly"?
Tomorrow.
- Steep it longer next time.
- [glass thuds]
[tense music]
[lock buzzes]
[gate clanks]
You're on time. Good.
All right, come on.
[Jacques] You stay quiet,
do what we tell you.
So, Karim, you missed us, huh?
[Karim] For sure.
- You all right?
- Yeah. You?
[Youssef] I'm good. I'm good.
Nobody mentioned a new guy. Who's this?
Adam. Jacques told me to come by,
just in case.
In case what?
In case I'm short one shit for brains
to take a beating for me?
If it pays well.
[scoffs]
[approaching footsteps]
Gentlemen. Weapons, phones, photo ID.
You fill out this information sheet.
[Youssef] Address,
cell phone number, shoe size,
clothes size, and your blood type.
When it comes to that last one,
don't write anything stupid.
[engine revs in distance]
Karim, you good?
Nothing's changed since winter?
- [Karim] No, all good.
- Glad to hear it.
Writing's not really your things.
[Youssef snickers]
[dog barking in distance]
I'm gonna see Vic.
Come on, this way. You'll meet the team.
[Youssef] All good, Hélène?
Don't you have school?
No, I have a four-hour break,
so I'll just study here.
[Youssef] These are the new guys.
Karim and...
What's your name again?
Adam.
All right, guys, around here,
the rules are simple.
Do what we tell you when we tell you.
You get your paycheck,
and everybody's happy.
[Youssef] Keep in mind,
Victor hates suck-ups.
And watch yourselves,
people have short fuses around here.
[Jonathan] Hey, Uncle Youss! Uncle Youss!
Look what I can do.
- Joe, damn it! You did it again!
- [Jonathan] Did you see?
I'm trying to rest here!
[Natalya] Get out of the pool!
Karim, you remember Manu?
He takes care of making
the neighborhood rounds now.
You'll be with him.
Adam, you'll stay here for the time being.
[hip-hop music playing]
Hey, dickheads, Adam. Adam, the dickheads.
Hey, guys, it's 10 after 2:00.
Time to get your asses in gear, isn't it?
Yep.
[Youssef] JB, you should be on the roof.
Why aren't you?
Oh, no, Youss, today, there's no way.
I threw my back out again last night.
- [JB] I can't.
- [men chuckle]
What? I'm not kidding. I can barely move.
Ask Pee Wee, I can't even tie my shoes.
Manu, take the new guy,
go to the job site.
- Come on, I just washed my jeans.
- [Youssef] I don't wanna hear it.
JB, Karim, you two come with me,
we gotta meet someone in the 13th.
Meet me at the car in 15 minutes.
[Manu] You lazy little bitch.
[JB] No, bro, legit. I can't.
My back really hurts.
- Yeah? So do my balls.
- [chuckles]
[paper rustles]
[Victor] That's really
the best he could do?
[accountant] Yes, sir. That's it.
Forty thousand is a very good offer.
You think so?
[knocks on door]
[objects clanking]
[sniffles]
- Yeah, come in.
- [door opens]
Yeah, Victor, I was hoping
to leave early today,
because I have my son this weekend.
[Jacques] I wanna take him somewhere
for a few days.
This is really bad timing, Jacq.
[Jacques] I know, I know,
but this year's been really tough
with the divorce and all.
It's important for his morale.
I brought in two more guys for you
while I'm gone.
One is Karim, you know him.
And Adam, you'll like him.
Ten years in the Legion,
just home from Africa, he's a beast.
[sighs]
And Youssef, what does he think?
You know Youssef, if you agree, he agrees.
Okay.
Appreciate it.
[accountant] So, the Milord...
[dog barking in distance]
- [car door shuts]
- [engine starts]
[Manu] First, I gotta do the dirty work,
and now this guy gets to take off
in the middle of the day?
I hope he had time to tell you
why you're here.
All he told me was
Victor's worried about his security.
[Bogdan] Hey!
What'd you mean by that?
Why? Did I strike a nerve?
[men chuckle]
[man 2] Oh, here we go.
Don't push it.
[chair rasps]
Yeah.
[approaching footsteps]
Because I'm the one in charge
of his security.
That must be why.
[grunting]
- [dog barking]
- [Manu] Whoa!
What the hell is wrong with you?
Do you want to get killed
on your first day, huh?
- [Victor] Hey!
- [dog whimpers]
[tense music]
Where do you think you are?
- [Adam] I apologize, Mr. Pastore.
- This is my house.
- [Victor grunts]
- [Adam groans]
This isn't the jungle. Understood?
[inhales sharply]
[coughs]
Now, go shake it off.
Come back when you've calmed down.
Sorry, Vic, I was supposed to go
with Bogdan, what do I do now?
Just take him with you instead.
You can get him up to speed on Amet.
And get Bogdan into the house.
[Victor sighs]
You've gotta be shitting me.
[lock clanking]
I did everything you asked me to.
You okay?
[tense music]
- [groans]
- [Jacques' son] Dad!
[hip-hop music playing]
[volume lowers down]
Fill me in on Amet.
He's a pain in the ass from Aulnay.
He thinks he's a big deal,
because he's got Chechen blood
and the big squad.
He overstepped.
He's been playing on our turf
for six months, but Vic's had enough.
Two weeks ago, there was an incident,
and they lit up the neighborhood.
Yeah, I saw a car earlier.
They'll shoot people in the back
and not give a shit.
The bastards are equipped up the ass.
Good to know.
Where are we headed now?
We're going to see the banker.
[doorbell buzzes]
[lock blares]
[banker] Don't touch my cut, okay?
Have him send his guys over.
I don't give a shit.
Right. It's always the same with you.
Yeah, yeah, that's fine. Whatever.
Yeah, you too. Bye.
Pee Wee.
Good to see you. Have a seat.
You want water? Coffee? Herbal tea?
You seem a little tensed.
Mm-mm.
[Pee Wee] Give me the plans,
and we're out of here.
Uh, okay.
There's just been a little delay
with the plans, but no worries.
What delay?
Yesterday, you told me we're good to go.
"Yesterday." But, uh, since then,
something's come up, nothing major.
In five days, I'll have you in
on something even better.
Golden. For the same price, too.
Victor will love it, I'm telling you.
No, no, no, you don't get it.
I came over here
to get the plans for tomorrow.
And I'm leaving here
with the plans for tomorrow.
You're the one who doesn't get it.
There's no more plans.
Yeah? Okay.
[cocks gun]
And now, still no plans?
[banker] Seriously?
You're pulling a gun on me?
What's the problem?
Okay, Pee Wee,
I'll tell you what's the problem.
I owe these guys one fucking huge debt.
I had to give them the scoop.
[exhales deeply]
These things happen.
Your fucking debt is not my problem.
Size matters, wouldn't you say,
asshole, huh?
I'm not leaving without those plans,
I told you.
Then you won't be leaving at all.
[banker] What are you
going to do, huh? Huh?
- [gunshots]
- [stones thud]
- Son of a bitch! You're breaking my arm!
- Where are the plans?
- No, that's the wrist.
- [bone cracks]
[screams]
Bastard! You broke my wrist!
- Where are the plans?
- In there, in the drawer. Let me go!
[banker groaning]
[groaning continues]
They're right here.
So there you go.
- Not so complicated, was it?
- [banker groans]
All you need to do now
is call your buddies,
and tell them in five days, it's all good.
[banker] Yeah, that's what I'll do.
Fuck.
[groans]
FRANCE IN THE SHADOW OF TERRORISM
- They're out of bacon.
- Shit.
[computer trills]
Hm, we got the info on the guy
they went to see this afternoon.
[mouse clicking]
[Mona] Several stints in prison
for fencing, accomplice to robbery,
and organized theft.
He's a small player.
No ties with Moktar or the other cells.
Okay, let's forget him.
[rings]
That's Victor's line.
UNKNOWN NUMBER
INCOMING CALL
[Victor] Hello?
[Moktar] Hello, brother.
[Victor] Hold on.
[loud static]
[keyboard clacks]
[Cisko] Fucking scramblers.
[Victor] Hello?
[Moktar] Hello, brother.
Hello, brother.
- Hello, brother.
- [mouse clicks]
Hello, brother.
RUNNING ANALYSIS
ANALYSIS COMPLETE
It's him.
[Cisko] Franco has to bug Victor's office.
We need to hear everything.
REFERENCE VOCAL SIGNATURE
AL TAYEB
- [woman] Yeah, I know it's tough.
- [phone ringing]
Look, I promised I'll be there.
I told you I was gonna be there.
[man 1] I didn't get everything on time.
- [seller] Here you go.
- [man 2] Thanks.
[seller] Hello.
Sit here.
[mouse clicking]
[keyboard clacking]
[creaks]
[in Arabic]
He's clear.
[tense music]
Hello, my brother.
Hello, Yacine.
I'm sorry for your loss.
We started the process as you told us.
But there's a lot of stuff to transport.
The Egyptian accepted to work with us.
Now, he wants money.
But I vouched for you.
He said he can wait for the payment.
Thank you. You're truly a brother.
No joke, man, you ruptured my eardrum
with that crazy move back there.
[Pee Wee] So, this is Adam.
- Really?
- How are you doing, Michelle?
- I thought you'd be bigger.
- Oh, relax, he's cool.
Bogdan kinda asked for it.
Their stuff is really high quality.
- I'll check it out.
- Sorry, I'm late.
- [Pee Wee] You good, Mimi?
- [Mimi] Yeah, honey, you?
- [Pee Wee] Same.
- [Mini] Great.
You guys have a good night.
- Thanks, you too.
- [Stacy] Hey. Hi, Pee Wee.
[Pee Wee] Hey, Stacy, how's it going?
Camel, can I get two scotch?
- [woman 1] Come on, girls. Get moving.
- [women laughing]
- [woman 2] Twenty minutes.
- Could you help me with my costume?
Bottom's up to your special skills.
[laughs]
[woman 2] Come on. Let's go, please!
Again.
[breathes deeply]
[clicks tongue]
It's good vibe, huh?
[Pee Wee] Tonight, we relax
and have a good time.
[upbeat music playing]
Hey, forget about Victor earlier.
He's a little stressed out these days.
He can't help it.
Because of Amet or something else?
Amet's not helping,
but there's other stuff.
[JB] Hey, Pee Wee! What's up?
- Hey, man, it's good to see you. Yeah.
- All good?
[woman 3] ...for Stacy, who'll be back
on the pole in half an hour.
[crowd cheering]
[Natalya] Sara, I need you to entertain
some real customers.
If you don't mind.
- Everything okay, gentlemen?
- Perfect.
[slow music playing]
Sorry, darling, you need
to get yourself ready.
Your dick goes anywhere but there.
Private property. Not one finger on her.
I'll get us another one.
[people chattering, laughing]
[retches]
[coughs, clears throat]
[flushes]
[laughter]
- [man 1] I'm telling you...
- [man 2] Hello, ladies.
- [man 3] Yeah!
- [overlapping chatter]
Can't let you in tonight, guys.
You serious?
We're not here to stir shit up.
We just wanna fuck the pretty girls.
You're done. Victor doesn't want you here.
What do you want? If it's a tip, say so.
- Huh?
- [men snickering]
- Hey, hey, leave the girls alone.
- Hey, I was talking to you.
- Get lost, I said.
- We're gonna kick your ass!
- Get off!
- [woman 4] Hey!
[Pee Wee] Carlala!
Hey, Amet's guys are beating
the shit out of Sofiane.
Come on, Pee Wee, move!
MILORD
[men grunting]
[slow music playing]
[brake squeaks]
Thanks for protecting us.
It's my job.
[breathes deeply]
It's just a scratch. I'm fine.
I really need you
to take Jonathan to school.
Normally, it's Sofiane who takes him
when his shift is done.
- Okay.
- Do you have a car?
Yeah, it's just out front.
You're an angel. Take this.
Keep the pressure on.
[Hélène] There are white muscles,
which are smooth,
and there are red muscles,
which are striated.
Red muscles are types of muscles
that depend on the, uh...
- Central...
- Central nervous system.
And the white muscles depend
on the autonomic nervous system.
- The autonomic nervous system controls...
- I got the files you wanted.
[Hélène] Oh, for Christ's sake.
Oh, and there was a shit show
outside the Milord.
Oh, yeah?
[Youssef] Soso took a beating
from some of Amet's guys.
Janusz and his gang. He's at the hospital.
He fell and cracked his skull pretty good,
broke a few teeth and fractured his jaw.
I suppose this is after he told them
they're not welcome.
[Victor] We need to put them
in their place.
[Youssef] If you want.
But the guys took care of it already.
Don't worry.
[Victor] Took care of it, how?
The new guy, Adam.
He demolished them.
I haven't seen the footage,
but apparently,
the guy can hit like Tyson Fury.
[door closes]
Ooh!
[loud footsteps]
[Natalya] What do you want me
to do about it?
His guys were spending money on my girls
long before you got
into this pissing contest!
[Victor] Pissing contest?
They shot at us last month.
[Natalya] They weren't involved in that.
[Victor] It's the same guys,
in the same gang. They work for Amet.
I don't wanna see a single one
of those assholes on my property.
- Do you hear me?
- [Natalya] But Janusz and his guys,
they don't give a shit
about your stupid games!
But what I give a shit about
is they spend five grand a night!
[Victor] Five thousand is what's
gonna cost to fix Sofiane's teeth!
You always say business comes first.
[Natalya] And now you're telling your guys
to refuse clients behind my back, too?
Stop thinking with your goddamn balls
and start using your brain!
Do I need to tell you
how much you need cash now?
Hey, don't you start with that!
What do you want, boy?
You're almost eight, Jonathan.
You're too old for kisses now.
Go on.
- [Victor] Did you test the new guy?
- [Natalya] Yes.
Come here, sweetheart. Don't be sad.
- And?
- Sofiane doesn't feel good today.
So you'll go to school with someone new.
His name's Adam, he's very nice.
- And?
- He knows how to behave!
[Natalya] I'm exhausted. I'm going to bed.
- [Victor] I'm not finished.
- [Natalya] Well, I am!
[Victor] Watch your tone
when you're talking to me!
[Natalya] You can pretend
you're Escobar all you want,
but I'm not your bitch.
Without my girls, you have zero cash flow.
[birds chirping]
[gloomy music]
I think you need boxing lessons.
[Adam sighs]
Let's go.
My sister said it's only losers
who'd get in fights.
But I don't totally agree.
There's a few kids at school
who would shut up if I knew how to fight.
Sure.
Anyway, are you coming
to my birthday tomorrow?
[Jonathan] Everyone's coming over.
It's gonna be super fun!
You can even play Wii with us
if you want, Wii is my favorite.
- I like PS4.
- [engine starts]
Yeah, but you can't play Mario
on PS4 or Zelda.
Even if it's kinda hard,
'cause it's confusing.
But the best is Mario Kart.
You could have lots of players.
[gasps]
Seriously?
[sighs]
[engine stops]
So where's Sofiane?
At the hospital.
Joe, I'll take you to school. Come on.
But we were talking.
- Natalya asked me...
- Natalya's judgement is off these days.
- [Hélène] Come on. Let's go.
- [Jonathan] I forgot your name!
- Adam.
- See you at my party, then, Adam.
- [Hélène] Oh, you're getting so big.
- [Jonathan] Bye!
[door slams]
[groaning]
[chimes]
I HAVEN'T HEARD FROM YOU.
IS EVERYTHING OKAY?
TIME FOR LEVEL 2.
YOU'LL GET BUGS AND GPS TRACKERS.
DO YOUR THING!
[groans]
[sighs heavily]
[doorbell rings]
Yeah. Hi. Adam Franco?
[beeps]
[blows raspberries]
[sighs]
[cell phone chimes]
[cell phone buzzes]
[sighs]
VICTOR WANTS TO SEE YOU.
YOUSS
[beeping]
[dogs barking in distance]
[clanks]
[knocks on door]
- Yes.
- [door opens]
Please, have a seat.
First, I want to say thank you
for last night at the club.
You really stood up for us,
the guys told me.
That's what you pay me for.
I'm glad you brought that up.
Yesterday, you worked for free.
And today,
you're gonna work for free also.
Because I had to pay
for all of Bogdan's expenses
when you nearly busted his larynx.
So let's get one thing clear.
You don't ever lift a finger
against your brothers
if you want to stay here.
Understood?
INVESTIGATION FILE
I've had your name running to my head
since you got here.
Adam Franco.
At first, I told myself,
"It can't be possibly that same kid."
What are the odds you end up sitting
right there, right now?
How many bullets did you take?
- Five.
- Five. In close range.
That has to leave a few scars, no?
No?
[exhales heavily]
Is it true that when you pointed
at the cops, your rifle was empty?
[clears throat]
At 15...
[chuckles]
It takes some brass balls.
Welcome to the family.
Do you miss being in Africa?
- No, I've seen enough.
- Where were you?
Moved around a lot. DRC, Mali, Tunisia.
- And a bit of Sudan.
- Sudan? Huh, I know it well.
It was beautiful before the war.
Very.
- South America.
- [cork pops]
Ten-year service, you must know.
The locals weren't always as sweet
as their rum.
- I can vouch for that.
- [wine sloshing]
- My daughter's mother is Brazilian.
- [bottle clanks]
[glasses clink]
Pee Wee told me Amet tried
to come after you.
I can help you with that.
Bogdan is in charge of my security.
Mm.
You've been here one day.
So for now, you'll take over for Sofiane.
At least tonight, because I'm sure
he can barely stand up right now.
Which also means you need
to pick up Jonathan at school later.
He's out at four. And he has Judo.
His bag is in his room.
His sister pulled him
out of my car earlier.
It would probably piss her off.
Look, my daughter is a royal pain
in the ass, like my wife.
I'm not looking to get that kid
a new chauffeur.
I need a bodyguard.
Okay.
Good. Now get some rest.
Thank you for the drink.
[ominous music]
STORAGE OF FLAMMABLE PRODUCTS
NO SMOKING
I can't thank you enough for agreeing.
I kept my word.
I hope you do the same.
Are we clear about the risks?
What would you do if you were me?
Same as you.
This is why I have accepted.
Lay low and be ready while my team
is taking care of the last preparations.
[in Arabic]
May Allah guide your hand, my brother.
[school bell rings]
[Adam breathes deeply]
INVESTIGATION FILE
MISSING CHILD
RAPHAËL FRANCO
[kids chattering]
Now, Elliot is in trouble again.
What for?
- I think he cussed in front of...
- Hey, Lila!
[Antoine] Why are you talking
to that loser?
Anyway, what's the difference
between a blowjob and a handjob?
[kids snickering]
Wanna guess?
Or do you wanna ask your mom? The whore.
- [kids laughing]
- [Jonathan grunts]
[kid 1] Hey, leave him alone!
[Jonathan groans]
- [laughter]
- [Antoine] Come on, get up.
[kids laughing]
You're such a baby, I swear.
- [kid 2] Who is that?
- [kid 3] Who is that? Do you know him?
- [Antoine] Aah! Aah!
- [kids gasp]
- I know where you live.
- [Antoine] Aah! He broke my nose!
Let's go.
I think we can both do
some boxing classes, huh? Yeah?
- Do you really know where he lives?
- No.
[kids chattering]
[motorcycle approaching]
What are you doing here?
I told my dad I was his ride.
I'm taking you home, Joe.
- [Jonathan] No!
- [Adam] He has Judo.
His stuff is in the car.
[engine stops]
[sighs]
INVESTIGATION FILE
[Adam] That's not too tight, is it?
[Jonathan] A little, but you can leave it.
[Hélène sighs]
Excuse me. Okay.
- See you tomorrow.
- [engine starts]
Yeah, see you.
[Jonathan] Don't forget my birthday.
[tense music]
FIRST NAME: ADAM
NATURE: MURDER
ONE SHOTGUN
ADAM FRANCO
THE TEEN WHO KILLED JEAN LUC MEUNIER
THE TEEN WHO KILLED MEUNIER
AT THE DIJON COURTHOUSE
THE VICTIM, JEAN-LUC MEUNIER,
DID NOT SURVIVE
MEUNIER,
MEMBER OF THE GENERAL COUNCIL
INVOLVED IN A PEDOCRIMINALITY CASE
COMPLICITY IN THE KIDNAPPING,
MURDER, AND RAPE OF SEVERAL CHILDREN
MURDER
RAPE OF SEVERAL CHILDREN
ADAM FRANCO WAS THE BROTHER
OF ONE OF MEUNIER'S VICTIMS
A COLD-HEARTED REVENGE
QUALIFIED AS A SUICIDAL ACT
MILORD
Gentlemen.
[muffled upbeat music playing]
[women laughing]
I have to go. My show's in 20 minutes.
Maybe I'll come for round two later.
[breathes deeply]
[indistinct chatter]
You have a sec?
Excuse me, I won't be long.
You were right. I got an address.
Good work.
[muffled upbeat music playing]
- [tires screeching]
- [engine revving]
[tense music]
[hip-hop music playing]
[hip-hop music intensifies]
[engine revs]
[Moktar's daughter]
Please, tell me another story.
[soft music playing]
[Moktar] Baby, you have to sleep.
We get up early tomorrow.
We're going to see the Eiffel Tower.
[Moktar's daughter] Come on. Please.
[Moktar] Okay, okay.
In the middle of the savanna,
there is Shanga.
- [loud crash]
- [metals clinking]
[bodyguard] Open the door!
Freeze! Get down, ma'am!
Imane!
[Moktar's daughter] Mama!
[gunshots]
[grunts]
[Moktar grunts]
Stay down! On the floor!
[groans]
[muffled gunshots]
[Moktar] Baby, baby.
Oh, no. Oh, no.
[sobbing]
[grenade clinking]
[groans]
- [blasts]
- [whimpers]
[panting]
[praying in Arabic]
[knocks on door]
Assan.
Masha'Allah.
When was the last time you prayed?
Take off your trinkets,
and go and do your ablutions.
[hip-hop music playing]
We're supposed to play as a team.
[blows raspberry]
- It was hilarious.
- Mommy, when are we going to the zoo?
I don't know, Joe.
Hélène's gonna take you.
So you're not coming with us?
Sweetie, you know how much I hate animals,
my mistake marrying one, I guess.
[women laughing]
- But you said today was my special day.
- Listen, I'm really tired.
And I need to relax.
You have everything you could want here.
Don't start acting
like a spoiled baby, okay?
[mellow music]
[Jonathan] Is that for me?
Why would it be for you?
Because today's my birthday?
This party's for you?
[scoffs]
[Jonathan] Oh, cool!
Is this so I can learn to fight?
[grunts]
You have to protect your face.
Because if you don't guard it...
Punch, and back.
Not so close to your face.
You need some space.
Out, in. Protect. Pow.
[grunts]
[Adam] That's it. Tuck your thumbs in.
- I'm going to the zoo later. You coming?
- [Adam] I'm your driver, aren't I?
Happy birthday, buddy.
Watch the thumbs.
[Hélène] Look who I found
to play hide-and-seek.
Mr. Bogdan. He starts counting now,
so you better hide.
Get going. Go, hide.
- Go, go, go, hide, quick!
- [Bogdan] One, two, three, four...
There you are.
Hey, don't go too far.
We're gonna need you for something.
I think you'll like it.
Spill.
Nah, dude, mystery's half the fun.
We move in an hour.
I'm driving the kid to the zoo.
It's fine, we'll handle it.
Handle it, how?
No more babysitting.
Isn't that what you wanted?
Playing with the big boys now, bro.
And don't you dare thank me.
MIC 1 CONNECTED
[suspenseful music]
[beeps]
Gypsy King testing.
The second bug is set up now.
- We're moving out, I'm not sure where...
- [door opens]
[door squeaks]
- [Victor] Is someone here?
- Victor.
[Victor] Who the hell is under my desk?
Hey, get out here!
[soft rattling]
What are you doing?
Shh, Papa, you have to whisper.
It's hide-and-seek.
Don't call me that, Jonathan!
[Victor] How many times
have I told you not to play in here?
Did I not make myself clear?
[static]
- Yeah, but I...
- It's my fault. We got carried away.
Get lost.
[static]
Are you an idiot?
It won't happen again, sir.
Is it bad?
Nobody knows about it.
- [kid 4] There he is!
- [kid 5] We found Joe!
- [sighs]
- [kid 4] He's the seeker now!
Go on, the others are waiting for you.
[kids chattering]
We've only got one now.
Can you check if it's useable?
We're far from the phone,
but it should be fine.
[Jonathan] I told you he'd be mad.
Are you in trouble?
[Adam] Yeah, a little.
[Pee Wee] For fuck's sake!
I've been looking for you.
We gotta roll.
I'm really sorry, Joe.
I won't be able to take you to the zoo.
[car doors close]
[engines start]
[line beeping]
[suspenseful music]
Yeah, it's me.
[Victor] They're on their way.
They should be there
in four or five hours.
Is that okay?
Yeah, start the operation.
Tomorrow night, it will be ready.
I'm sure.
OPERATION? TOMORROW
[Victor] Okay.
- I will pray for you, my friend.
- [keyboard clicks]
I don't have trackers on the van.
Is Franco inside?
I'm not sure.
Christ, I'll follow them.
Manu, tell me again.
We go in the main door,
if that doesn't work, I flash my badge.
Once we're in, I neutralize the guard.
And customers...
[whistles]
Towards the bathroom, on their knees.
Scared of my gun.
I cover the main entrance
and check the time.
I head straight to number five.
Smack the cashier
with my favorite weapon and bam!
[JB] "Everybody, hands up!
I want Olivier Lopez!"
"He has ten seconds to unlock these gates
if he wants little Annie to show up at
Pierre and Marie Curie's daycare Monday."
And, schlack! I take his badge,
stuff the employees under the counter,
and I stay in guard in front of the door
of the safe, and wait.
Not bad. But didn't you miss
an important detail?
No, come on, it's right here, Pee Wee.
[JB] I didn't forget it.
Get me all stressed out.
[indistinct radio chatter]
Your turn.
I move up front and wait for you.
With the motor running.
[Manu] Hey, turn it up, JB.
[man 3] Moktar Al Tayeb,
a known terrorist,
could be here on French soil,
preparing an attack in a suite?
And isn't it unusual that no one saw
any movement...
[JB] Who cares?
It's always the same story.
[man 3] ...15 minutes after the explosion?
Where do you get your information?
Last I heard...
[Manu] I give that sucker
three more days, tops.
He's got every cop
in the country on his tail,
which is great for us.
[JB] No shit, he's going down in flames
like all the others.
- [thumps]
- What's with you?
[host] ...since Moktar Al Tayeb's
still at large.
Gentlemen, a lively debate...
Find something more upbeat.
[radio chatter]
[upbeat music playing]
[upbeat music continues]
[Manu] Ladies and gentlemen,
this is a robbery!
Do what we say and no one gets hurt.
THE BANK IS CLOSED
FOR MAINTENANCE
- [Karim] I'm parked out front.
- [Hélène] Okay.
[Jonathan] I was hoping
Adam can come with us too.
He didn't have a choice, I told you.
- I don't like things this way.
- What way?
When everybody acts like I don't exist,
like I'm not even here.
Hey, Adam isn't your friend, okay?
He brought you that punching bag
to be nice, but he works for Dad.
[Jonathan] Yeah,
but at least he doesn't pretend.
[upbeat music continues]
Go, man. We're good.
Fucking, eh. I told you, didn't I? Huh?
[Pee Wee] I told you, didn't I?
Genius, Pee Wee. That was too much.
Motherfucking clockwork, bro.
[JB] Good job, Adam.
You were patient, very cool.
I just want a whiff of that money.
How much do you think we've got?
- Three hundred at least. Come to Daddy.
- Three hundred, four,
it could even be five!
With this, Pee Wee,
you can finally get a decent car
and get rid of that shit box you've got.
Yeah, and you can finally
get someone to fix your back.
- You wanna whiff of this, taxi-man?
- [JB] That's a kick-ass fare.
I don't think taxi
likes the smell of money, guys.
[JB] Yeah, he only likes the smell
of ass-kicking.
[Manu] Speed it up, though, won't ya?
I want to get home already.
[tires screeching]
[distant cough]
[groans]
[hip-hop music]
[gunshot]
[muffled gunshot]
[muffled siren blaring]
- Gimme a rifle.
- [gunshots]
[Adam] Get Pee Wee out.
[Manu] Take care of Pee Wee,
I'll cover you!
[JB] Okay, okay.
Come on, come on.
Let's move!
[Manu] Take cover!
- You all right, bro, huh?
- Yeah, I'm good.
[Manu] Adam, behind you!
Get us a car!
Move now!
Go.
[indistinct shouting]
Manu, you have ammo?
Get in! Get in!
[Pee Wee] JB, hurry up!
[car engine starts]
Let's go.
[JB] Shit! Pee Wee!
[gunshots]
[tires screeching]
[Pee Wee] They got company!
[Manu] I'm going!
[groans]
Come on, Manu!
Come on. Pee Wee?
Let's go! Let's go! Let's go!
[JB] Adam, come on!
Go, go, go!
[Adam] Get down!
Fuck.
[JB] Can I sit up straight now?
Oh, I'm sure it's Amet's motherfuckers.
Who else would try that shit?
[reporter 4] Several residents
of the neighborhood
were caught in a cross fire,
two with life-threatening injuries.
The police commissioner issued
a statement just a few minutes ago.
He did not refute a possible link
between this altercation and the attack
at the Star Hotel that shook up
the capital, Saturday night.
With Moktar Al Tayeb's still on the run,
the commissioner stated
that another terrorist attack
in the Paris region
is highly probable in the coming days...
[panting]
Wait.
[sighs]
Who was it?
[Marconnet] The guy you brought in?
[Kruger] Yes, sir.
[exhales deeply]
[Marconnet] What's going on?
Have you decided to ruin
your entire career in three days?
You're right on track, Kruger.
My agents intercepted a call from Moktar.
He's preparing another hit.
From the sound of it, tomorrow.
Does he want revenge or something?
Is that why he's still here?
- What else?
- Nothing.
Hm.
Franco will find him.
I give you my word, sir.
I had a conversation
with Khartoum this morning.
They're losing patience.
Because we promised he'd be dead,
that's part of the deal.
And it was your idea to get him here
and assassinate him.
Instead, we're looking
at a possible attack
on French soil, because you failed.
If you blow this,
they'll trace it back to you and to me.
To Sudan.
He'll be dead by tomorrow.
- He'd better be.
- [watch beeps]
- They followed you?
- [JB] No, they were waiting.
They cut us off.
Someone told him the route.
Youssef, hand out the shares.
Bogdan.
Go see the banker
and get answer from the son of a bitch.
[Youssef] Here. Give Manu his cut, too.
Go on.
[tense music]
I suggest you get far away from here.
Leave with Jonathan tonight if you can.
What the hell are you talking about?
If I know, then Victor
will figure it out, too.
[whispers]
Fucking hell.
[suspenseful music]
[cell phone ringing]
[Amet] Be very careful
with what you're about to say to me.
Did you try to screw me?
What? No.
Half wasn't enough for you?
Of course, it is.
What are you talking about?
[Amet] The new bouncer you'd brought in,
you didn't tell us he'd be there.
Who is he?
You get your new guys
from special forces now?
[Natalya] Adam? I didn't know.
He works for Victor.
How could I know
he would be there today?
[Amet] You promised me
this thing's rock solid.
All we had to do was ambush them
and get the money.
But your new guy,
whatever the fuck his name is,
he's lit my guys up, he's gonna pay.
And you're gonna pay for it too.
[Natalya] Please, I swear to God,
I had no idea.
I didn't know anything about it,
you have to believe me.
[Amet] I don't have to believe
a word you say,
but now you need to listen.
Normally, I'm a very reasonable guy.
You know that.
But when I don't get what I want,
what I'm promised,
I start acting like a spoiled little shit.
[Hélène] Dad!
- [Amet] I can do really stupid things.
- [Manu] Victor!
- I need help!
- [Natalya] No, no, no.
[Amet] This afternoon, I was kinda bored,
so I went out to get some fresh air.
- I went to see the lions at the zoo.
- [Victor] Hélène!
[Amet] I ran into your kids.
They're cute. Very polite.
I kept the little one with me.
He even told me it was his birthday today.
- We're gonna have fun.
- [Jonathan] Mommy!
- Mommy, come and get me, Mommy.
- Sweetheart.
Mommy's coming right away.
Everything's fine.
- [Jonathan] I wanna come home.
- Don't worry.
[Amet] You're going to give me
my money, Natalya.
I'll get in touch with Victor.
Then you're going to convince him.
Otherwise, I'll do something
we'll all regret.
[Jonathan] Mommy!
[sobbing]
[suspenseful music]
[doorbell chimes]
[music fades]
- [Manu] Oh, sorry. Don't move.
- Forget it, I'll do it myself. Okay?
[Manu] All right,
I'll leave you alone then.
[distant thud]
[Victor] Who does he think he is?
Is he serious?
He thinks he's gonna blackmail me?
Bogdan, get all our contacts
going on this.
You find that fucker's mom
and bring her in here!
- He'll get the message!
- You have to pay, Victor.
- I'm begging you.
- He'll get nothing.
We will not pay a ransom.
It's a matter of principle.
If we show any weakness,
we lose all respect.
What respect?
You really think he respects you?
He tried to screw you over today!
He kidnapped our son!
Enough with that!
[groans]
[Bogdan] Victor.
Are you all right?
Really, Victor?
My son's worth nothing
because his blood's not yours?
[Natalya] You disgust me.
You disgust me!
Watch yourself, Natalya.
Why should I? What are you gonna do?
- Enough, Natalya. Calm...
- Get your hands off me!
Asshole! You're his fucking godfather!
[door slams]
[Hélène] Where's Adam?
[cell phone buzzing]
Yeah, Manu?
[Hélène] They took my brother.
They kidnapped Joe.
What do you mean?
Amet wants the money,
my dad won't pay him.
I'm freaking out.
Adam?
Adam? Are you there?
- I'm busy right now.
- They'll kill him.
[sighs]
[breathes shakily]
[Hélène] Thanks for nothing.
[sighs]
[Adam] Open the trunk.
What are you doing?
LOCALIZING KARIM'S CAR
I'm moving.
You keep your eyes on that store.
Pee Wee is the link. Potential contact.
Franco!
[suspenseful music]
[engine starts]
- Franco took off. I don't know why.
- [Mona] Shit.
Hélène called him five minutes ago.
- The boy Jonathan got kidnapped.
- What?
[Mona] The guys who ambushed them
at the bank
are holding the kid for ransom.
He's heading south. Should I follow him?
Cisko?
- Cisko?
- Mona, I have contact. Call you back.
Al Tayeb!
Hands up.
[Cisko] Turn around.
Step forward.
That's far enough.
- [gunshot]
- [body thuds]
[Moktar] Assan.
Assan!
We got to go now, cousin.
Come on, quickly, let's go!
[baby crying in distance]
Shit.
[breathes deeply]
[coughs]
[indistinct shouting]
- Uh, I need some smack.
- [man 4] You have cash?
Yeah.
[coughing]
What the hell? You stink.
Go ahead. That corner left. Then down.
[dog barking]
[Adam coughing]
[TV chatter]
Fifty a smack.
[drawer thuds]
Is there somewhere to relax?
It's rough out there.
[man coughing]
[man groaning]
- [man coughing]
- [indistinct chatter]
- [groans]
- [Adam] Where's the kid?
- [choking]
- Where is the kid?
What floor?
[man] Fifth floor.
- He's with Amet.
- [neck crunches]
[body thuds]
[man 1] Hey, tell Janusz
to get his ass up.
Boss wants to see him.
[man 2] Janusz? Come here.
[hip-hop music playing]
[man 3] Janusz? Where are you?
- Amet's looking.
- [Janusz] Yeah, okay. I'm coming.
- [bones crunch]
- [groans]
[man 4] Janusz, where are you?
[woman grunts]
Janusz?
[woman moans]
[mutters]
[suspenseful music]
- [gunshots]
- [women scream]
[dogs barking in distance]
- [indistinct shouting]
- [woman screams]
[gunshots]
[man mutters, groans]
- [gunshots]
- [groans]
[man groans]
[Adam groans]
[cracks]
[man shouts]
[both grunting]
- [gunshots]
- [groaning]
[yelling]
[hip-hop music playing]
[muffled clattering]
[muffled grunting]
[man 1 groans]
[both grunting]
[man 2] Fuck!
[yelling]
[indistinct chatter]
[man muttering]
[both grunt]
[cocks gun]
[groaning]
[Amet] Move your ass.
I don't know, just get people up here.
- Yeah, it's the guy from the robbery.
- [Adam grunts]
I don't know, some guy Victor brought in.
[Amet] Go fuck yourself!
[Jonathan whimpering]
[Amet] Stop whining, kid!
I'm going to open the door.
- [Jonathan] Adam!
- [Amet] Shut up, you little shit!
[Jonathan whimpering]
[gunshot]
Where the hell's Victor?
I wanna see Victor!
[Adam] He doesn't know I'm here.
Who the fuck are you?
- [gunshot]
- [Amet groaning]
[Jonathan] Adam!
I just wanna go home.
It's okay, buddy. It's over.
[Amet] Wait, wait, hold on.
We can work it out.
[muffled voice]
Let-let us talk about this.
I-I have money. Anything you want.
Name your price.
[muffled gunshot]
[calm music]
[car approaching]
[Natalya] Joe! Joe!
- Thank you.
- [coughs]
It's okay, Jojo.
- Everything's gonna be okay.
- Baby, I'm so sorry. You're so brave.
[Natalya] I love you so much.
Adam?
[Hélène] Can you hear me?
[monitor beeping]
[beeping]
[door opens]
[Kruger] I was told
you were ready to die out there.
I'm looking for people exactly like you.
What would you say
to getting a clean slate?
To getting a brand-new start somewhere?
A brand-new life.
A brand-new identity.
A brand-new family.
[soft sobbing]
Think about it.
And bring me Al Tayeb.
[door opens]
[soft grunt]
- [Hélène] Adam?
- [groans]
Are you okay?
You can't go on your own.
Adam, take it easy.
You have to recover.
You lost a lot of blood, remember?
I'm not letting you go. This is crazy!
- [groans]
- [objects clattering]
This is bullshit. You can barely walk.
You wanted your brother, you got him.
Now, leave me the hell alone.
[Adam grunts]
[door slams]
JASMIN STREET
[suspenseful music]
[Bogdan] No. He doesn't know anything.
He didn't sell us out.
Yeah.
I'm sure.
[coughs]
We have a problem.
Whoever talked is one of us.
[Adam coughs]
Youssef, drive him home, would you?
You look like hell.
How'd you know where Joe was?
Pee Wee told me about Amet.
I went on his turf, I got lucky.
You got lucky?
How come you didn't call us?
Hélène said Victor
wouldn't pay the ransom.
I'm good to get home on my own.
Don't bother.
CONTACTS - ALL CONTACTS
AURELIE - BÉRÉ - CISKO
[line rings]
[female voice] Hello. You have reached
the answering service...
Damn it.
[engine revs]
[thrilling music]
[pills rattle]
[alarm blares]
[groaning]
[gunshot]
- [bullet clanks]
- [alarm stops]
[mouse clicks]
[soft tense music]
[keyboard clacks]
[mouse scrolling]
[thumps on table]
[groaning]
CONTACT CONFIRMED.
DELIVERY UNDER 24H.
- [tires screech]
- [siren wails]
[car doors open, close]
[cop 1] Come out now.
- Keep your hands in the air.
- [cop 2] Down, now.
[cop 1] On your knees.
- [cop 2] Put down the weapon.
- [groaning]
[cop 2] Put it down gently.
I'm undercover.
Badge number 223-416.
[cop 1] Okay, verify that.
[tense music]
[engine starts]
[gasps]
[Adam] Just go home.
- [Adam groans]
- [lock rattles]
[door opens]
[object clatters]
Thank you.
[computer trills]
- [Bogdan] Yeah.
- [Youssef] What the fuck is going on?
No one's answering at the house
[Bogdan] Vic lost his shit.
He fired the whole crew.
I hadn't seen him that bad in a long time.
[Youssef] Why the hell he'd do that?
[Bogdan] I went to have a little chat
with the girls at Milord.
Now we know who told those assholes
about our plans.
It was Natalya.
She was supposed to get half the take.
She's been wanting to leave for a while.
- She can't take it with Vic anymore.
- [Youssef] Dumb bitch.
I hope for her sake,
he's in a forgiving mood.
[Bogdan] Forget that.
He's had a few drinks already.
It's not looking good.
[Youssef] Wanna hear something else?
- Adam is a fucking cop.
- [Bogdan] I knew it.
[Youssef] We'll take him out.
Call JB. We'll meet outside his place.
- [Bogdan] Okay.
- Fuck.
I want you to put an end to it.
My guy spotted him.
It's a matter of hours.
He spotted him?
He was right outside my window.
Just last night.
Watch yourself, Kruger.
My patience has its limits.
I'm starting to get a tad bit irritated.
Take a look at what he left me.
[Marconnet] What does he want?
To scare me, I suppose.
[Marconnet] Is he planning
to leak all the files, is that it?
HARDER TO WAIT THAN TO WITHSTAND FIRE
You now have access
to two commando units from Tactical Ops.
You can't imagine
how much that's costing me.
So as soon as your special agent...
MONA: ADAM'S COVER BLOWN,
CISKO UNREACHABLE
...has him in sight,
call the men to clean up.
I want no trace of this.
None.
Am I perfectly clear?
I want every bit
of this fucking disaster buried for good!
[Marconnet sighs]
Understood.
[retreating footsteps]
[JB] Hey, guys, I don't know about this.
He saved our asses at the ambush.
[Youssef] He's an infiltrator,
sent in to fuck with us.
[JB] Fuck with us, how?
I'm serious, Youssef. Fuck with us, how?
I saw what I saw, JB. Shut your hole.
He's the one getting fucked.
All I know is we better have
one hell of a plan going in.
You guys weren't with us.
The guy is lethal.
[Youssef] There's three of us, one of him.
We go in, light him up,
and we're out of here!
[knocks on window]
What does she want?
[Mona] Hi, guys. Do you have a light?
- Sure, we do, miss.
- Thanks.
- Wanna smoke?
- Thanks, we're good.
I'm trying to quit.
[gunshots]
[groaning]
[car alarm blaring in distance]
- [blaring continues]
- [woman yelling]
- [gunshots]
- [Bogdan groans]
[Pee Wee] Hey, Adam.
I didn't have a chance
to say bye to you yesterday, and...
I won't get another one.
I wanted to thank you for everything
you've done. I won't forget it.
You saved my life.
And more than that, actually.
Thanks to you...
Well, you'll never know how...
[in small volume]
...big of a thing you did.
I would've loved
to get to know you better,
but it wasn't in the cards, bro.
Sorry it doesn't make any sense right now.
But I just wanted to say
you're one hell of a beast,
and bye, buddy.
[door clattering]
[labored breathing]
What happened, Mona?
I took them out.
Victor's guys came for you.
[softly]
I won't make it.
I'm sorry.
[computer beeps]
SEARCH COMPLETE
[suspenseful music]
[door opens]
[door closes]
[birds chirping]
[suspenseful music]
[man on video]
Another great move by Bennacer.
Oh, and then... Goal!
[cheering on video]
[grumbles]
[indistinct chatter on video]
- [Adam grunts]
- [groaning]
- [clanging]
- [man choking]
[indistinct prayer in Arabic]
[praying in Arabic]
- [gunshot]
- [screaming in pain]
Give me your weapon.
[in Arabic]
What are you preparing?
[in English]
You work for those assholes?
And how is my friend Kruger doing?
[Moktar] He must be an Army General by now
with everything he's stolen
from my country.
What was the money for?
What is the operation?
[monitor beeping]
You two, out here!
Out, now!
To the wall.
To the wall!
[Pee Wee] I don't know what they told you,
but it's all lies.
We're not terrorists,
we're not hurting anyone.
On your knees, hands on your head.
- What's the plan, Pee Wee?
- There's no plan, the money was for her!
We couldn't go to the hospital.
Who is she?
My daughter.
[Pee Wee] There was never
an attempted attack at the hotel, Adam.
- They wanted to kill Moktar...
- [gunshot]
What are you doing in France?
I was invited by your Minister
to discuss a cease-fire in South of Sudan.
[Moktar grunts]
[Moktar] Everybody thought
it was a miracle
when you came to South Sudan in the 1980s.
The French, helping us gain our freedom.
And it worked.
We got our independence, thanks to you
and the blood of our people.
But look at where we are today.
Allah warned us,
when you make a pact with the devil,
he always comes back to get his due.
And this is the sad truth.
Your masters were only interested
in one thing.
Not democracy, not peace. No.
The only wealth
that you could see in our country...
was our black gold.
I have fought for one thing,
and one thing only,
the freedom of my people,
our right to decide for ourselves,
our land, and our resources.
And because of this,
today, I am a terrorist,
when yesterday, I was an ally?
And you invite me under diplomatic cover
to murder me?
You want my life?
Take it!
You've already taken all that I have.
My land, my honor,
the love of my life.
You even took her from me.
Her operation was a success.
She's gonna live.
[Moktar] I just want to say my prayer
and say goodbye.
You can do what you want with me
after that.
But she has nothing to do with it.
[Adam] Come here.
Come on!
[Moktar] Hey, sunshine.
I came to say goodbye.
I love you so much. You can't imagine.
A government agent did this to her.
[Pee Wee] A guy just like you.
Was it you?
[Moktar praying in Arabic]
- [gunshot]
- [Pee Wee gasps]
[rapid footsteps]
[commando 1] Go, go, go!
- [screams]
- [gunshots]
[Adam] Hold your fire!
Hold your fire! I'm one of you!
[commando 2] Here!
[commando 3] Men down! Men down!
Stay down.
[gunshots]
[indistinct radio chatter]
[Adam] Down!
[Pee Wee] Watch out!
- [explosion]
- [groans]
[high-pitched ringing]
[dramatic music]
[muffled gunshots]
[Adam] Pee Wee.
Pee Wee!
They're gonna send others.
This isn't over. Get what she needs.
[cocks gun]
[suspenseful music]
How many are they?
I'm not sure, four or five.
Maybe more on the roof.
There's at least one team surrounding us.
We won't make it.
You're gonna have to trust me, Pee Wee.
Do exactly as I say, okay?
In one minute, you crack the door open.
You throw this grenade
in front of the ambulance.
You make a rain bullets, okay?
They'll hone in on you. So take cover.
- I'm not cut out for this, bro.
- Hey, you can do this.
Remember why you're here.
- One minute.
- [beeps]
Fuck.
[ominous music]
[timer beeps]
[hissing]
[suspenseful music]
[man shouting]
[explosion]
[gunshots]
[Adam] Pee Wee, go!
Move! Move! Move!
[commando 4] Get him.
Behind the ambulance!
[commando 5] In the ambulance!
- [gunshot]
- [groans]
- [explosion]
- [man screams]
Pee Wee, let's roll!
All right, Pee Wee, go!
[gunshots]
Adam, come on! They're everywhere!
Hit it.
[gunfire in distance]
[explosion]
[mellow music]
[inaudible]
TERRORIST?
THE SHADY TIES BETWEEN MOKTAR AL TAYEB
AND MINISTER MARCONNET
[mellow music continues]
[cop] I'm sorry.
Good luck.
[woman] ASC Social Services,
how may I help you?
My little brother was brought in
two days ago.
I'm trying to get a hold of him.
His name is Jonathan Pastore.
Can you give me your access code, please?
- What?
- Your access code.
They would have given it to you
when you were registered
with visitation rights.
If you're not registered,
you'll have to call back in the morning.
A counselor will transfer you
to visitation. They're close for the day.
Can you please tell me how to reach him?
He's only eight years old.
I understand it's hard.
But there's nothing I can do tonight.
I'm sorry.
Call back tomorrow.
[ominous music]
[chuckles]
[Jonathan whimpers]
[man groans]
- [flesh squishing]
- [man groaning]
[calm music]
[gloomy music]