[chattering on radio]
[alarm blares]
[announcer on PA] Attention,
all dome personnel and residents.
Due to the meteor shower warning,
the lockdown will start in seven minutes.
Please return to your living quarters
and remain there until further notice.
I repeat,
the lockdown will start in seven minutes.
[teen 1] How much longer?
The lockdown's about to start.
[teen 2] Oh, thanks. We didn't hear
the super loud announcement.
[teen 3] Is that supposed to be blinking?
[teen 1] You guys are bad at being bad.
-[teen 2] Hey, you could help, you know?
-[teen 1] I got us in here. Doing my part.
[teen 2]
Could you at least hand me that wrench?
Seriously, guys. Why is this blinking?
Probably because we're stealing it.
Why don't you say that a little louder in
case the microphones didn't pick that up?
Don't worry, genius.
They don't have microphones down here.
Seriously, you don't have to wear that.
Says you.
They probably have facial ID scans.
Borney, it's a garage, not a food vault.
[teen 2] And you look like an idiot.
Yeah, well, my brother told me once,
this kid, he got caught
messing around down here,
and then they put him in a holding cell
out by the terra complex
and left him there for 60 years.
-You're doing it again.
-Doing what?
You're catastrophizing.
-Okay, that's not even a word.
-Of course it's a word.
-[teen 1] It's totally a word.
-[door opens]
What was that?
[door closes]
Everybody, hide.
[whispers] Go, quick, quick.
[grunts, sighs]
[worker 1] Where is everybody?
[worker 2] They're in lockdown like
we were supposed to be 30 minutes ago.
[worker 1] Okay, okay.
[door closes]
We're clear.
Don't tell me I'm catastrophizing.
Dylan, it's almost lockdown.
What is taking so long?
[Borney] Catastrophizing. [scoffs]
[Dylan grunts] What's your personal record
for hot-wiring a rover, huh?
[grunting]
[engine whirs]
-[Dylan laughs]
-Whoa!
[Dylan] Yes!
How'd you like that, huh?
[alarm blaring]
-You said there wouldn't be alarms.
-Yeah, on the doors.
-What do you mean--
-I told you, but nobody listens to me!
We're gonna spend
the rest of our lives in a tiny cell!
Do something! Turn it off.
Oh, yeah. Let me get right on that
for you. I don't know how!
-What do you mean you don't know how?
-[teen 1] You're the one who did it!
[Dylan] Your dad's on the science team.
Just do something!
[door opens]
You must be Caleb.
My name is Maria Slater.
Sorry to keep you waiting.
We've only got a few more hours until
the lockdown, so things are a bit chaotic.
Would you like some chocolate?
It's real. Just arrived
on the cargo shuttle this morning.
Caleb, are you aware of the death benefits
included in your father's contract?
Yes, ma'am.
It said if he died working in the mines,
then any family he had here with him
would get to go to Omega.
That's right.
It's important that you understand
how much we all appreciate
your father's service.
I can only imagine
how devastating this must be.
I understand that you also
lost your mother a few years back.
Seven.
She died seven years ago.
The journey to Omega,
as you probably are aware, is 75 years.
You, of course, will be in cryosleep
for the duration of the trip.
Once you arrive, it'll be like waking
from a long, peaceful nap,
exactly the same age you are now.
Do I have to go? Can't I just stay here?
I'm afraid that is not an option.
I understand that you probably
will miss your friends.
I'll never see them again.
By the time I wake up,
they'll be old or dead.
You will make new friends on Omega.
Caleb, your parents sacrificed
a great deal to give you this opportunity.
People who come here
and work in the mines,
they spend years
fueling the transports to Omega,
all so that their families,
their children, can be on them.
Now, the meteor shower warning
will be in effect for the next 72 hours.
Once the lockdown is lifted,
and we have the all-clear,
you will be on a transport
and on your way.
I thought the next transport didn't leave
for another two months.
Scheduling is always a bit fluid.
I know it may not seem like it right now,
but this really is the start
of something special for you.
[workers chattering]
[grunts, pants]
[Michael] Come on, Caleb. You can do it.
Don't be scared.
What if I fall?
Geez.
That'd be pretty messy, wouldn't it?
We can go back down if you want.
We don't have to do this.
But if we do, you gotta get up there
on your own.
-You understand why?
-Yeah.
You wanna go down?
-[sighs] No.
-Good man.
Go on then. Let's do this.
[Michael]
You see that little star right there?
Just off the edge of that cluster.
-You see it?
-Yeah.
[Michael] They say it burned out
over a hundred years ago.
But it was so far away, the last
of its light hasn't reached us yet.
Your mom used to say
it's like a memory traveling through time.
We'd sit up here, and she'd say
life was just like that star.
And all the memories we have, all
the people we love, the places we've been,
that's the light we see,
even though the star is gone.
You were born here, raised here.
This dome is the only world
you've ever known.
So many memories you never got to have.
We're gonna fix that someday.
How?
Well, there's a place me and your mom
used to sneak away back to
before you were born,
just off past the eastern ridge.
It's the only place up here
she really loved.
Right there.
What's so special about it?
You'll see. When you're a little older,
you and me are gonna take a road trip.
A what?
[chuckles]
Something we used to do back on Earth.
No better way to travel
when you gotta get somewhere.
-Hey.
-[Caleb] Hey.
Figured I might find you up here.
How'd things go with Ms. Slater?
They're putting me on a transport
in three days.
As soon as the lockdown's over.
We could still do it.
No, it's fine. We don't have to--
Hey. Whatever's out there,
your dad wanted you to see it.
We're doing this.
-Just thought we'd have more time.
-Me too.
[Borney panting]
Marcus, this is too high.
Why do they always have to go up so high?
-[Marcus] You're almost there.
-Here he is.
Hey, did you get your pills?
[Marcus] Yeah, I got my pills.
Why are you always bothering me
about my pills?
Because you've got a heart
the size of an asteroid, that's why.
[Marcus] Yeah? Well, you've got the mouth
the size of a black hole. [chuckles]
[Borney] Good one.
-Hey, guys.
-[Dylan] Hey.
[groans] Hey, how about from now on,
we do this a little lower to the ground?
-[Marcus] Hey.
-That sounds pretty good to me.
-[Marcus] How'd things go with Ms. Slayer?
-[Borney] That lady scares me.
[Marcus] Yeah, that lady scares everybody.
[Borney] My brother told me
this kid talked back to her,
and then he disappeared for two days.
A-And when they found him again,
he said he couldn't remember
a single thing that happened.
[chuckles]
You realize not a thing
you just said is true, right?
Yeah, well, what do you know?
My brother's a genius.
He knows these things.
Seriously, what was she like?
She gave me chocolate.
Like, actual, real chocolate?
Man, real chocolate.
I can't even remember
the last time I had chocolate.
W-Wait a second. What's going on?
What's wrong with you guys?
He's leaving in three days.
What?
But-- But the next transport
didn't leave for another two months.
They're sending one
as soon as the lockdown's over.
So, we're still leaving, though, right?
Are you kidding me?
We're leaving tonight.
[Borney] Are you guys sure we're ready?
[sighs] With what we added today,
I think we have enough.
Hey, can you imagine what they'll do to us
if they find out we stole this much stuff?
-I can.
-We're gonna need more oxygen.
They're definitely gonna notice
if we take more.
Yeah, but they won't notice
before tonight.
Oh, yeah, yeah, yeah.
You guys, I got a crack-smacker.
-A what?
-You know, for cracks.
-Do you mean a sealant pen?
-Yeah, if you wanna be all technical.
[knocking]
Hey, quick. Quick, cover this up.
-Wait, wait, wait.
-[Borney] Marcus, hey, help me hide this.
[keypad beeps]
Caleb Channing?
Yes, sir.
[messenger] Your father's ashes.
Sorry for your loss.
That was depressing.
[laughing]
-[Dylan] You okay?
-[Caleb] Yeah.
[Dylan] You sure?
You're all right, buddy.
I'm just saying, the whole point
of a lockdown is so you don't leave.
Yeah, that's why tonight's perfect.
Once we get clear of the perimeter,
they can't come after us.
-It's like an insurance thing.
-But there's a meteor shower warning.
Yeah. They issue those warnings
all the time.
Have you ever actually seen
a meteor shower?
That's a dumb question. How could I?
We've never even been outside before.
You don't have to come
if you don't want to.
Of course I'm coming.
What about you? You sure you can do this?
He's gotta bring his pills.
Dude,
will you knock it off with the pills?
Stop worrying.
It's not good for you. Thank you.
If I don't worry, who's gonna worry?
I wanna go outside.
That settles it then.
Hey.
We don't have the access codes
into the garage.
How are we gonna get out?
I got an idea about that. [chuckles]
[Borney] Addison Weaver. That's your idea?
Don't stare.
Yes, that's my idea. It's perfect.
She just came up from Earth,
like, a couple of months ago.
Doesn't have any friends.
[whispers] I hear she's weird.
[Dylan sighs] Well, I can handle that.
Plus, her dad's on the science team.
So she has all codes
to all subbasement garages.
I don't know, man. Like you said,
she doesn't have any friends.
So we're just gonna be all nice
to get the codes?
[Dylan] All right, look.
We can all do something really nice
for her when we get back, okay?
Right now, this is the only way
we get to do this.
[Borney sighs]
All right.
[Dylan clears throat]
[sighs]
Hi.
Can I help you?
My name's Dylan.
-Cool name.
-[chuckles] Thanks.
You know, I saw you sitting over here,
and I thought you--
Hey-- Hey, wait! Hold on.
-Hey, come on. [grunts]
-Hey, watch it.
[Dylan] Addison, wait.
[sighs]
I don't think it's going very well.
[Dylan] Just hold on. Wait.
-Hey, hey, hey. Hey.
-What?
-Just--
-I know the way you guys think about me.
I'm just
a spoiled little Earth girl, right?
The only time that anyone here talks to me
is whenever they want something.
So whatever it is, the answer's no.
Okay. First of all, you don't know
why I came over here.
Maybe I came over here
because I feel bad no one talks to you.
Okay, great. Are we done?
Okay, okay. Just hold on.
Hey, can you hear me out?
-Please?
-What?
Look, my best friend is about to leave.
Like forever. Okay?
His dad was the miner
that got killed last week.
I'm sorry. I didn't--
I didn't know.
[chattering]
Bet she tells Ms. Slayer on us.
Then we're really in for it.
You need to be more positive, man.
Oh, I'm plenty positive.
Positive she's gonna tell on us.
Are you trying to freak everyone out?
[Borney] But why would she help us?
[sighs]
So what do you need the codes for?
Uh, we need to borrow
one of the long-range rovers.
Why?
'Cause we gotta go somewhere.
-Where do you have to go?
-That's not important.
Well, it is if you want the codes.
Okay.
There's a crater
about a day's ride from here.
It's in the eighth quadrant.
Nobody's supposed to go out there.
Not even the miners go out there.
Look, all we need from you are the codes
to get the rover and to get outside.
I still don't get exactly
why you're doing this.
I told you already, okay?
His dad wanted him to--
Yeah, yeah. No, I get why he's doing it.
Why are you?
'Cause he's my friend.
Yeah. Okay, fine.
-Yeah, I'll get you the codes.
-Really?
-Under one condition.
-Yeah, yeah. Anything.
-She what?
-She wants to come, okay?
Why?
I don't know. She said it's the only way
she'll give us the codes.
This is a bad idea. No.
-No, this is, like, the worst idea ever.
-Why?
-[whispers] Because she's from Earth.
-[Dylan] So?
Earth people have different ways.
They're-- They're peculiar.
You're peculiar.
Let's give her a shot, man.
But she doesn't know how we do stuff.
Okay, look. She's not gonna give us
the codes unless we let her come, right?
Pretty much.
-Then we vote. All in favor?
-Yeah.
-It's gotta be unanimous, Borney.
-Borney, put your stupid hand in.
[groans]
-Thank you. Now let me win this one.
-[Borney] Hey, not fair.
-[Caleb] Nope. Nope. Uh-huh.
-Come on, guys!
-Nope.
-[Marcus] You're gonna knock my drink.
-What are you doing?
-You guys done?
Oh.
So, what's it gonna be?
Let's go steal a rover.
[Addison] Let me get right on that!
I don't know how to turn it off!
[Borney] See, I told you! What did I say?
I said this was a bad idea!
[Dylan] Borney, you're not helping!
So why don't you just--
Yeah! Yeah, that'll work.
[alarm blares]
[announcer on PA] Attention. Attention,
all dome personnel and residents.
[panting]
Mandatory lockdown of all dome facilities
will commence in T-minus three minutes.
We should go.
Yeah, you think?
[Caleb] Oxygen looks good.
-[Marcus] Okay. This-- This is good.
-All right.
-[Borney] Marcus?
-[Marcus] I got it.
Are you sure you know
how to drive this thing?
You kidding?
These things basically drive themselves.
[engine cranks, sputters]
I got it. I got it.
[engine starts]
Go punch in the code to the door.
So you guys can drive off without me?
No, thanks.
I got it. What's the code?
Ten, 28, 58.
Ten, 28, 58. Got it.
[door hisses]
[Dylan] Hey, what's that?
[Addison] Just a little something
from Earth. It's a tradition.
You said it was a road trip. Right?
-Okay.
-[Marcus scoffs] Earth people.
[announcer on PA]
Attention, all personnel.
Mandatory lockdown
will commence in T-minus one minute.
You know the best thing about road trips?
You get to leave everything behind.
[alarm blaring]
[Michael]
No matter what's happened before.
Whatever mistakes you might have made.
Whatever dreams you might've lost.
Whoever you're supposed to be
or whatever the world
has tried to make you.
Let's go. [sighs]
[Michael] Because now you're deciding.
You're the one choosing the path.
And the most important thing to remember,
it's not just about where you're going.
It's about how you get there,
the people you get there with.
You're never quite the same when
you finish as you were when you began.
In that magical space between where
you've been and where you're going…
you're free.
You're the master of your own fate.
[Caleb] We did it. We're actually outside.
[Borney] Whoa. Look at that.
It just goes on and on forever.
-You okay, man?
-Yeah.
[Borney] Oh, man.
This is gonna be so cool.
We're like-- like adventurers now, like--
Uh, what's the word?
Masters of our own fate.
[Borney chuckles] Yeah. Yeah, I like that.
-You guys ready to see the moon?
-[Caleb] Yeah.
-Whoo!
-[laughing]
-Let's do this!
We're gonna visit all these places.
We're all gonna hang out.
Gonna be so-- Gonna be so fun.
-[Marcus] Let me grab the wheel.
-[Borney] Gonna be so fun.
[Dylan] Let's do this!
-What does this one do?
-[chuckling] No, no, no. Not those.
[Marcus] Is this one… This one stops the--
We are on track.
We've been driving for, like, two hours.
So we have about ten more hours to go.
[imitates gunshots]
[both scream]
-Hey! Not funny!
-[Marcus chuckling]
-[Marcus] Get off of me! Get off of me!
-Hat. Give me the hat!
-Stop!
-[laughs]
-[Borney] Hey!
-[Marcus laughs] Look at you. Look at you.
-[Marcus] Oh, my God.
-[Borney] This looks better.
[Marcus]
Addison, does it look better? Seriously.
[Dylan] Is that the transport?
Yeah.
[alarm beeping]
[Borney] Time for your pills.
[beeping stops]
-What are those for?
-He's got a giant heart. Like huge.
The doctors think he'll probably die
in a few years.
-Dude.
-What? They do.
But he won't because he takes his pills.
So, he's fine.
-Well, that's good then.
-[Borney] Hey. [sighs]
Will you hold on a second?
You gotta drink water.
-Otherwise, you'll cough the whole time.
-[slurps]
Hey.
Hey, guys-- Guys, guys, check that out.
[Borney chuckles]
[Dylan chuckles]
I've never seen anything like that before.
-[Addison] Whoa.
-[Borney chuckles] Whoa.
[Addison chuckles]
I wonder what it was supposed to be?
My dad used to talk
about places like that.
He said back a long time ago
when they first came up from Earth
and started building here,
the moon was gonna be this big deal.
Like a paradise.
The kinda place people on Earth
only dreamed about.
But once they found Omega,
everything just stopped.
Now there's all this stuff out here
that never got finished.
Can you imagine
if they'd finished building it?
[Addison] Yeah.
That'd be really cool.
[Borney]
Are the buildings on Earth that big?
[Addison] Yeah, most of them are bigger.
Wow. Hey, what else is different?
-Between the Earth and the moon?
-Yeah.
Let's see. There's, uh--
There's trees that have leaves
that change color in the fall.
Uh…
Water. You don't have television.
Haven't seen a book since I landed.
You don't really have music,
rain, snow, wind, weather.
I mean, don't they teach you guys
this stuff in school?
[Dylan, Caleb chuckling]
Mmm, no. No, see, school is
where they teach us how to mine helium,
how to deal with low gravity in the mines,
uh, mining helium, and how to handle
helium once it's been mined.
All so a bunch of rich people
can have enough fuel
for their transports to get to Omega.
I mean, it's a really great program. Yeah.
Well, if that's true,
then how do you know so much about Earth?
Because my dad grew up there.
So? Didn't all of your parents
grow up on Earth?
[Dylan] Not mine.
My grandparents did though.
-Uh, Borney over there, his--
-Great-grandparents.
Yeah. Right. Marcus…
Marcus, how long's your family
been on the rock?
A long time.
Well, that doesn't even make any sense.
It's a 20-year contract.
You work in the mines for 20 years,
then you get to take your family to Omega.
[Caleb] That's what they tell you.
What they don't tell you is
every time you're late for a shift…
Or you get a cold…
Or delay production in any way…
[Caleb] They add more and more time
to your contract.
When my old man started in the mines,
he had six years to work off from his dad
before he could even start his own 20.
The whole thing's a giant scam.
I'm sorry. I didn't--
I didn't realize.
Is the sky really blue?
What?
The sky, um, on Earth,
uh, is it really blue?
Yeah.
During the daytime. Blue as can be.
-[Marcus sighs]
-[Borney chuckles]
Wow.
Caleb, what's in the crater?
I don't know.
Whenever my dad talked about it,
all he really said was how important
it was to my mom that I see it.
There was one time he said something
about a brook that splits in two.
A brook? Inside the crater?
[Caleb] He was probably just confused.
-I-I bet there's treasure there.
-You think there's treasure everywhere.
But there is! My brother told me
that the first settlers who came here
brought all sorts of treasure with them.
Then, they hid it in all these places
in the middle of nowhere.
If there was any treasure,
they would have packed it up
and put it on a ship to Omega years ago.
You don't know. When I find treasure,
I'm not letting you have any of it.
And you're gonna get all sad and say,
"Aw, geez, Borney.
Can I please have some treasure?"
And I'm just gonna say, "Sorry, Dylan.
You're just gonna have to put more faith
in me next time,
and then maybe, maybe,
I'll give you some of my next treasure."
If you say treasure one more time,
you're going out the rover without a suit.
T-rea-sure.
-That's it. You're going outside.
-[Caleb] Whoa.
-Hey, hey, hey.
-[Borney chuckles]
[Caleb] Speaking of going outside,
you guys ready to have some real fun?
[air hissing]
[Marcus] Thanks.
-Okay, you ready?
-Yeah.
-[Borney] All right. You're all set.
-Thanks, Borney.
[Borney] Wow,
your suit's a lot nicer than ours.
My dad got it for me.
So, who wants to do the honors?
Marcus, you should go first.
-Yeah.
-[Dylan] Yeah, man. Definitely.
Okay.
[Dylan chuckles]
[Marcus] Okay.
[Marcus sighs]
[breathes shakily]
[Dylan chuckles]
[grunts]
[chuckles]
[Borney] Whoa. Whoa.
[Borney chuckles]
[Caleb chuckles]
[chuckles]
[pants]
[sighs]
[Dylan laughs]
Hey, Caleb. Caleb, look!
-[laughs]
-[Caleb] Whoa. [chuckles]
This is awesome.
-[Marcus laughing]
-[Dylan] Whoo!
-[Borney] Look.
-[Marcus] Whoa.
[Dylan] I'm, like, so high! [laughs]
-Whoa.
-[laughing]
[Borney] Whoa.
[Dylan] Yeah! Whoo! [laughs]
Bet you don't get anything like this
on Earth, huh?
[Dylan] This is amazing! [laughs]
[Borney] Wow, look at that.
Is that Earth?
-Hey, Addison, which part did you live on?
-Dude.
What?
You know what?
We're gonna do something fun. [chuckles]
Tied at the bottom of the ninth,
two outs and a loaded count,
Tollefson is at the plate.
Weaver will try to close out
what has been an electrifying game seven.
[gasps]
This is it, ladies and gents,
and the home crowd knows it!
Oh, you can hear them chanting,
"Weaver, Weaver, Weaver, Weaver, Weaver."
-What is she doing?
-No idea.
[imitates crowd cheering]
Here it is, the wind up.
[Addison grunts]
-[metal clinks]
-[Marcus grunts]
[Addison chuckles]
Tollefson hits a doozy towards the center!
[Marcus laughs]
-[Addison] You gotta catch it!
-It's flying into space.
[scoffs] Well, run the bases.
-The what?
-[Dylan sighs]
This is seriously
one of the most popular games on Earth?
Hmm, yeah. With gravity.
-[Caleb] Seriously?
-[Dylan chuckles]
The moon sucks.
[Marcus] I kinda liked it.
-Hey, where are you going?
-On a walk.
-Don't go too far.
-[Addison] Okay, Dad.
[Dylan sighs]
[sighs]
[pants]
[breathes shakily]
-[oxygen tank blowing]
-[Marcus laughs] Hell yeah!
-Go, Dylan!
-[Borney] Come on!
-Don't go higher!
-[Dylan] Hey, Earth girl.
Check it out! [grunts]
-[Caleb] Oh, my God!
-[Borney] Are you seeing this?
[Dylan] All right, remember,
the name of the game is launch-off,
so the more you launch, the higher you go.
So you wanna crouch all the way down,
and launch as hard as you can
while you open the valve.
Are you sure this is safe?
-Of course I-- Borney, don't be a baby.
-You're a baby.
What the hell are you doing?
Are you trying to get yourselves killed?
Don't be dramatic, okay?
All you gotta do is pump the tank a little
on your way down to slow your fall.
Oh, yeah? And what if the cable snaps?
You'll end up miles away
in the middle of space!
This cable can haul thousands of pounds.
I think we'll be okay.
Also you're wasting oxygen!
It's an extra tank.
Which, I'm not quite sure
if you've noticed, we need out here.
If we don't use it,
it'll just go to waste.
That's the stupidest thing
I've ever heard.
[Dylan sighs]
[Caleb] Wait, Dylan. [sighs]
What do you know?
You thought baseball was fun.
-There's a meteor shower warning!
-Do you see any meteors?
[scoffs]
Come on, Earth girl.
Just admit it. You're scared.
[Addison screams, chuckles]
Whoo!
[laughing]
I like her.
She's neat.
[Addison] Whoo!
[Dylan] Yeah. She's all right.
[Caleb] Way to go, Addison!
[Addison grunts, chuckles]
[grunting]
[chuckles]
So? What'd you think?
I don't know. I guess
you might have been a tiny bit right.
It was just a little bit of fun.
[chuckles]
[both laugh]
[Dylan] You've got this.
Whoa!
This is amazing!
[laughs]
[laughing] Whoa! Whoa!
Whoo-hoo!
Whoa.
You ready?
No, actually,
I think I left something in the rover.
-[Dylan] Three, two, one.
-What?
-Launch!
[Borney laughing]
[Borney] Masters of our own fate!
-[Caleb] You got this, Dylan.
-[Borney] Yeah!
-Whoo-hoo-hoo!
-Yeah!
-[Borney] Yeah!
-[Addison] Whoo!
-[Caleb] She's doing really good, man.
-High-five!
-Whoa. Whoa.
-[Marcus] Whoo-hoo-hoo!
[Borney] Oh, my God.
Yeah!
Whoa, whoa, wait!
Oh!
Whoo!
[laughs]
[Marcus] All right, let's go, Borney.
-Whoo!
-[chuckles, whoops]
-[Addison] Yeah, Borney!
-Whoa.
[panting]
Whoa!
[Borney screaming]
-No, no, no, no, no, no!
-Borney!
Wh-- What do we do?
[Borney] Please! Please!
I wanna come down.
[grunting, panting]
Borney, listen to me,
you have to shut off the tank.
Shut off the valve on the tank. Okay?
The tank! It slipped. I can't reach it.
If we don't do something,
then we're gonna lose him!
-What are we supposed to do?
-I don't know! You tell me!
[Borney] Please.
I wanna come down, please.
-[Marcus] We need to move. Fast.
-[Addison] And do what?
-[Dylan] Marcus, what are you doing?
-[Addison] Marcus!
Mm-hmm.
[Dylan, Caleb panting]
Wait! I'm coming with you.
You need to guide us.
-We need you to be our eyes down here.
-[panting] I…
Come on, Earth girl. We need you.
Okay.
[Caleb grunting, panting]
Marcus, your angle is off.
You need to go to your right!
Once Borney unhooks his tank,
he's gonna start to fall.
You're gonna need to catch him.
We're gonna get him back.
Hey! Hey! We're gonna get him back.
-[Addison] Borney, you're doing great.
-[Borney] I'm scared.
[Addison] Try and stay calm.
Everything's gonna be fine.
-[Borney] Okay.
-[Addison] Come on!
[Dylan, Caleb grunting]
Borney, Marcus is on his way.
Please, I need you to listen to me.
You need to unhook your tank.
-I see him! I see him!
-[Addison] Okay?
Borney, you can do it!
Reach down, grab the strap, then pull.
[Borney screaming]
-[Addison] Marcus! Look out!
-[grunting]
[Borney screams] Marcus!
-Reach for my hand!
-Help me. Help me, please, Marcus.
-I got him.
-[grunts]
[Borney] I-- I can't hold on!
-I can't hold on!
-[Marcus] Borney!
[Borney] Oh, God, help!
[Addison] No! No, no, no, no! [whimpers]
I'm right behind ya!
[all grunting]
Watch out! Watch out!
[Caleb grunts]
[all grunting, screaming]
[Borney screams]
Whoa! Whoa!
[all screaming, grunting]
[panting]
[groans, sighs]
[all grunting]
[Marcus panting]
I think I prefer baseball.
[grunting, coughing]
[Dylan] Borney! Borney! Are you okay?
-I'm fine. I'm fine.
-[Dylan] You're sure?
Okay. Okay.
Hey, you better patch up that strap.
Luckily,
someone grabbed the crack-smacker.
Are you okay?
[Dylan] Yeah. Yeah, we're fine.
I think we have to go back.
-What?
-[Marcus grunts]
To the dome. We have to go back.
Look. I get it, okay? I get it.
You were right.
It was stupid.
Do you really think I care
about being right?
It's just math. We used too much oxygen.
You don't know that. [pants]
[Addison] You said that you only brought
one extra tank. We lost two.
Plus whatever you guys used
getting out there and back.
We wouldn't even have enough
to make it to the crater.
[pants] Oh, my God.
We can figure something out. Right?
We all played. It's not your fault.
Wait.
What if we can get more?
How?
You still have that projector thingy?
[Dylan] Wait. How is that gonna work?
Look. Come with me. I'll show you.
[Dylan, Caleb panting]
-No, turn to the left.
-I…
This is left.
-Are you looking for the-- Oh!
-Yeah.
-What are we looking for?
-Ooh! Wait. Right there.
-Hey!
-[Dylan] Well, zoom right there! Please?
[Addison] What is this?
[Caleb] That's where we get more oxygen.
It's an old outpost
from the first settlement.
It's where miners used to get supplies
for long-range digs.
Do you think there's anything left?
[sighs]
[Caleb] There has to be. It's the only way
we make it to the crater.
[Addison] Dylan, even if this works,
we're gonna be out here
a lot longer than we planned.
[Dylan] Okay, but there's time.
Lockdown's not even halfway over.
[Addison] I'm just saying.
At some point, we're gonna have to sleep.
[Dylan] Right, sure.
Let's make sure we can breathe first.
So if we're not going back to the dome,
then where are we going?
We're going to an outpost.
It's where we're gonna get more oxygen.
An outpost? What outpost?
There's nothing out here except for--
-Wait a minute, not the outpost?
-Here we go.
Are you kidding me? That's the outpost!
-We can't go there.
-[Dylan groans]
Borney, those are just stories.
Wait. [chuckles] What?
Space ghosts, that's what.
-We gotta turn around.
-No. We're not turning around.
Borney,
there is no such thing as space ghosts.
You don't know.
You guys think you know everything.
-My brother told me--
-No, for crying out loud!
You know what? Your brother? He sucks.
-Take that back.
-[Dylan] No.
I said, take it back.
No. Because he messes
with your head. Okay?
He tells you all these stories
so that you'll walk around
scared of your own shadow all the time.
-The guy's a total loser!
-You're a loser!
-Fine! He's a bigger loser!
-All right. That's enough.
At least I don't have any cowards
in my family.
What'd you say?
-Come here!
-[Caleb] Hey!
-Stop!
-[Dylan] Wanna talk now?
-Don't talk about my brother!
-Hey, Dylan! Stop!
-You wanna talk now?
-Get off me!
[both grunting]
-Enough!
-You know, what? Get off me!
-[Caleb] Get off him.
-You hear what he said?
Hey, everybody knock it off!
[panting]
Is this how you guys wanna spend
our last few days together?
Come on.
[Borney] I'm sorry.
Really.
I shouldn't have said that.
Yeah. Me too.
-I love you, buddy. [chuckles]
-[Borney scoffs]
[Borney] Yeah, yeah. I love you too.
[chuckles]
[Addison]
You really think there's oxygen in there?
[Caleb] I mean, it should be.
These outposts were supply centers.
[Marcus]
But that was a long time ago. Right?
[Addison] How long?
[metallic thud]
[door beeps, opens]
[all breathing shakily]
-[Caleb] Hey.
-[Marcus] What the--
[Caleb] Uh…
Uh, what?
Oh. [sighs]
The sooner we turn the lights on,
the sooner we get the oxygen tanks, right?
-Yeah.
-Right.
-[Dylan gasps]
-[Addison] Come on.
Careful.
Space ghost!
[all screaming]
-[Dylan] Oh, my God!
-[Addison screams]
[screaming]
[screams, grunts]
[electricity powers up]
Huh?
[Marcus] Hmm.
These space ghosts have nice taste.
-[Borney] What the…
-What is this place?
This isn't an outpost. It's a model home.
[Borney] Huh?
[Caleb] A what?
Whenever developers on Earth would build
new communities, like, nice ones,
they'd usually always start out with
one house that was, like, a showcase.
[Borney] This is what the houses here
would have looked like?
It's really nice.
I mean, these things are
super creepy, but…
At least we don't have to sleep
in the rover tonight.
Uh, you're still sleeping in the rover.
You snore.
I just can't wait
to get out of these suits. [chuckles]
[Addison] Whoa.
This place is supposed to be packed
with surplus equipment.
Where is everything?
[Addison] There's a bunch of rooms
we have to check.
[Dylan] Yeah, I guess.
Who was Borney talking about?
-Uh, in the rover. Who was he--
-Yeah, I know what you meant.
What do you wanna know for?
God, you're so--
Just forget I even asked.
There's no oxygen here.
[Dylan] All right, fine.
Remember how I said my dad still had
six years left to work off from his dad
before he could even start his own 20?
Well, one day, he just--
He just couldn't take it anymore.
He decided to sneak onto
one of the shuttles back to Earth.
They told my mom
they found him right after takeoff.
Don't do that.
-Don't do what?
-Don't-- Don't--
Don't stand there and look at me
like you feel bad for me, okay?
You wanna feel bad for someone?
Feel bad for Borney.
'Cause I love the kid,
but he's not built for this place.
Marcus?
He probably got born with that heart
because his family's
been up here too long.
Screwed him all up.
So you wanna feel bad for someone?
Feel bad for them,
because I don't need your pity.
Pity? I wasn't…
God, you guys think that you're the only
people who have problems in your life.
What, you think my life is perfect?
-I don't know.
-[Addison] No, you don't know.
I bet you don't know a thing about me.
I'm just the girl who helped you
and your friends steal a rover
so that you could have
your little adventure.
Right?
[sighs]
I don't feel bad for you.
I was just trying to get to know you.
[footsteps departing]
[door opens]
I don't snore.
Are you kidding me?
Every time you take a nap,
the ground shakes on Omega.
That's not true.
How would you know?
You're too busy sleeping.
I'd know.
Whoa!
That's a lot of stuff.
[sighs] This is gonna take forever.
[Marcus grunts]
Hey, do you think
Caleb's having a good time?
I mean, I know he's sad about leaving,
about his dad.
But I just…
I want him to have a good time, you know?
I know.
[clattering]
[roars, laughs]
Promise me you'll always take your pills.
Promise!
Okay. Promise.
[Caleb] Dad?
You in here?
[Michael] What?
Dad,
why were you just sitting in the dark?
[Michael] The math doesn't work.
[Caleb] What?
There's not enough time.
The math doesn't work.
Dad,
what are you talking about?
When your mom was pregnant,
she was so scared you'd end up stuck here.
Turn 18
before we finished out the contract.
But the math worked, see?
As long as we worked hard, stayed focused.
But your mom got sick.
And I took too much time.
Figured I'd make it up.
Work it off before you turned 18.
Before they put 20 years on you.
And I tried, buddy, I did. I tried.
-[feedback on comm]
-[Borney] Hey! Hey, Caleb, are you there?
Any luck?
Oh, yeah!
And we didn't just find the oxygen tanks.
We found a feast!
[both laugh]
-[Dylan groans]
-[Borney] What a meal.
-That was amazing.
-[Marcus] Mmm, mmm.
[sighs] I never-- I never knew there were
so many different types of food.
[Addison] Want some?
[burps]
-[Marcus] Nice one.
-That was impressive.
I don't think I'm ever going to eat
anything ever again.
There's so many flavors right in my mouth
right now, I don't even know what to do.
-What is that?
-Um…
It's called, uh, "freeze-dried ice cream."
Is it good?
I think it is the most amazing thing
I've ever tasted.
-Here, let me try it.
-Wait.
No, let me try it.
-Give me some.
-Hey.
You can't hog it all. Dude! Dylan!
-Oh, my God! This is amazing.
-You can't--
-You can't hog it all to yourself.
-Come on. Give me some.
-Oh.
-Oh, yeah.
-Dude, come on. One piece.
-[Caleb laughs]
So, the whole freaking world
was actually at war with each other.
Literally millions of people died.
That's insane.
[Addison] Yeah, I mean,
that's not the only part.
The entire thing happened
again 20 years later.
You wouldn't believe the stuff
that you find in history books.
You guys would love it.
It's just all of this stuff that dates
back, like, thousands of years.
All these different cultures
and belief systems and…
It's all so beautiful and so sad and so…
I don't know. It's just all of this stuff
really happened.
To people who thought it was the most
important thing in the entire universe.
And Earth was everything to them.
Now, it's like all anybody cares about is
when they get to go to Omega.
My brother always really loved history.
You have a brother?
Yeah, his name is Charlie.
He's ten.
He's on a transport ship with my mom
to Omega right now.
See,
when my parents got divorced…
it wasn't enough for my mom to just move
out of the house like a normal person.
She actually chose to spend 75 years
in a cryogenic sleep,
so she'd never have to see my dad again.
And my dad,
for some reason,
just couldn't let her have the last word.
So he just had to leave Earth too.
So, here we are.
She brought Charlie with her
onto the transport ship last year.
I lost my best friend.
Sorry.
Yeah, well, I don't need your pity.
[laughs, sniffles]
[beeping]
Hey, hey. Borney,
be careful over there. Don't--
[screams]
Borney.
[electronic voice]
Welcome to the Alpha Project.
You are one of the lucky few
who were selected to receive
the once-in-a-lifetime opportunity
to purchase one of our luxury condos
here on the lunar surface.
Are you excited?
You're listening to Alpha Radio.
Let's take a trip into the past
and listen to some golden oldies.
["Miracle Mile" playing on speakers]
Geez. When is this from?
Don't look at me.
I'm from Earth, and I've never heard this.
[Borney sighs] Man,
I wish they kept building.
This would've been
a really nice place to live.
[Dylan] This place was never meant for us.
[Borney] Okay, but no one's ever gonna
use this place again.
[Caleb] Listen to me.
This place is every promise they ever made
and never meant to keep.
Just like the contracts people signed.
They could've made it so much better here,
and they just didn't care.
So why should we?
[Borney chuckles]
Yeah.
-Yeah.
-[Addison] Yeah!
-Masters of our own fate! [laughs]
-Yeah!
♪ I'd be all right
If I could just see you ♪
♪ Come up for air
Come up for air ♪
[grunting]
-[laughing]
-Yeah!
[Addison] Whoo!
Hi.
Nice to meet you. Hi. Nice to meet you.
[song continues]
[grunts]
[Dylan screams]
♪ I feel the air upon my face ♪
[Addison] Whoo! [laughs]
♪ Forget the mess I'm in ♪
♪ Hold me again
Don't count mistakes ♪
♪ I lost track of them ♪
[grunts]
-[glass shatters]
-[laughs]
Whoo-hoo! [laughs]
[Dylan] No, no, no.
[Caleb, Dylan grunting]
[laughing]
No, no, no, Marcus!
Those are the life support controls.
Oh.
Good catch.
-[Addison laughs]
-[Marcus grunts]
[all laughing]
[Caleb] Yeah!
♪ Come up for air
Come up for air ♪
♪ Come up ♪
♪ Come up for air
Come up for air ♪
♪ Come up ♪
♪ Get outside
Get all over the world ♪
♪ You learn to love
What you get in return ♪
♪ It may be permanent
It may be peace of mind ♪
♪ But you have to slow down
And breathe one breath at a time ♪
♪ So come up ♪
[song continues]
[all cheering]
[both screaming]
[all screaming]
Yeah! Yeah!
[song fades, ends]
[snoring]
[footsteps approaching]
Can't sleep?
Figure I'll be sleeping plenty
soon enough.
[Caleb sighs]
[Dylan] That is not a cookie.
[Addison] What?
Because I already had one.
[Caleb] He talks in his sleep a lot.
[Addison] You're kidding.
It's really weird.
Most people mumble. Dylan has arguments.
[chuckles]
They're gonna miss you.
[sighs] I know.
The first time I met Dylan,
it was the night my mom died.
Then I went to the commissary.
I'd been crying nonstop for hours and,
I guess,
all of a sudden I just realized
how hungry I was.
It was like after all that,
if I could just get a sandwich,
maybe everything would be okay.
But when I got to the commissary,
everything was locked for the night.
What did you do?
Well, um, I was about
to head back to the dorms
when all of a sudden Dylan comes out
of the air vent above the door.
[chuckles]
He said he'd been breaking in for months
to steal fruit tarts for his mom.
[chuckles] So we snuck back inside
and spent the rest of the night
in a giant refrigerator eating sandwiches.
[chuckles]
I didn't even know who he was,
and he still sat there with me
the whole night.
Why'd you tell me all that?
Because I think
it's gonna be hard for him.
When I'm gone.
Harder for him than the others.
He might need someone to stay up with him,
eat some sandwiches. [chuckles]
Hmm, I barely know him.
Well, he didn't know me either.
[sighs]
You know, we're kind of the same.
What do you mean?
Well, neither of us really gets to be
who we are anymore.
We're both something different now.
I'm just the girl from Earth,
and you're just the boy
whose parents died.
I already told you,
it's not supposed to be green.
[Addison, Caleb chuckling]
[Caleb] Yeah.
Hey, are we there yet?
[all] No.
We're five minutes closer
than the last time you asked though.
Okay, well, how much further?
The map only says
about another mile or so.
[alarm beeping]
What's going on?
Hey, what's happening?
I don't-- I don't know. It just--
What?
What did you do?
I didn't do anything. [sighs]
It's an old model. It just--
[sighs] Come on.
[sighs] We're so screwed.
[Dylan] Come on, come on, come on.
[Caleb] Okay.
How much oxygen did we get from the depot?
Not enough to make it back
to the colony on foot.
Well, how about to get to the crater?
[Dylan] Oh, yeah,
we got enough for that, but…
I don't know.
[distress signal blaring]
Hey, hey. What are you doing?
-That's the distress signal.
-[Addison] Yeah.
We're in a broken-down rover
in the middle of nowhere.
-Oh, my God.
-[groans]
We're gonna be in so much trouble
when they catch us out here.
We're gonna be in even more trouble
if they don't.
Look, the good news is
that the rescue vehicles can't leave
until the dome's lockdown is over.
We've got plenty of time
to get to the crater and back.
Don't you guys really wanna know
what's out there?
Don't you?
[panting]
[Michael]
I need you to promise me something.
Will you promise me?
Okay.
Anything ever happens to me,
you promise me you'll get out there
to the crater, like we talked about.
Wait, Dad. What's gonna happen to you?
Nothing.
I just--
I promised your mom.
The night she died,
I held her hand,
and I promised her you'd see it.
So you promise me now.
You promise me you'll go.
Okay. I promise.
[Michael] Okay, no matter what.
And you look for the place with the brook.
It splits, it goes in two.
That's where you look. That's the spot.
Dad, I don't know what that means. I--
It's okay, you will.
You'll see.
Okay?
Good.
Good man.
[Michael groans]
Hey.
I love you, Caleb.
More than anything.
You know that, right?
Yeah, Dad. Love you too.
My baby boy.
[Dylan panting]
[Dylan] Hey, guys.
I think we're here.
Come on. [pants]
[all panting]
[Borney grunts]
[Dylan] We made it.
-[Marcus] What do you think it is?
-[Caleb] Wow.
[Dylan] We really did it. [chuckles]
We're here, man.
[Caleb] Yeah.
Hey, last one down
doesn't get any treasure.
[Marcus] W-Wait, Borney.
[Borney] Oh, whoa.
Whoa. Whoa. [chuckles]
Whoa. [chuckles] Whoa. Whoa. Whoa.
Marcus?
-[Addison] Whoo!
-[Marcus] Whoa!
You ever have this much fun on Earth?
[Addison]
I've never had this much fun anywhere.
[Addison, Marcus laughing]
Hey, you coming?
Yeah.
Okay.
[Dylan laughing] Whoo! Whoo!
[Caleb grunts]
[Caleb] Yeah.
[chuckling] Whoa.
[Dylan] Caleb! This is awesome!
Yeah!
[Caleb, Dylan laughing]
-[Caleb] Whoa.
-[Dylan] Whoa.
[Borney] Hey, Marcus. Any luck?
[Marcus] I'm still looking.
[Addison] Hey, guys. Come look at this.
[Dylan] What does it mean?
[Marcus] Guys,
I found the control for the door.
[Caleb] Guess we'll find out.
[door opens]
[Dylan sighs]
[Marcus] You first, Caleb.
Hey, you got this.
[Marcus panting]
[panting]
[Addison exhales]
[Caleb grunts]
[Dylan sighs]
[Borney] Oh, come on.
[Dylan] This can't be it.
It's just a giant empty room.
I think we're at the wrong place.
[sighs]
Maybe whatever used to
be here is just gone.
[sighs]
Wow.
"On gilded wings
we have reached the stars.
But let us never forget the skies
we left behind."
[Addison exhales]
What are you doing?
I've been in a room like this before.
Just give me a second.
[gasps]
[Caleb] Wow. [chuckles]
[Addison chuckling]
[Borney] Cool!
What's going on?
[Borney] I think we're gonna die.
[Dylan] We're not gonna die, Borney.
[Addison] Just give it a second.
-[Marcus gasps] Are you guys seeing this?
-[Addison chuckles]
[birds chirping]
[Borney] Marcus. Marcus, look!
[Marcus] It's beautiful.
Wow.
[Borney] Whoa.
[Addison chuckling]
[Marcus] I can't believe it.
[Dylan] Is that--
That's Earth.
That's home.
[chuckles]
[gasping]
[Addison chuckling]
Look!
[Marcus] It is blue. [chuckles]
[Borney] See? I told you guys
there'd be treasure.
-[Dylan chuckles, sighs]
-[Addison giggles]
[water running]
[electricity humming]
Huh?
-What?
-[Marcus] No.
[Borney] No. No, what happ--
What happened?
[Marcus] Is that all there is?
[Addison] I don't know.
-[Borney] No, no, no. No. No!
-[Marcus] Make it come back.
-You can make it come back, right?
-Where did it go?
-[Addison] Look, I can try.
-[Marcus] Please.
Hey. Hey, Caleb, what did you find?
[Marcus shushing]
[sighs]
Hey, your dad would've wanted this.
-[Caleb sniffles]
-He would've been proud.
Don't say that.
What?
Hey, Caleb, stop.
Look, I get it's hard. Okay? I get it.
But, you can't just--
It wasn't an accident.
In the mines.
What happened wasn't an accident.
My dad knew about the death benefit.
He knew if anything happened to him
that I'd get to go to Omega.
When we get back, I'm telling Ms. Slater.
What?
Maybe she'll cancel the contract,
revoke the benefit.
I could stay.
Look, everything about this sucks.
But none of that matters.
Because you're the one that gets to go.
Whatever you think your dad did,
he did it because he loved you.
Dude, I would give anything
to get off this rock.
We all would. And you know that.
But we're gonna spend
the rest of our lives here.
And that's fine.
You know why?
Because when you go,
a part of us gets to go too.
You're gonna be out there
for the rest of us.
It's gonna be amazing.
-You're gonna forget all about this place.
-No, I won't.
[Dylan] Yes, you will.
And you should.
Caleb, you've got
so much more ahead of you.
So many things you're gonna see and do.
You're gonna be a leader.
Somebody people depend on.
Somebody that goes
where other people are scared to go.
You don't think we're gonna
let you ruin that, do you?
-[Marcus groans]
-[body thuds]
[Borney] Marcus! Hey!
Oh, my God!
-Hey! Marcus!
-[Dylan] Hey, it's okay.
Hey. I'm okay. I'm okay.
-[grunts] What happened?
-[Marcus] It's okay.
His heart rate is way too low.
No. No, no, but he took all his pills.
You guys have never been
outside before, right?
[Dylan] No.
The low gravity could be affecting
his blood pressure.
So give him another pill.
I can't. They're back at the rover.
-Oh, no.
-Why didn't you say anything, Marcus?
I didn't wanna ruin the trip.
-Please. No, no, no.
-Okay. Come on.
We need to get him back
to the rover, like, now.
Okay. Let's move.
-Okay. Come on.
-[grunting]
[all grunting]
[Marcus groans]
[Dylan] Right behind you, Marcus.
Come on, yeah. Push. Go.
-[Marcus grunts]
-Take my hand.
[Addison] What was that?
-[Marcus grunting]
-[Dylan grunts, pants]
[grunts, sighs]
[whooshing]
The meteor shower.
Run!
[all panting]
Marcus, I've got you.
[straining]
-[Borney] Look out. Whoa! Whoa! Whoa!
-[Addison screams, grunts]
[Borney] Come on. Ow!
[Caleb] Okay, come on!
[Addison screams]
The rover's right there.
-We need to make a run for it.
-We're never gonna make it.
Yes, we will. Borney, look at me.
-I can't.
-You want us to die out here?
-Do you want Marcus to die?
-No.
Then tell me you can do this.
I can do it.
-[Caleb] Tell me you can do it!
-I can do it!
Then run!
[panting]
[Addison] Go! I'll watch your backs.
-[Dylan] Come on.
-[Caleb] Come on.
Let's go!
[grunting, panting]
This way!
[Dylan] Come on! Come on!
[Addison screams]
[screams]
[Borney grunting]
-[door lock beeps]
-Hey, Borney. We're right behind you.
[Borney] Come on, guys. We gotta go.
We gotta get Marcus inside the rover!
Hey. Hey, where's Addison?
[Marcus groans]
Addison? Addison, where are you?
Addison!
-Over there!
-Addison, if you can hear us,
-we're coming to get you, okay?
-Let's go.
Okay.
No! Dylan, don't come out here.
Dylan, can you hear me? Then answer me!
[Dylan] Hey!
You having fun yet?
-Right. So, let's go.
-Get down!
No!
Dylan!
[Borney grunts] We gotta--
-But, Borney. The door--
-You're good.
-[Marcus] The door. Wait.
-No. No, it's fine.
It's fine. The door is closed.
You're good.
[screams]
Okay.
[straining]
I need to seal the cracks
before they spread.
-But is it gonna hold?
-I don't know.
We can't stay here.
We need to get him up right now.
-Okay.
-[Caleb] We have to go.
[straining]
Okay. [sighs] Everything's gonna be fine.
Where is everybody?
-Ready?
-Okay.
Let's go.
[grunting]
[Caleb, Addison panting]
[Caleb grunts]
Oh, my God!
[Caleb, Addison panting]
I got you. Come on.
-Let's get--
-Get him up.
[straining]
Let's go!
[Caleb grunting]
[banging on door]
[Addison] Come on, Borney! Open up! Bor--
-[grunts]
-[door whirs]
[Addison sighs, pants]
What happened?
-[Borney breathes shakily] Is he--
-He's fine.
[rumbling]
-He's fi--
-[Borney gasps]
He's fine. It's gonna--
The rescue vehicles
are gonna be here soon.
No, they won't.
The storm.
It means they're still on lockdown.
They aren't coming.
[crying] No. Don't say that.
-[Caleb] I'm sorry.
-No, don't--
Don't say that.
Okay, they're-- They'll be here.
Right, it's gonna--
Everything's gonna be fine.
-[rumbling]
-[Borney whimpering]
[Addison] They'll be here.
[Marcus] Addison…
what happens when we run out of oxygen?
Well…
As the levels get lower…
your suit will start
to recycle carbon dioxide.
And you'll just start to get really tired.
Once you're asleep, the suit powers down.
It will try to make the oxygen last
as long as possible.
Then at some point, you'll just…
slip away.
It's peaceful.
Well…
that sounds okay, I guess.
[chuckles]
[Addison, Marcus chuckling]
[sniffles]
[breathes shakily]
Caleb?
Huh?
Hey, man. I'm right here.
How long was I asleep?
For a while.
A few hours at least.
The rescue vehicles?
They're on their way.
Everything's gonna be just fine.
You're a pretty bad liar. You know that?
[chuckles]
Are they--
[Caleb] They're just sleeping.
I never should have made you guys
come out here.
[Dylan sighs]
You're an idiot.
These were the best two days of my life.
Same goes for them.
We got to see the sky, man.
All that blue.
It's the most amazing thing
I've ever seen.
So quit pissing and moaning
about how bad you feel.
[chuckles]
[Dylan] Besides,
you didn't make us do anything.
I would've dragged you out here
whether you wanted to go or not.
[both chuckling]
-That's probably true.
-You're damn right it's true.
And don't laugh.
You're wasting oxygen.
[both laughing]
You'll always be my best friend.
No matter what.
I know.
[suits beeping, powering down]
Dylan?
[suit beeps, powers down]
Dylan, what's going on? Dylan?
Dylan.
[breathing heavily]
[suit beeps, powers down]
-[comm beeps]
-[rescue] Lunar rover?
This is rescue vehicle two. Do you copy?
We have visual contact
and are approaching.
Please acknowledge.
Dylan?
[sighs]
Guys?
Huh? [grunts]
[nurse] Easy. Not too fast.
Your body's been through a lot.
[sighs]
Is everyone okay?
Everyone's fine.
The trip was a complete success.
Trip?
[grunts]
What trip?
Aboard the transport.
You're on Omega, Caleb.
What?
No.
No! No! No! No!
-I have to go.
-[nurse] You can't.
-I have to go-- I can't--
-Hey. It's all right.
I was just on the rover. I fell asleep.
I didn't get to say goodbye.
[birds chirping]
[nurse] It's difficult at first.
You're going to need time to adjust.
This may help.
What is it?
Messages from the Lunar colony.
From the last 75 years while you slept.
There's a foster family
you'll be staying with.
They're coming by this afternoon.
They're very excited to meet you.
[sighs]
[device beeps]
[Dylan] Hey, man. Uh, you're not gonna
hear this for a pretty long time,
which is really weird.
Anyway, there's some folks here
who wanted to say hi.
-[Addison] Hi, Caleb!
-[Borney] Uh, where do I talk?
[Marcus] Uh,
just put your face near the microphone.
[Borney] Oh, oh, oh.
There it is. Hi, Caleb!
[Marcus] Uh, hi, Caleb.
I hope Omega's nice.
[Dylan] All right, guys. Come on, come on.
We're on a clock here.
Anyway, I wanted you to know
that everyone's okay
so that you didn't worry when you woke up.
-Addison talked to her dad and--
-[Addison] Actually, I yelled at him.
[Dylan] Yeah, she did.
He said that they'd let me use
the transmitter once a year.
Apparently, that's way more than usual.
So, you'll have plenty of catching up
to do when you wake up.
And, listen, don't be sad. Okay?
Things are gonna be okay.
For you, for us, for everyone.
I love you, man!
[Addison] I love you too!
[Dylan] Addison loves you too.
[device beeps]
[Dylan] Hey, buddy.
I can't believe it's been a year already.
[chuckles]
I don't know what you said
to Addison before you left,
but the girl won't leave me alone.
All year she's been showing up
with sandwiches.
I guess it's not so bad though.
Hey. Everybody misses you, man.
We talk about you all the time.
[sighs]
[device beeps]
[Dylan]
It's hard to believe it's been so long.
It feels like just yesterday
we were out there planning our trip.
Hi. Nice to meet you.
[Dylan] And now here I am working
down in the mines.
At least all that wonderful schooling
is paying off.
Yeah.
[Dylan] It's not so bad though.
Borney and I are on the same crew.
And Marcus is trying to get his foreman
to let him rotate over.
-Addison keeps staging these protests…
-This way.
…demanding changes in the contracts.
The funny thing is,
we were just walking
down the hall one day…
[laughing] …and she held my hand.
And then we just--
Neither one of us let go.
Caleb! She did it!
She actually did it!
She finally got them to close
all the loopholes in the contract.
No more passing down unfinished hours
from one generation to the next.
And now she's got Borney
helping her form a commission
to restart all those
old construction projects.
So Borney wears a suit and tie now.
Yeah, but we still give him a hard time
about the space ghosts though.
[device beeps]
[adult Dylan] I know I'm early this year,
but I couldn't wait.
I asked Addison to marry me.
She said yes!
Man, I think back to that day
she and I met in the cafeteria.
We were all so nervous
about bringing the Earth girl along.
Guess what.
Marcus started a baseball league.
I still don't get the game,
but kids here seem to like it.
Now he's got a whole team
bugging him about his pills.
We're just glad the big guy is still here.
Addison's pregnant.
I'm gonna be a dad.
-[passerby] Hi.
-[adult Dylan] Can you believe that?
-[Caleb] Where can I find it?
-Follow that path…
[adult Dylan] I look around now
at everything that's changed,
the lives, the homes we built.
It's because of you.
You brought us out of that dome
and showed us what this place could be.
That's the world we made.
It's funny.
The more that time goes by,
the more I realize just how much
that trip really meant.
There are these moments
that only happen once.
Those are the ones you hold on to.
They become the stories that you tell.
That way you never really have
to say goodbye.
[elderly Dylan] It's so strange to think
of you out there still frozen in time.
You have no idea how much joy
it's brought us all these years
to imagine the incredible things
you'll do, all the adventures you'll have.
Hey, I'm taking my grandkids out
to the crater next week.
Can you imagine that?
We have good lives here, Caleb.
We became the masters of our own fate.
And now, my friend,
it's time for you
to become the master of yours.
[sighs]
[device beeps]
[birds chirping]
[sighs]
Hi.
Hello.
I was told I could find you here.
I think this belongs to you.
[gasps]
Your sister was a friend of mine.
Wait a second. Are you Caleb?
My sister talked about you a lot
on my transmitter.
I think she must have snuck this
into my bag before I left.
She'd probably want you to have it.
[chuckles]
I never thought I'd see this again.
I think you and I are gonna have
a lot to talk about.
[chuckles]
[sighs]
Did you guys really steal a rover
and go across the moon?
Sure did.
Addison said you almost blew
one of your friends into space.
[chuckles] We didn't blow him into space.
We were just playing launch-off.
-What's launch-off?
-It's a game.
See what you had to do is,
you get an oxygen tank,
turn it upside down, and you hold it
in front of you as tight as you can,
like this.
Why do you turn it upside down?
That's where you get the propulsion.
This game seems like a terrible idea.
Yeah. Your sister thought so too.
You know,
I'm gonna need someone to show me around.
You think you're up for it?
Really? Me?
What are you doing tomorrow?
[Caleb] Well,
I guess we're going on an adventure.