Downloaded from
YTS.MX
Official YIFY movies site:
♪ On the first part
Of the journey ♪
♪  I was looking
At all the life ♪
♪  There were plants and birds
And rocks and things ♪
♪  There was sand
And hills and rings ♪
♪  The first thing I met
Was a fly with a buzz ♪
♪  And the sky with no clouds ♪
♪  The heat was hot
And the ground was dry ♪
♪  But the air
Was full of sound ♪
♪ I've been through the desert
On a horse with no name ♪
♪  It felt good
To be out of the rain ♪
♪  In the desert you can
Remember your name ♪
♪  'Cause there ain't no one
For to give you no pain ♪
♪  La, la, la la
La la la la, la, la ♪
Starting to get backed up here.
Well, let's get going.
How's it going, JJ?
Almost there.
Yo, get him to open the trunk.
Jack Jack?
On it!
Turn off your truck
and step out.
Why?
National Security.
Shame on you, bastard.
You are helping the infidels.
Could you kindly turn off
the truck and step out?
Make me if you can.
Is there a problem here?
Time's up!
Eddie. Chow chow?
Eddie's ready. Tom?
Don't talk to me, talk to John.
John! Chow chow?
What's in the back
of the truck?
Jack Jack?
Fishy, John.
Yeah, hold tight. Comin' in.
- He says
it's empty.
- Don't fool...
Tell him to open it!
- Tell him to stop!
- Jack Jack?
- Tell him
to fuckin'--
Jack Jack!
Fuck!
Move! Move! Move!
Now! Move, move!
All blue
personnel to report to
communal area for 1800 hours.
Aircraft engine maintenance
required on runway five.
Thank you, bro.
I heard
he's a solid guy.
We'll get him ready,
huh? Jizzy?
Looks like
he got some fresh panties on.
Sergeant Kinley?
Steve Kersher, uh,
I'm the new ECO.
Nice to meet you.
Kersher? Pleasure.
Hey, JJ. Meet your new junior.
Hey, I'm JJ.
Hey, what's up? Steve.
-Introduce him to the boys.
-Sure.
Come meet the guys.
-Guys. Kersher.
He's our new ECO.
- Hey, Kinley.
I got your interpreter.
'Sup? I'm Steve.
They all military trained?
Some more than others,
but they all
been through basic.
I need someone in shape.
You see that bald one
with the beard?
I'd bite that one.
Now, he speaks four languages
that are worth speaking.
He can be kinda tricky, though.
He won't be pushed around.
Some units don't like him,
you know,
they won't work with him.
All right,
have him step forward.
Hey, Ahmed.
Step forward.
Do you smoke?
No, not for me, sir. No.
Why you want this job?
I need the money, sir.
And what was your profession
before this?
Mechanic.
You good with cars?
Anything with an engine.
Oh, yeah? Well, what's...
what's this?
That's an engine, sir.
You patronizing me, Ahmed?
No. No.
I would never patronize
an officer, sir.
How long you been here?
Five years.
Do you like it?
It's a job, sir.
Well, Akhmed,
this unit specializes
in finding Taliban munitions
and explosive sites.
Basically, we get into trouble.
Sadly...
we lost our last interpreter.
Understood.
And it's "Ahmed", sir.
Oh. Yeah.
Well, it's "Sergeant",
not "sir".
Hey, guys, meet Ahmed,
our new interpreter.
- Hey. What up, bro?
- What's up, Ahmed?
Don't disappoint and turn out
to be a pain in the ass.
Not me, sir.
Fucking gross.
I'd kill for some swine.
Do you only think
about food?
And he just ate.
There's nothing here
a man can eat.
Tom, what does that eat?
What it always eats, sausage.
There's nothing wrong
with a little sausage.
You just keep telling
yourself that, Chow Chow.
All right, all right, children.
School time.
You know,
if you're looking for weapons,
you are not gonna
find any here.
Oh, yeah? How do you know?
I know what goes on
behind these doors.
Ah.
The Oracle doth speak.
Again, Haadee.
What's going on?
U.S. Military brother.
I can see that.
What do you want?
They are looking
for Taliban firearms.
I have nothing to do
with those murderers.
I believe you.
But they need to believe you.
They're going to make
their way in.
But they will be as quick
as it takes to confirm
your innocence.
And your house
will be left prettier.
Than the alternative.
All right.
Clear!
All clear.
Clear.
All clear, too.
The fuck is this place?
What's it look like?
It's a fuckin' sports bar.
What's he saying?
He says
your intel is poo-poo.
Oh, another Oracle.
I'm just tired
of this bullshit.
All right, well,
I'm gonna stay here
and have a smoke.
I'll see you guys at sunrise.
How come you know so much
about what cooks here?
I'm a man about town.
So, this is how you spend
your lazy afternoons?
You're a dark horse, Ahmed.
All right.
Let's get outta here.
Don't lick, squeeze,
or pop anything.
Jizzy,
don't touch that pipe.
Well, that was fun.
On to the next one, I guess.
Jackpot!
Fuckin' Tali HQ.
We got 'em surrounded.
Haadee,
pull security for a second.
What a quaint
little house on the prairie.
You and I
could retire here, Jizzy.
And we can adopt a labradoodle
and milk something.
What are these coordinates?
It's turning into a fuck fest.
Where is this intel
coming from?
Straight outta head office.
-What'd you wanna do, John?
-I wanna stop wasting time.
Anyway, we got a couple hours.
You got that barbeque,
Chow Chow?
What do you think?
Impressive.
You know, whatever they may
say about us, Ahmed,
we're not all animals,
apart from Chow Chow,
of course.
To Jack Jack.
When do you think Steve
should get his first beer?
Yeah, I don't know.
When do you get to drink
your first beer, Steve?
Uh, whenever you say so, sir.
-Bon appetit.
Merci, mon general.
To the boots
I hope to fill, boys.
How do you like
them apples, sir?
I love these
goddamn apples, John.
I wouldn't normally bother you
with issues like this, sir,
but you're the only one who'll
get anything done around here.
Oh, yeah? What's the problem?
We keep going out
and achieving nothing.
I keep putting my men
in constant danger.
It just feels like we're moving
sand around a sandbox.
I heard your needle got stuck
on this point before.
Look, you've been tasked
with finding IED factories.
You can get creative
in finding them, yeah?
Do it your way.
I don't think
you'll like my way.
I don't think it's important
whether I like it or not,
especially if I don't know
about it.
I really enjoyed
not having this conversation.
You have a good day.
I enjoyed not having
this conversation
with you also, sir.
We are waiting on you
to get back, sir.
ETA, 23:00.
I know, sir.
Declan?
John?
Come through for me?
I feel used by you, John.
You only ever want me
for my brains.
Oh.
It's not like you're
a generous lover.
Well, that's 'cause you never
bought me dinner first.
And, no,
I did not come through.
It took me years
to get these stripes
and I'm not peeling them off
for you.
And since you didn't have
a conversation with Vokes
I just saw you having,
it would be impossible for me
to give you this list
of unvetted targets.
You always play hard to get.
All you gotta do is chase me.
Aircraft engine
maintenance required
on runway six.
What you doin'?
-Oh. Tightening
the fan belt, sir.
-You recognize this guy?
Yes, I do.
All right, come with me.
That's him.
That's Faraj.
Let's do this.
Stay still.
Don't say a fuckin' word.
Oh, relax.
We're gonna go for a ride.
- Come on. Move.
Easy, easy.
-Move. Move. Go.
-Easy.
Let's go!
Go, go, go, go, go!
Say "cheese".
What do you want?
You know who we are.
Tell him
that this could go
one of two ways.
The money way,
or the other way.
This can go one of two ways,
money or...
You traitor.
You have turned your back
on your own people.
I know who you are.
You're Ali's brother.
I will personally kill
your entire family.
Your wife will see your death.
Just before
I set the dogs on her.
I will tell you nothing.
That doesn't sound
very positive.
He's not too keen to help.
That it?
Pretty much, yes.
Give him some lube.
Carrot.
Stick.
That suit
is for a hot little island
in the Caribbean.
The other is to buy yourself
something pretty.
What do they want to know?
He's ready.
Simple question.
Where do they build the IEDs?
Where is
the Taliban's main location
for making bombs?
It's not just one location.
And you know why.
But I've seen some places
where they make explosives
and stock them.
What'd he say?
He's fishing.
He wants more cash.
Tell him he'll get it
when we finish the job.
We can save a lot of time here
if we give him the cash.
Excuse me?
He'll get it
when we finish the job.
You'll get more
if the information is good.
If you cut
the Taliban's head off here
it will grow back
some place else.
Get on with it.
-The f--
Just in these past two days
new explosives
have been sent
across the country.
I was also supposed to be there
and help.
He has a lead.
A lot of fuckin' dogs
around here.
Hey, Eddie?
What did Faraj say to Ahmed?
He said he'd wipe out
his bloodline,
and murder him in front
of his wife
before he fed her to the dogs.
How do they know each other?
Not sure
this is common knowledge,
but from what I understand,
Ahmed used to work
in the heroin trade.
It's a family business.
They used to work
with the Taliban.
So then,
why is he workin' for us?
Because the Talis killed
his son.
Why the fuck didn't you
tell me this before?
It's the price
of givin' orders.
Don't ever override
my authority again.
I understood your objective.
I apologize
for my clumsy method.
So, we understand each other?
Yes, Sergeant.
Good work.
- Okay. Yeah.
Okay, buddy.
All right, thank you. Bye.
Sir.
Well,
you got your result.
What do you think, John?
There are two sites.
Do this one at a time.
Keep it quiet.
Well, you need any help,
I'm a phone call away,
all right?
Thank you.
The first IED location
is 30 clicks.
One hour's drive
on a straight track.
And then we reach a fork
in the road, and bang a left.
Excuse me. Sorry.
Yeah, what is it, Haadee?
When we reach the fork
in the road,
my feeling is that
the quickest route
is to turn right,
even though left is shorter
as the crow flies.
Well, quickest, why?
According to the map, it's not.
In the last rainfalls,
most of the road on the left
got washed away.
What do you think, Jizzy?
I guess so.
There is no intel
to confirm or deny.
All right, how much time
does it add to the journey?
About 20 minutes.
Thirty, tops.
All right. So, we got a plan.
Right is right.
-Push that to the highers.
-Cool.
-Okay, let's move out.
-All right, let's go.
Sergeant Kinley,
can you please stop
the vehicle?
Excuse me?
I need to speak
to you, Sergeant.
We don't stop
the vehicles. We keep moving.
I think
we have a problem.
Please stop the vehicle,
Sergeant.
Okay,
stop the truck, Jizzy.
-  All vehicles
for a tactical stop.
- Come on, guys.
-What is it, Ahmed?
- Three-sixty watch.
-Let's go!
-Something's wrong.
There's no logical reason
for Haadee
to lead us
down this route, unless...
Unless what?
...unless he's leading us
into a trap.
Well, that's
a pretty big assumption, Ahmed.
Deduction, not assumption.
Now you're teachin' me English?
North side clear.
I've been thinking
about all the possible reasons
why he'd take this route.
All the answers smell bad.
He lied about the road
being washed out.
The rainfalls
didn't affect this area.
Haadee's been vetted.
You can say
whatever you want, Sergeant.
We just don't
wanna go down this road.
You're out of
your bounds, Ahmed.
You're here to translate.
Actually, I'm here
to interpret.
All right.
You wanna be right, Ahmed?
-Hey, Jizzy.
Check the drone.
-On it.
JJ, Tom Cat,
go up to the top
of those rocks there
-and tell me what you see.
- Copy that.
Viper 6-2, Viper 6-2,
this is Havoc 3-3.
Havoc 3-3,
-this is Viper 6-2, over.
-Roger. We need
live imagery now.
Why have we stopped?
The road is safe.
What are we waiting for, John?
I'm waitin' to hear if there's
a fuckin' ambush up ahead.
ETA, ten minutes.
Look, I haven't got
ten minutes.
We need the imagery now.
Roger that.
Grid to mark, 4-5.
JJ?
All clear.
Tom Cat?
All clear, too.
-It's clear.
-  6-2 for Havoc 3-3,
-we're live.
-Viper 6-2, imagery received.
-Havoc 3-3, out.
-  Roger.
Okay,
what do we got here?
Whoa, whoa,
whoa, whoa. Ahmed, stop!
Get the fuck off!
Get the fuck off Haadee! John!
Get the fuck off of him, Ahmed!
-Put the fucking gun down!
- Hey! Hey!
Get that gun out of his throat!
He's a traitor.
I don't give a fuck what he is.
You take that gun
out of his throat.
He gave up our position.
Take the gun out of his throat.
I am not gonna ask you again.
He says they have his family.
John,
you're not gonna like this.
What is it?
We've got a problem.
What the fuck is it?
Looks like an ambush.
Tali kill box
eight klicks up this road.
All right,
let's turn this thing around.
-Get back to base.
-  Copy.
Get in the truck.
Pick him up.
Look what I got, Daddy.
Look what I got.
It's from Johnny's dad.
-Why are you going to bed
at lunchtime?
No, baby.
Time is different here,
you remember?
I'm ten hours ahead of you.
It's nighttime.
I miss you.
I miss you, too. All of you.
Hey, kids?
You let me talk to Mommy
for just a second?
I'll be out
in a minute.
-  Love you, Daddy.
I love you, too.
Have a good rest of your day.
-Hey, sweetheart.
-Hey, babe.
How's... how's business?
Well, it's... it's good.
We have bookings
for the next six weeks
and beyond.
-That's good news.
-Mm-hmm.
How are the books?
We're up on last quarter.
So, you're all over it.
You're all over it.
Oh, you know me,
of course I am.
Just another one
of the reasons I love you.
Well, you know how much
I love you, John.
-Just hurry up and get home.
- Yeah.
Are you okay?
Yes, yes, I'm good.
Sit, sit.
You must rest.
Do you want me
to get you something?
I could eat some more.
Leave it to me.
Did you hear
about Hadyah's son?
What happened to him?
He's joined the Taliban.
And he won't talk
to her anymore.
When I saw her she was crying.
Poor woman, first she loses
her husband, now this.
I'm worried about him, Ahmed.
What about
our Special Immigration Visas?
It takes time. Don't worry.
Hey.
I'm on it.
-Ease up 'til they get back.
-Sir?
John.
Interpreter came through, huh?
Just don't know
how wild he is.
Yeah, well, he still saved
eight people's lives.
Yes, he did.
So, what's your next move?
-Second location,
120 klicks away.
-Awesome.
Three hours in a Humvee should
be fun for the old back.
Well, you could give us
a couple of birds.
Yeah.
No.
Happy hunting.
Thank you, sir.
Why do the Talib always seem
to have their arms cache
hundred clicks from our base?
Jizzy's hemorrhoids
won't be able to take it.
All right, look.
This is our fourth tour here...
And what have we achieved apart
from losing Jack Jack?
Even if we do find shit
that goes bang...
You think it's gonna make
a difference or bring him back?
What's that got to do
with Jizzy's hemorrhoids?
Why are you always
talking about ass Tom Cat?
Where do you think
he got the name Tom Cat?
We're here.
Nothing like
a three-hour drive.
All right,
we're 120 clicks from base,
and 30 minutes
from air support,
so, uh, do a final
comms check, Tom Cat.
Roger that. Comms clear, John.
Put your fuckin' hands up now!
Get your fuckin' hands up now!
Put your hands up!
Get in line over here! Now!
As you can see
I'm with the U.S. Army,
we're here to conduct a search.
Are you the land owner?
Yes, the land is mine.
What are you looking for here?
We're looking for explosives.
Explosives?
This is a closed mine.
There has not been
any explosives here for years.
This shouldn't take long.
Thank you.
Are you looking
for the Taliban?
Yes, we're looking for Taliban.
I knew this would happen.
But you guys have come
to the wrong place.
Down there's
another plantation.
The Americans are here
at the mine.
The Americans
have found the mine.
Send the men there.
More soldiers are coming.
That's where you'll find
the people you are looking for.
Thank you.
We will check there next.
Welcome.
Something's not right.
He's lying.
Jizzy, hold what you got.
Secure the area.
We're moving up.
On it.
- Hey! Come here!
Move! This guy was
on his phone!
Give me that!
Put your hands on your head!
On me.
Kawa, pick up the rear.
Roger.
Everybody on the floor!
-On the floor!
- Get down! Now!
Clear.
Kawa, take over watch.
Keep eyes on the road.
John, it's Jizzy.
We found a big weapons cache
down here.
What do you wanna do?
Secure those bodies,
take up a security position
and stand by.
Copy.
Hands behind your backs!
Get 'em on the floor!
-Don't fuckin' move!
- Get down!
Tom Cat, JJ, cuff 'em.
Kersher,
watch the fuckin' road.
No! No! No! No!
Tom Cat, it's John.
We got an IED factory.
Four Tangos.
We need
air support immediately.
We're goin' in.
Viper 6-2, Viper 6-2,
this is Havoc 3-3.
We've hit jackpot.
Requesting immediate QRF. Over.
Copy,
Havoc 3-3, assigning QRF.
Ahmed, you stay here.
We don't need a translator
for this.
Fuckin' animals.
It's Jack Jack's killer.
Fuck!
- Fuck.
- Fuck!
-Clear. You all right?
Motherfucker got me
in the arm.
- Ahmed! We good?
- We're good.
- Fuck.
- Watch the door.
Fuck!
Hold on, stay there.
All right,
charge is set. Three minutes.
-Let's go. Move.
Move, move, move.
Hold, hold.
Move, move.
All units, we have
a three-minute burning fuse.
Keep that 50-K locked
on the north road.
Copy that.
- Kawa, we are
on your left. Cover us--
Shit!
Eddie! Eddie!
-Eddie's down.
-  Eddie's down.
-Get 'em on their feet.
-Get up!
-Get up right now!
-Move!
We're at the top of the hill,
making our way to you.
Move him, move him.
I don't want
the fuckin' Taliban to see him.
Steve, Talis approaching.
-Eleven o'clock. Two SUVs.
-Contact north!
Two Taliban trucks!
Get in position.
-Keep your eyes on the road!
-  Copy!
Covering nine o'clock.
- Shit!
- Talis on
the north bridge!
Contact left!
On the ridge, Tom Cat!
Keep your eyes on the road!
Viper 6-2, Viper 6-2,
troops in contact.
I repeat, troops in contact!
Viper 6-2,
we are 15 minutes out.
First truck has arrived
at the left
at the north entrance.
Kersher's down.
Tom Cat, get on the gun!
Go! Go!
Steve is down. Over.
Hold position. Coming to you.
SUV inbound.
East entrance.
Second SUV approaching.
Kawa, let's move!
Following, John--
Open fire--
Tom Cat!
JJ's down!
Move!
Fuck.
Fuck!
Move!
John! John! We need a plan now!
You have an SUV coming.
We'll cover you.
Take that truck,
go to higher ground,
and take a position.
John,
we're fuckin' pinned!
Move. Move.
Cover me!
- Jizzy, go, go!
Ahmed, get in! Get in!
John, follow me.
Straight ahead.
We'll punch up the--
Fuck. Jizzy! Jizzy!
Control this.
Dagger 1-2.
Dagger 1-2,
this is Dagger 3-3. Come in.
We're out of range.
Dagger 1-2, Dagger 1-2,
this is Dagger 3-3. Come in.
Fuck!
Ah, shit!
We've got a flat.
All right,
we have to abandon ship.
Ahmed. Ahmed.
We've found their car,
they're on foot.
I will send everyone,
go after them and kill them.
I want them alive.
Get them alive.
Spread out, find them.
Havoc actual.
Roger.
This is Viper 6-2.
We have approximately
40 KIA Taliban.
We recovered all 3-3 bodies,
minus John Kinley
and the interpreter. Over.
I think we're good
for now.
We'll rest here for the night.
Here's the challenge.
The satnav says
the beer is 120 clicks
in that direction
over shit terrain.
And Taliban are everywhere,
so we can't use the roads.
They will be on us
in two minutes.
We're not walking,
we're double-timing. You good?
I'm good.
They're on us.
Gun up?
-Gun's up.
Let's move.
Where's your fuckin' gun?
Halfway up the hill.
This belongs to you now.
Just don't lose it.
You ready?
Following you, boss.
Rifle.
Let's go.
Hey.
Is he dead?
Yeah.
Get him up.
It fuckin' stinks in there.
We'll rack up here
for the night.
Listen my brothers.
You will find them.
God is with you,
not the infidels.
They are the enemy
of our prophet.
They are a long way
from their base.
They will never get home.
It is your duty
to bring them to justice.
I want them brought
to me alive.
They see a house.
We haven't seen too many
of those.
If we can hear them,
they gotta be close.
Pack up your shit.
Ahmed.
Stop him
I must kill him.
Calm down brother.
He must die.
We need him alive.
Calm down.
Calm?
Hey.
John.
We're going home.
It's gonna be a long journey.
We can't take the roads.
They know we're here.
More men will be coming here
in trucks.
Here you go.
We've broken down,
we need a ride.
Okay, I will take you
anywhere you want.
Drive a few kilometers
up this road.
Okay, I will take you.
What are you doing
out here brother?
Looking for two men,
an American and the other,
a Muslim traitor.
Have you seen
anyone suspicious?
I have seen no one,
these roads are quiet.
I am surprised to see even you.
We will find them,
this is our territory.
What's in the back?
I'm a rug seller.
Are you interested?
Just drive.
Stop the truck.
Thank you.
Peace be upon you.
Hello brother, how are you?
Good thank you.
I apologize
for disturbing your meal.
Sit.
Thank you.
Did you hunt those?
You shall feast tonight.
Brother, I have a friend
in the truck, he's hurt.
How can I help?
We need some food
and some pain relief.
And if you give me
your wooden kart...
I will give you my truck.
May I see your friend?
Of course.
So you're the two
they are looking for.
I don't like Taliban.
I will help you.
He needs opium.
It will ease his pain.
Thank you.
There's a heavy price
on your heads.
They have hundreds of Taliban
looking for you.
They have been
village to village,
setting fire to those
that give no information.
They will not stop hunting you.
You are a long way
from his base.
Do not use the roads,
patrols are everywhere.
You must use
the mountain passes.
Peace be upon you.
-Peace be upon you.
Would you like something?
Give me the water.
Thank you.
Peace be upon you.
Hello brother.
Give me water.
Hey, catch.
Put your fucking hands up!
Hands up!
Get down on the ground!
Get the fuck down!
Get down!
Stay down!
Look away!
I have one of yours.
-He's in the cart.
-Check the cart.
It's John fuckin' Kinley.
Hey! Hey,
it's John fuckin' Kinley.
We need a medic over here!
Dr. Kale, please dial 1-1-8.
We're going home.
Welcome home, Mr. Kinley.
-I'll get your doctor.
Heard they're
giving you a medal,
Distinguished Service Cross.
- Come on,
put it away, guys.
-That was quick.
- Dinner's in five.
- Well,
you did crawl
on your hands and knees
over broken glass
for a 100 clicks, so...
If I did,
I don't remember any of it.
You still don't remember
a thing?
I mean, I remember waking up
in the hospital.
So, why should they
give me a medal?
They should give it to him.
As far as I know,
I was just a passenger.
I don't think
it's a medal he wants
as much as a visa he needs.
Well, what's goin' on
with that?
Well, even if we can get
the visa,
we still gotta find him first.
Find him?
Where'd he go?
Well, after your little hike
in Afghanistan,
Ahmed found himself
a local folk hero
to everyone, but the Taliban.
Let's just say,
they're not pleased
he dragged you 100 clicks
across their territory,
and they were unable
to catch you.
Your story has developed
something of a following
among the populous.
What's that look like?
He ended up
on their top ten
most-wanted list
with a price on his head.
Disappeared and went
underground with his family.
Before you ask,
I reached out
to his smack-dealing brother.
I sense he knows where he is,
but he's not gonna give us
that information
until we get Ahmed a visa.
Ahmed. Ahmed Abdullah.
And how are you
spelling that, sir?
Yeah, A-B-D...
Yes, I know, ma'am. I...
Has his visa been approved?
Mr. Abdullah was... was set
to have his visa issued.
And the name, sir?
-Ahmed.
Your friend needs to fill out
-an I-360 form.
-I-I can't get him
on the phone.
His... his family have
been forced into hiding.
-Ma'am, I've explained
this situation to...
-  Just one minute.
-...your supervisor already.
Can you not...
-Just one minute.
-Just gonna put you
on hold, sir.
-Can you...
How are you supposed to do
a background check
on a three-month-old child?
Can you not put me on hold?
I have been holding
for one and a half hours.
Just one minute.
Well, first we have to
figure out how to make sure
their visas are issued,
and then I can figure out
how to find them.
Would you leave your wife
and child behind? Would you?
He disappeared and went
underground with his family.
underground with his family,
because of you.
-Because of you.
I just gave you
all that information.
I literally just gave that
to your supervisor.
No, I'm not related.
He's in Afghanistan...
Just
gonna put you on hold, sir.
-Fuckin' hold music!
You leave people on hold
for an hour and a half,
they're gonna get frustrated.
Yes, ma'am. Yeah.
Yes, I have
the letter right here.
From Colonel Masters?
-That's correct.
Yeah.
It's from Colonel Masters.
Okay, so yeah, well then
how long will that be?
It's a minimum
nine months, sir.
They...
they can't wait nine months!
If they wait nine months,
they will be dead!
-Good night, boss.
-Hey, I'll lock up, Miguel.
I'll lock up.
You're through to USCIS,
-how can I help you, sir?
-Uh...
Are you gonna put me
on hold again?
-Yeah, go ahead
and put me on hold again.
-If you could just bear
with me for one minute, sir.
Don't, don't, don't, don't,
don't, don't, don't.
Don't put the phone down.
-Don't put
the fucking phone down.
-It will just take
one moment, Sergeant.
-I will find someone
that can help you.
-You put... You fucking put me
on hold again,
and I will find you.
Put me on hold! Come on!
What's
your fucking name, huh?
What's your name?
I will come
to your fuckin' house,
and I will find you!
There's a fuckin' man stuck
in a goddamn cave!
I will find you!
Drink this.
You're okay.
Hey.
Quiet.
John?
John.
As if it wasn't enough
for him to carry me
across those mountains,
now I can't get him
out of my fuckin' head.
I'm lying in this bed.
I kiss my children
before they go to school.
And he's hiding
in a hole somewhere.
A hole he can never get out of.
A hole that we put him in.
And that wasn't the deal.
The deal was that we offered
his family sanctuary.
Then we tied a noose
around his neck
and we kicked the stool
out from under him.
I should be
in that hole.
You think he blessed you?
Well, he fuckin' cursed me.
I am a man who gets no rest.
Please continue to hold.
Your call is in a queue.
Your call is in a...
We both know
how this is gonna end.
I am gonna have
to get him out myself.
I know a guy.
Parker.
Private security contractor.
I hear he's very good,
and he can help you.
But it's gonna cost.
We'll have to give you
a different name
and background.
If the Talibs find out that
you're back in the country,
they'll know why.
And they'll throw everything
they have at finding you both.
Hello.
Taliban are here.
Where?
They are a few doors down.
-Get out of there.
-Basira.
I will have to move you again.
Leave now.
Yes, I know, I know.
Basira the bag, the bag.
Let's go.
They've executed Abdi.
Your house is next.
Let's go, let's go.
Taliban heading towards you.
Wait, wait.
-Where, where?
He's approaching
the back entrance.
Wait.
He's twenty feet
from the door.
Twelve feet.
Three Taliban heading
towards your front door.
The back door is clear.
They're in your house.
Out the back, turn right.
I see you.
Get down,
more Taliban are here.
Move, now.
- Mornin', boss.
-Mornin'.
I could only find three
of these.
I swear there's two more
around here.
All right.
So, you know where
to find us
if there's a problem.
- Great. Thank you.
-Pleasure doing business
with you.
Bye.
Mr. Kinley.
Mrs. Kinley.
Looks like you've
got everything under control.
Mm-hmm.
The Cadillac will be ready
this afternoon.
and the Harleys will be
picked up at six o'clock.
Guess you don't
need me then.
Nope.
But you sure look purty.
I'm gonna go...
put on something sexy.
I know and have accepted
what you do, John.
We've had this conversation
many times.
I've said goodbye to you,
not knowing
if I'm going to see you again.
And I've been doing this
for 12 years.
But this time, it's different.
This family believed
that you were dead.
We suffered this news
for three weeks.
Do you know what the children
and I went through?
But you have put me
in an impossible position.
Being your wife is one thing,
but being their mother,
it's... it's something else.
We owe that man your life.
So, we will remortgage
the house,
you'll get those visas,
and you will go.
And you will do
what you have to.
You'll come back alive.
You'll come back alive,
John Kinley.
Colonel. Declan.
John, please, have a seat.
Everything all right, John?
No, everything's not all right.
Have a seat.
I'd rather stand,
if you don't mind.
So, you seem
to have been making
a lot of noise lately.
What's your fucking name? Huh?
-  Sergeant, there is no--
-  What's your name?
-  It's First Officer
Cowell.
-  I will come
to your fucking house,
and I will find you!
Sergeant,
please calm down.
There's
a fucking man stuck
in a goddamn cave!
Sir, I assure you,
we're doing everything we can.
Fuckin' hole and...
There's been a,
uh, official complaint.
Oh, I see.
You brought me here
for an intervention.
Or to slap my wrist.
That's not why I'm here.
You think if I could be shot
of this debt, I wouldn't be?
Do you think if I could just
go through the usual channels,
I wouldn't?
That is not how
this debt works.
It demands a result,
not an appeasement.
There is a hook in me.
One that you cannot see.
But it is there.
And you think I have a choice?
There is no fuckin' choice.
I am going to get that man
and his family
out of the position
that we put him in.
And of that, I have no doubt.
And you're gonna
help me, Colonel.
The reason that I am here...
I saved your life
eight years ago.
So you're gonna
get those visas.
I don't know how.
But you're gonna get them.
Because I know
you are the type of man
that pays his debts.
Pay your debts.
I love you both so much.
I'm gonna
miss you, Daddy.
I'm gonna miss you.
I'll miss you, too.
Okay.
We are gonna miss you, John.
I know. I'll be back in a week.
Come here.
Kiss me.
Ron Kay? Vokes' man?
Parker, yeah?
-Yeah.
-I hear good things.
So, we set?
Well, I've contacted
Ahmed's brother, Ali.
He says he's found the village
that Ahmed's at,
but he's had
no contact directly yet.
So, we're goin' to the brother?
Yeah, well, that was the plan.
Was?
We've been pulled away
to do another job.
We have a contract, Parker.
We have an agreement.
And I need you to honor it.
This outranks me.
It comes from the top.
We got a UN diplomat,
got his detail in hot water,
we gotta deal with it.
That's all there is to it.
Listen, you hold up here
for three days,
my team's all yours.
That's not how
this contract works, brother.
In three days,
a warm body turns cold.
And I know
it's not ten million dollars,
but you said, "Yes."
And I'm two pints of blood
and a 150k in the hole.
Well, Ron, if you're not happy,
you can take your money back.
Oh, no, I'm definitely
not fuckin' happy.
I don't want the money.
I want you
to honor the fuckin' deal.
I hear you have
an impressive team.
Now I need you
to back yourself.
All right, listen.
Let's, uh...
compromise, shall we?
If you can find Ahmed
and his family,
call us with the location,
we'll come in,
airlift you out,
get you back to base,
put you
on the next transport home.
Done.
You just gotta find him.
I see how this works.
I pay you
so I can wash the car.
Come on, man.
You know how to adapt.
Use what you got,
and this is what you got.
Now, you can wait three days,
you get the full magazine.
Or you can go now,
but you're goin' solo.
I'll set you up.
I'll give you four good wheels
and a full set of tools,
but you're gonna be alone.
There's $10,000 cash
and a sat phone.
You got an M-4 in the trunk,
with six magazines.
You got a full tank of gas,
satnav address
that's gonna take you to Ali.
You can touch base
with him first.
Ron, it's 72 hours.
If I was you, I'd wait.
Yeah, but you're not me.
Are you, Parker?
Ali,
are you accepting customers?
John!
John, come in.
Sit down, please.
Please sit down.
Relax.
Just a second.
Hassan!
You want some tea?
Do you know
what John means in my country?
My dear. My love.
My brother told me about
your beautiful blue eyes.
You have beautiful blue eyes.
Ahmed's son also
had beautiful blue eyes.
Cigarette?
The only reason
I haven't been tortured
about the location
of my brother,
is because I do a lot
of business with the Taliban.
I guess you know what
I'm doing for a living, right?
Yeah, I think I understand.
Hmm.
You also understand my brother
has become very unpopular
with my partners.
They don't like the fact
that the story of your rescue
has become so famous.
Well, that's why I'm here. I...
I feel bad about that.
I owe your brother my life.
If you can give me
the location of your brother
I can get him
out of the country.
Is that your truck there?
You can't take that.
It's too dangerous.
I organized some transport.
There's my truck driver,
his name is Pooya.
He has a pass
to get him through
the Taliban checkpoints.
However, sometimes,
they can be still difficult.
When was the last time
you talked to your brother?
A week ago.
And he's due
to move in two days.
But this is his last chance.
The price on his head
is too great now.
Good luck, John Kinley.
Goodbye.
Stay hidden. Stay hidden!
Show us the papers.
-Make it quick.
It's okay.
Checkpoint! Checkpoint!
Hello brothers.
Turn off the engine.
-Step out.
-What's the problem?
-I said step out.
-I paid for this.
Step out.
But, I paid for this.
What's in your truck?
I paid for this.
I said what's in your truck?
Corn boxes, I have brought them
for your brothers.
-Delivering, where to?
-Jalalabad.
So show us.
Open this too.
-You see.
-Be quiet son of a dog.
There is nothing.
Be quiet son of a dog.
Take this money.
I do not care about your money.
Who are you to pay me?
On your knees.
You good?
I thought we were dead.
Let's get him outta here.
Do you hear, Commander Satar?
Fakhrudin?
We have trouble.
Two men have killed
our soldiers at the checkpoint.
Find out who they are.
I'll follow them.
Keep in contact.
John?
John, it's Vokes.
I got the visas.
Whole family.
I'm having them delivered
to Parker.
-Good man.
-John.
Good luck, brother.
We are here.
Red 6, this is Red 1,
got you Lima Charlie...
Ron for Parker.
Boss, it's for you.
It's Ron Kay.
-Red 6, good copy.
-Ron.
Result?
Parker, I found him.
Tracking your location now.
You make contact?
No.
But I am looking at him
right now.
Uh, got his location now, sir.
All right, we got you.
Yeah, just wait a second.
Nearest extraction point
is Darunta Dam,
two kilometers due east
from where you stand now.
-Darunta Dam. Got it.
-All right, call us back
when you got your man,
his family,
and you're en route.
You'll have a two-hour window
from that point, all right?
Uh, yeah, one more thing,
Parker, um...
We don't have much time.
I left a messy trail.
All right, we'll make a call.
See if we can get some eyes up.
Go get your boy.
A lot of dogs around here.
I like your outfit.
And I like what you've done
with your hair.
Must've been quite challenging
to find me.
Eh.
I can get you
and your family outta here.
We just have to leave now.
Now?
That's a shame.
I like it here.
Mmm.
Mmm. I can see why. Yes.
Fakhrudin.
What is it?
I found them.
The American and Ahmed.
Are you sure it's them?
I'm positive.
He's found John Kinley
and Ahmed.
Get men out there now.
Follow them right now
and get their picture.
Yeah, what is it, Joe?
Ron Kay.
What about him?
Yeah, I thought
he looked familiar,
but I couldn't
put my finger on it.
So, I ran him through
the system and our intel shows
he's on the Talib's
most-wanted list.
He's on a list?
Why is he on a list?
Oh, fuck me.
"Ron Kay", that...
that's John Kinley.
Why didn't he
tell us that before?
It's John Kinley
and Ahmed.
I think if John Kinley
is popular with the Talib,
then Ahmed is the fattest
fuckin' pig in the pen.
Let's turn this thing around.
-Cody, get Bagram
on the line, now!
- Yes, sir.
They're gonna want in on this,
and we wanna get
an  Angel in the air.
-You two, get the drone footage
up right now.
- On it!
At last,
gonna get my boots dirty.
Basira.
Basira, this is John.
John?
Ahmed, what's going on?
John has got us visas.
We are going to America.
We have to go now.
Where are they?
I have someone watching them.
I'll take you there.
Let's go.
They are in the truck
heading towards the dam.
They are heading
towards the dam.
Fakhrudin, listen to me
very carefully.
Do not let them get away,
I want their heads
or else I'll take yours.
I can see the dam.
Taliban trucks!
Pooya, block the tunnel.
- Move!
Come on!
Move, move, move,
move, move!
Move, move, move!
Cover, cover, cover!
Go, go!
To the building,
to the building!
Ahmed!
Covering!
Crap!
Motherfuckers!
-Cover me.
- Get down.
Fuck!
Shit!
- Go, go, go!
Down!
Fuck!
- Get down!
-Argh! I'm almost out.
Ah, shit! I'm out!
Come on, Parker!
Where the fuck are you, Parker?
-Shit. Shit.
I'm out.
Identifying multiple targets,
west end of the dam.
Go in hot on the 105.
I have visual, 0-6-0.
Copy that, Spectre 3-7.
They are clear.
Copy that.
All tangos down?
Confirmed. Off the trigger.
FOB 2, this is Spectre 3-7,
we are all clear.
Everyone all right?
Bradley, Mike,
get him up and in the air.
- Yes, sir.
You know,
if you'd have told me
that you were John Kinley,
and he's the Ahmed,
you'd have got this
whole thing on me, pal.
These are from Vokes.
Visas for Ahmed,
his wife, the kid.
All right, this is gonna
take you back to base.
There's a transport airplane
waiting back there.
It's gonna take you home.
Parker.
Kinley.
Pleasure doin' business
with you.
You backed yourself.
Ahmed, good work.
You need anything,
you look me up.
♪ Truth ♪
♪ The truth is that
I never shook my shadow ♪
♪  Every day it's trying
To trick me into doing battle ♪
♪  Calling out "faker"
Only get me rattled ♪
♪  Want to pull me back behind
The fence with the cattle ♪
♪  Building your lenses ♪
♪  Digging your trenches ♪
♪ Put me on the front line ♪
♪ Leave me with a dumb mind ♪
♪  With no defenses ♪
♪  But your defenses ♪
♪  If you can't stand
To feel the pain ♪
♪ Then you are senseless ♪
♪  Since this
I've grown up some ♪
♪  Different kind of fighter ♪
♪  And when the darkness come
Let it inside you ♪
♪ Your darkness is shining ♪
♪  My darkness is shining ♪
♪  Have faith in myself ♪
♪  Truth ♪
♪  I've seen a million numbered
Doors on the horizon ♪
♪  Now which is the future
You choosin' ♪
♪ Before you go dying ♪
♪  I'll tell you 'bout a secret,
I've been undermining ♪
♪  Every little lie
In this world ♪
♪ Come from dividing ♪
♪  Say you're my lover,
Say you're my homie ♪
♪  Tilt my chin back,
Slit my throat ♪
♪  Take a bath in my blood,
Get to know me ♪
♪  All out of my secrets ♪
♪  All my enemies are turning
Into my teachers ♪
♪  Because lights blinding
No way dividing ♪
♪  What's yours or mine
When everything's shining ♪
♪  Your darkness is shining ♪
♪  My darkness is shining ♪
♪  Have faith in ourselves ♪
♪  Truth ♪
♪  Yes, I'm only loving,
Only trying to only love ♪
♪  And, yes, and what I'm trying
To do is only loving ♪
♪  Yes, I'm only loving,
Trying to only love ♪
♪  I swear to God,
I'm only trying to be loving ♪
♪  Yes, I'm only lonely loving ♪
♪  Yes, I'm only feeling
Only loving, only loving ♪
♪  You say it ain't loving,
Ain't loving ♪
♪  Ain't loving, my loving ♪
♪  But I'm only loving,
Still only loving ♪
♪  Swear to god,
I'm only loving ♪
♪  Trying to be loving, loving ♪
♪  Loving, loving,
Loving, loving ♪
♪  Yes I'm only loving,
Yes, trying to only love ♪
♪  I swear to god, I'm trying
But I'm only loving ♪
♪  You say it ain't loving ♪
♪  Ain't loving, ain't loving ♪
♪  Ain't loving,
Ain't loving my loving ♪
♪  But I'm only loving,
Loving, loving ♪
♪  Loving the truth ♪
♪  Truth ♪