Congratulations, Pancho!
Who would've thought
someone with your shady background
would get so far, and become
the corporate general manager.
Cheers!
- Cheers.
- To success in your new position.
Thanks, Don Jaime, but I owe it all
to you and your trust in me.
Nonsense! You earned it in your own right.
It's a shame your family couldn't be here
on such an important day.
I would love to meet them
and congratulate them in person.
You might not remember,
but I told you a while back
that my parents passed away
when I was an only child.
My only family is my dear Mari
and my beautiful children.
You don't need much else, my boy.
Your wife's a hot piece of ass.
You truly hit the jackpot.
She's pretty much the reason
you've been losing your tackiness,
and small town ways.
Isn't that right, Mariquita?
Thanks, Don Jaime.
Dinner is served, please take your seats.
Go ahead.
- Monsignor, please.
- Please, go ahead.
Thanks.
- Your napkin, dear.
- Sorry, my love.
Thank you.
Enjoy everyone.
We hired an excellent caterer.
Try the foie gras, sir
and the Jabugo ham is to die for.
Are we expecting anyone?
Honey, did you invite anyone else?
Sir?
There are two men at the door
asking for you.
They say they're relatives,
but they're really ugly and they stink.
I'm sure there must be
some kind of mistake.
Don Jaime, give me two minutes
to sort this out.
I'll be right back. Excuse me.
Check it out, Pops!
I figured this son of a bitch
was swimming in cash,
and that's why he's forgotten about us.
Do you know them?
Do you know this pair of shabby scumbags?
Who, them? No, I've never met them.
Listen up pals! This is private property.
If you don't fuck off right now,
I'll call my bodyguards to kick you out!
López probably sent them
to ruin the party.
Listen up, dandies!
First person that moves
gets pumped full of lead!
Pops, I've told you, no one
calls them dandies anymore.
That was back in your day.
Like the President says,
these fuckers
are privileged conservatives.
To me, they're the same scum
that derailed the Revolution.
Dad! Grandpa!
This isn't the time.
Let me send my guests home,
and we'll talk this through.
Screw your guests.
The only way they're leaving
is in a body bag!
Stop the nonsense!
Friends, let's not get caught up
in the intolerance and polarization
promoted by this populist government.
If it's money you want, I have plenty.
I'll give you as much as you want.
- Take your money...
- Yes.
- ...roll it up...
- Yes?
And stick it up your ass.
Please get a grip on Grandpa.
Dad, I'm begging you.
- You're going to ruin my life!
- Ruin your life, Panchito?
Look how you've treated us,
ungrateful bastard.
The whole family made sacrifices
to put you through college,
and look how you've repaid us.
Twenty years of neglect and abandonment!
All the while living the high life
at our expense, huh?
All right, Rosendo.
Quit being such a pansy.
Take them to the back,
let's get this over with!
Yes, Pops. Come on, move it!
You too, blondie! Move your asses!
- You're staying right here.
- Panchito, come with me.
- Come on, hurry.
- Wait, no!
Go on, move it!
Back to the wall!
Now, face the firing squad!
Dad, Grandpa...
I realize I've been
an ungrateful, lousy son,
but I swear that from now on,
things will be different.
What's mine will be yours,
and I will never abandon you.
Too late, Panchito.
The hour of revolutionary justice
has come for you.
The poor come first now!
- Blindfold him, Rosendo.
- Sure, Pops!
Please don't!
Please, Dad. I'm begging you.
Think of my children.
You've always been so good to me.
Sorry, Panchito.
When you had the chance
to help us, you didn't.
It's time for you to pay
for all your bullshit.
By the way, your mother
and siblings send their love.
Thank you.
- Ready, Rosendo?
- Yes, Pops.
Ready!
Aim!
Fire!
Fran? Fran!
Pancho!
Having one of your nightmares again?
Oh, Mari, you have no idea
what a horrible dream I had.
- Your family, again?
- Yeah.
I've told you a thousand times,
you need to see a therapist.
This isn't normal.
Now, let me get some sleep
before your alarm goes off.
Yeah, I could use some sleep myself,
I have a big day tomorrow.
Good morning.
- Morning, Dad!
- Good morning, Lupita.
I'm meeting with Don Jaime,
I can't be late.
- Can I fix you something?
- Just a coffee, real quick.
How do I look?
A little tired, but super handsome.
- So handsome, Daddy!
- Thanks, sweetie.
Why do you keep wearing
those shoes with that suit?
The black Ferragamos look so much better.
I don't have time to change,
what can I say?
Fix your shirt, it looks wrong.
Hello? Yes, this is the residence
of the Reyes family.
Who?
Oh, one moment.
Sir, it's for you.
Says he's your dad, Rosendo.
He says it's important.
No, tell him I'm not here.
Tell him you don't know when I'll be back.
Lupita, whatever you do,
don't give him my cell phone.
Got it?
Mr. Rosendo?
Mr. Pancho left for work,
he's not sure when he'll be back.
No, I don't have his personal number.
Oh.
Don't worry, I'll tell him for you.
Okay, then. Goodbye.
He says it's an emergency,
something about your grandpa.
He wants you to call him back.
Such bad timing
- This is the last thing I need.
- Do you know what he wants?
He probably wants money,
but I can't deal with him today.
I would've liked to talk with Grandpa.
Some other day, champ.
- Bye, family! See you later.
- Bye, Daddy!
- Have a nice day, sir.
- Bye!
This is what I've been saying,
all this area is filthy,
so this guy over here...
Missed a spot. How's the A-4?
- Fantastic, sir.
- Perfect.
How is this machine still out of order?
Why haven't you fixed it?
Good on supplies? Perfect.
Mr. Reyes, your father is calling for you.
Mr. Reyes, Mr Reyes,
your father is on hold.
Good morning. Raise your hand
if you can hear me.
Thank you.
Colleagues, as all of you know,
the economic situation is dire
for the country and our factory.
Despite our efforts and sacrifices
to stay ahead of this situation,
only Mr. Sampaolo's generosity
has kept us afloat.
Unfortunately, the situation
has become unsustainable.
We only have two options
if we hope to stay in business.
Either we move the plant
and its subsidiaries to Asia,
or we could opt for a drastic,
yet necessary downsizing.
Appealing to your solidarity
to your colleagues,
I ask that you raise your hand
to volunteer for early retirement.
All right, since no one is taking
the company's generous offer,
I will be selecting
those who will be laid off.
Alcántara, Tiburcio.
Bojórquez, Ignacio.
Cárdenas, Cuitláhuac.
Mr. Reyes, Mr. Reyes.
You have a call from your father.
- Damn it.
- Mr. Reyes.
You have a call from your father.
Please!
Colleagues, please.
Congratulations, Pancho.
Thanks to you, productivity
is off the charts.
- And profits are higher than ever!
- Thank you, Don Jaime.
- How many did you sack today?
- Another 40.
Honestly, I don't think
there's any more fat to trim.
There always is, Pancho.
Once the new machines
from Germany get here,
we'll be able to cut an extra
ten percent off those parasites.
Another 180 employees out on the street?
I hope the union
doesn't threaten a strike.
Those commie troublemakers
from the union can suck my dick!
Now that our populist president
keeps gushing over the poor,
they're starting to think
they can make demands.
Yes, Licha?
Mr. Sampaolo, sorry to interrupt.
Mr. Reyes' secretary is here with me.
She says she urgently needs
to speak with him.
Send her in, Licha.
Good afternoon, Don Jaime.
I'm sorry to interrupt.
Mr. Reyes, your father
has been calling all morning.
He needs to talk to you,
it's a life-or-death emergency.
Don't worry, I know my dad.
I'm sure it's nothing.
Tell him I'm not here,
and next time I'm in a meeting
with Mr. Sampaolo,
do me a favor, never interrupt me.
Certainly, sir. Once again,
I'm sorry to bother you.
You can bother me whenever
you want, gorgeous.
I can't promise not to spank you, though,
or maybe even bend you
over my desk, kitten.
Are you tapping that ass, fucking Pancho?!
- No.
- She's smoking hot,
and anyone can see she needs a good fuck.
No way, Don Jaime.
Not in this day and age,
when you can get accused of
sexual misconduct over nothing.
All that bullshit about #MeToo,
and anti-harassment policies
can suck my dick.
That's why I'm the boss, don't you think?
Yeah, of course.
What's this about your family?
I thought you were an orphan.
No, you must be mistaking me
for someone else.
I'm sure that my father is overreacting.
My family thinks I'm rich,
so they're always hitting me up for money.
Tell them to fuck off!
My poor relatives are the same.
I'll always remember
what my father used to say.
"From the family and the sun,
the farther, the better."
What was I saying before
your slutty secretary came in?
That's right, I was saying
I'm sick of this government,
and its Echeverría-era populism.
I might as well sell the plant
to the gringos,
or move the entire operation
to China or Singapore.
- I even had budgets drawn up.
- No way, Don Jaime.
Don't even joke about that.
It's just... how should I put it?
I haven't paid off my mortgage yet.
Don't worry about that.
Despite your dubious social background,
you're one of us now.
If you keep up the good work,
and learn English and Mandarin,
I might just promote you
to general corporate manager.
General manager? Are you serious?
Of course I am.
Tell you what,
handle the Aguascalientes plant.
See if there are any parasites
we can exterminate!
You got it, Don Jaime. Excuse me.
What is it Lupita?
My father, again?
If he calls again,
tell him you couldn't find me.
Yeah, just tell him.
Tell the missus I'm on my way.
Fine, then. When she gets home. Bye.
Good day, sir.
We wanted to talk to you
about the layoffs.
Cirilo, I'm terribly sorry
but I have a meeting.
Let's talk some other time.
Sorry, excuse me.
Small town, new-money.
He won't forget us, though.
- Am I right?
- Yeah.
ASSHOLE
Jealous fuckers.
No wonder the country is going to shit.
Up yours!
PARADISE HILLS, MAKE YOUR
DREAMS COME TRUE!
- I'm home!
- Oh, Fran.
I'm so glad you're home,
I'm losing my mind.
- What happened?
- Your dad keeps calling.
And I'm fed up.
- Did he say what's it about?
- Something about your grandpa.
- He wants to tell you himself.
- New dress again, darling?
It's for Paloma's wedding.
Saks had a sale, I couldn't resist.
I got you a tie, and some Montblanc
gold cufflinks to die for.
- Do you like it? It's Dolce.
- I mean, it's very nice.
Please, you have to stop spending,
our credit cards are maxed out.
- I know, yes.
- Where are the kids?
Toni, Cati! Come say hi to your dad.
If the wife doesn't spend,
the husband won't prosper.
What's up, kiddos? How's it going?
Any news? Why haven't you changed?
I got an A in history!
Sister Idalia gave me
the role of Cinderella.
That's great to hear,
because I also have big news.
- What?
- No, no.
Go with Lupita and get changed for dinner.
- You got extra vacation days?
- Patience, María Elena.
Don Jaime congratulated me
and said if I keep it up,
and I learn English and Mandarin,
he'll make me general manager.
He might just make me partner.
- Does it come with a raise?
- Of course, at least double.
As much as that wimp of a manager makes.
Congratulations.
The truth is, we need a new SUV
and a better school for the kids.
One where they can meet
more affluent kids,
and learn English and French.
You know what else?
We should get a beach house.
- Don't you think?
- Yeah!
When you're the boss,
will you buy me a motorcycle?
- I want a pony like Paty's.
- Hang on.
Before you get too excited
and spend it all,
we need to pay off the mortgage first,
then we need to pay off the cars,
but more importantly, María Elena,
we have to pay off our loans
and the credit cards, right?
- What?
- Don't be a downer.
Honey, I'm not a downer,
I'm being realistic.
We can't just spend money
as if we were rich.
At least not until I get that promotion.
Excuse me.
Lupita, come here.
What is this slop?
What you told me to cook,
cheese and spinach "chuflé."
More than a soufflé, this looks like clay.
I told you to check with me
if you had any questions.
Yes, but you went "chopping"
so I did what I could.
Take this away and make us
some turkey sandwiches.
To teach you a lesson,
you're eating the whole thing.
- All right?
- Yes, ma'am, as you wish.
It's not enough she's filthy,
she doesn't know her place.
I don't know why you engage with the help.
Should I say you're not here?
I'm sure it's your father again.
I'll get it, Lupita.
My goodness, she thinks she's one of us.
- Hello?
- Hi, son!
How are you Dad?
How's everything?
Let me tell you, son.
Your grandfather Francisco,
may God rest his soul,
passed away a few days ago.
Grandpa Francisco died? How old was he?
- I'm so sorry.
- We just did the math.
He was somewhere around 120,
but no one knows for sure.
Give my love to Mom and Grandma Pascuala.
- Mari also sends her love.
- I will, son.
Listen, it's very important
that you come to Prosperidad.
That's going to be a bit difficult.
I'm swamped with work.
We don't really have
much of a choice here.
Pancho, look.
As part of your grandpa's
last will and testament,
he wanted you to attend his funeral.
And he ordered his attorney
not to open his will
until you are present.
If you don't come home,
they might even kick us out of the house.
Oh, man. That really sucks.
Listen, this really isn't
a good time for me.
Maybe I could try to visit
in December, how's that?
Come on, son. Don't do this to us.
Grandpa died days ago,
he's starting to stink.
Don't you get it?
It's a case of life and death.
What do you want me to say?
I can't do it, period.
Fine! If you can't, you can't!
What else is there to say?
I can't force you to come.
All right, give my love
to everyone back home!
Same here, Pancho! But let me tell you,
coming from you, I'm not surprised at all.
You've always been a lousy son.
Selfish, ungrateful,
and a full-fledged bastard!
Come on. Let's go, Filemón.
He hung up on me.
Oh, Fran.
You've never been close to your family.
- I'm surprised you're so upset.
- No, sweetheart.
My family is the worst,
but grandpa was different.
I was his favorite.
He helped me move away
and paid for my education.
Really? Maybe you should
visit your family after all.
- To claim your inheritance.
- What inheritance?
A plot of land somewhere?
A house in ruins?
Two donkeys and a cow?
There's nothing of value.
Maybe he left you the house.
I'm sure it's worth something.
I mean, sure.
But my parents and siblings
have always lived there,
So if I end up getting it,
I can't just kick them out.
I'd like to visit your hometown
to meet my grandparents.
I want a donkey and a cow to live with us!
- Aren't they sweet?
- Yeah.
I promise to take you
to Prosperidad one day,
so you can meet the family
and see where I grew up.
You'll see how beautiful the town is.
You know what, family?
We should go to bed, it's getting late.
- Shall we?
- Here are the sandwiches.
- Don't you want them?
- Thanks, have a good night.
Lupita, you can eat them or toss them out.
But eat the whole soufflé,
see if you learn.
Good night.
Up yours!
Do you profess or practice
the Catholic faith?
I'm a Christian...
- Please, shut him off.
- Why, honey?
I'm sick of seeing him everywhere.
I hate his tropical accent,
and his endless speeches
about the noble masses,
and that the poor come first.
"Let's take from the rich
and give to the poor."
...like the works of Jesus.
He was the most important
fighter for social justice.
He's comparing himself to Jesus now!
The country is in shambles,
maybe he has a point.
Don't even joke about that.
Like my girlfriends say,
he's a populist demagogue
who'll ruin our country
and turn it into Cuba or Venezuela.
That's ridiculous. You know what?
You and Don Jaime should
chat about the President.
If you heard the stuff he says,
you'd idolize him.
I'm sure Don Jaime is right.
Good night, Lord Populist.
Good night, Lady Privilege.
Hey, Fran.
Are you absolutely sure
it's not worth finding out
what your grandfather left you?
Maybe he has something
you don't know about.
No, I'm absolutely sure it's not worth it.
Good night, sleep well.
Night.
Pancho!
Pancho, come here!
Check out what I found.
Another one, Grandpa?
This one's huge! How many does this make?
Plenty, my boy. Plenty.
Don't forget this is a secret
just between you and me.
In the end, once I'm gone,
all this will be yours.
Of course, Grandpa. Don't worry.
Always remember that
it's full of vultures out there,
just waiting around to steal from us!
You haven't said anything
to anyone, have you?
Nothing about the treasure?
How about my safe, Pancho?
I haven't told anyone! I swear to God.
I don't believe you, you lying brat.
I'm sure you told your parents
and your siblings.
I have to make sure
you keep your mouth shut,
Forever!
Fran!
You were having another nightmare.
We have to go to Prosperidad.
I want to ask for the chance
of taking three weeks off.
What do you mean, three weeks off?
Not even I take that much time off!
I'm not going on vacation, Don Jaime.
I have a very serious family situation,
and they need me in town
to handle some paperwork.
Pancho, you disappoint me.
I put so much trust on you
and you repay me with this?
Just because I'm fond of you,
I'll give you five days.
- No more.
- Thank you so much.
Rest assured,
I'll leave everything in order.
I'll be back before Thursday
to sign for the new machines.
Don't take your eye off the prize.
Thank you, sir.
Are we almost there, Daddy?
Princess, I already told you
we're three hours away.
- Take another nap.
- Your hometown is so far!
We should've flown to Durango
and rented a car there.
Honey, I told you already.
Coming from Durango,
it's an eight-hour drive
across the mountain range.
Oh, really? How long has it been now?
We're getting closer, right, family?
Yeah.
Good.
Hey, Mom. Tell us the truth.
How come you haven't met Dad's family?
Don't ask me, ask him.
How come, Dad? Were you ashamed of them?
To tell you the truth,
I don't really know.
First, I finished college,
got a job at the plant,
then I met your mom, we got married,
and then you were born.
I guess we just kept putting it off.
The other day,
I heard Mom telling Aunt Jackie
that you never visited because
my grandparents are gross,
and they're always asking for money.
Catalina!
- Not cool.
- When did you last visit?
If memory serves, it's been 20 years
since the last time I visited Prosperidad.
Twenty years without seeing your parents?
That's almost twice my age.
- Holy shit.
- Toni!
I've told you over and over not to cuss.
Don't even think about cussing
in front of your grandparents.
Look at that, family.
We made it to the detour.
Great, does that mean we're almost there?
No, it's two more hours
- Take a nap.
- Listen to your parents.
Lupita, give Cati a pillow
and find the snacks.
Just don't leave crumbs everywhere.
Yes, Mom.
Check out this landscape. So beautiful.
Two hours of this?
- Can we roll up the windows?
- Good idea.
- Turn on the A/C.
- No, the dust will get in.
Does it remind you of your home, Lupita?
No way, sir.
San Pedro de los Saguaros
is much nicer, no offense.
It's so hot.
I'm roasting, jeez.
Oh, for fuck's sake.
We need to move that yuca.
Can you help me, Lupita?
Yes, sir.
- Let me get off, I'll help.
- Jesus!
- Kids, get out of the car.
- Okay.
- Grab that side, Lupita. We'll carry it.
- Sure.
- It's so heavy, sir.
- Hold on.
- Are you okay?
- Yeah.
- Here we go.
- Fran.
What is it, honey? What?
Mom!
Howdy, friend. That yuca looks heavy.
Yeah, but we have it under control.
Lucky you.
This is a lonely road,
it gets pretty dangerous.
- Isn't that right?
- Stay put, miss.
Gentlemen, please. Let's all relax.
Here's my watch and my wallet.
You're welcome to take
anything from the car.
Any relation to the Reyes
from Prosperidad?
Yes, that's my family.
Fucking Pancho Reyes.
Don't you recognize me?
Filiberto R. Arriaga.
We were together in elementary school.
Beto? Didn't we use to call you Mapache?
Well, sorry about this.
A man's gotta make a living.
Yeah, I get it.
- You're here about your grandpa.
- Yes, such a tragedy.
My deepest condolences.
May God keep Don Francisco
in his holy glory.
Thank you, Beto.
Brother.
- Thanks.
- You staying in town?
Let's meet up for a drink and catch up.
- Sure, I'd love to.
- You have a nice family.
- Congratulations.
- Thanks, man.
- We'll clear the road for you.
- Thanks.
Sorry to scare you, miss!
Bye, kids! Welcome to Prosperidad!
- Thanks, Beto!
- Well, giddy up!
Come on.
Here we go.
See ya!
Look, children.
We've arrived in Prosperidad.
- How about a photo?
- Yes!
This can't be right. I don't have service!
My cell phone doesn't either,
and it's newer than yours.
Mine either, but listen.
I'm sure this is going to be
an unforgettable experience.
- Let's take a picture.
- Okay.
- Make it vertical.
- Let's do a boomerang.
All right.
Ready? One, two... Say cheese!
Cheese!
This isn't like you described.
It's a ghost town.
Must be the time of day.
I guess folks are napping.
See that place, honey?
That's Mapache's house.
- Don't remind me.
- Good morning!
- They don't seem too friendly.
- Hey, Dad?
Is this the whole town? Isn't it small?
And ugly.
Believe it or not,
Prosperidad was once
Mexico's wealthiest town.
The mountains had so much gold,
you could find it lying around.
Yeah, right.
All I see on the street
is trash and dog poop.
Look at the donkey.
Human poop?
- Don't look, kids!
- Children, please!
Wow, this is such a beautiful thing.
Check this out.
This is one of Prosperidad's
most beautiful traditions.
When someone dies, the family
parades them all over town,
to a beautiful, old song
called "Las Golondrinas."
Judging by the coffin size,
they were kids, just like you.
Pancho!
- What?
- I said, shut up.
- They're here!
- They made it!
Let's go tell Grandpa!
Grandpa! Grandpa!
Grandma!
The rich relatives are here!
LA ESPERANZA MINE
They're here!
They came!
Fran... What is this?
Pancho Francisco Reyes!
I'm so glad to see you, son!
My dear father!
I'm so glad you came,
because in a couple years
we might not be around.
- My beautiful mother.
- Praise the Lord!
Oh, son!
My Pancho.
Folks, meet my family.
This is my wife, Mari,
and these cuties are my children.
- Hello.
- Toni and Cati.
A white woman to boost the bloodline, son.
- Welcome to our home, ma'am.
- Thanks, Don Rosendo.
Nice to meet you, Doña Dolores.
Nice to meet you, ma'am.
Come on, Mariquita.
Meet the rest of the family.
Oh, Pancho!
This is my eldest son. Rosendo, after me.
Even though he's a big guy,
we all call him Rosendito.
What's going on, Rosendito?
You stink of manure.
Have you showered since I left?
Fucking Pancho, always running your mouth.
Have you been humping that cow?
Pervert.
This religious prude
is my daughter Socorro.
The Divine Providence
granted me the miracle
of seeing you again in this life, Pancho.
Socorrito, I see you didn't
become a nun after all.
This useless, lame, good-for-nothing,
who used to be the town teacher
and now thinks he's a poet,
is her husband Cruz.
Prosperidad's poet muse.
- Eyes serene, so clear!
- All right, enough.
This is my son, Hilario,
the artist in the family.
- Nice to meet you.
- And this girl...
- What was your name, again?
- Pánfila, Don Rosendo.
You forgot again? Pánfila Lucía
Margarita Pérez Hernández,
and now Reyes, at your humble service.
What's up, Hilario? How have you been?
You couldn't find anyone younger, fucker?
The perks of being the town's
most famous artist.
How are you, kiddo?
This gangster-looking boy
is my son, Rufino.
The black sheep of the family.
And this busty little minx
is his current girlfriend,
Gloria.
'Sup, lady.
Pleasure to meet you.
You're hotter than I thought, sis.
Thank you.
Rufino, look at yourself.
You look like a druglord.
Come on, Pancho. Life isn't fair.
We can't all be as lucky as you.
Here, we do what we can, not what we want.
Give me a hug, man!
- It's good to see you.
- Come here, bro.
Come on.
I'm Gloria López, but call me "Culichi."
- Pancho!
- Welcome back.
- At your service.
- Same here.
How should I explain this mess?
This lady used to be my son, Jacinto.
One day, to the family's
shame and dishonor,
she decided she wasn't a man
and became Jacinta.
Did I explain that right?
Nice to meet you, sis.
Sorry about Dad's nonsense.
Rosendo is your typical Mexican macho.
Oh, Pancho!
Look at how handsome you turned out!
I suppose you're surprised,
but it's not contagious.
Jacinto, I can't believe you've done this.
You were always weird, even as a kid.
Jacinta, even if it takes you
a second longer.
Hang on, meet my hubby.
- Lupe!
- Yeah.
- Nice to meet you.
- Guadalupe Flores, at your service.
- Good to meet you, ma'am.
- Nice to meet you.
And this one here is my daughter Bartola.
The only good one in the family.
Although, to be honest,
she's not too bright.
The idiot has six children
with six different men,
including a black one and an Asian one.
This latest one was a gringo
who didn't even speak Spanish,
but I guess you didn't do
much talking, huh?
Look at you! You were a baby when I left.
You're all grown up now!
So, which one of these is your husband?
- Oh, Pancho!
- What?
As soon as Billy found out I was pregnant,
he left without saying goodbye!
- Oh, sister.
- Anyway.
Those are Brayan, Yaroslavi,
Dudinka, Reagan,
and a bunch I don't know,
but they're all my grandkids.
All right, family, this goes to everyone.
This is Mari, my beloved wife,
and these are my kids, Toni and Cati.
- Hi, everyone.
- That's Lupita.
She helps around the house
and decided to join us.
Is she your servant?
Dad, that word is outdated.
She's a domestic worker.
- Are you banging her?
- Don't say such things, Dad!
Where's my hello, Panchito?
Have you forgotten about
your fucking grandma?
Ungrateful bastard!
Grandma Pascuala!
What a nice surprise!
Of course you're surprised,
you little shit.
You probably thought I was gone, right?
I wouldn't dare, Grandma!
Look, meet my family.
These are my wife and my children.
- Hi, there.
- Cute family, fucker.
You're so lucky your kids
came out looking white.
But you're still a bastard
for abandoning us all these years.
Come closer, yes.
I have a feeling they're not yours.
Pancho, why don't we take you
to your room?
You must be tired, let's go.
I'll see you later.
I'm glad you haven't changed.
- All right, your majesty.
- Come on.
I hope you and this woman wouldn't dare
to show up here empty-handed.
I hope you brought me
a nice gift, at least.
Yes.
Just a little something from all of us.
- They're Fendi.
- Nice save.
Now we're talking!
You look great, Mom.
- I know, right?
- Let's go.
Let's see your grandpa first,
so he knows you're here.
Come on, everyone!
We put him in this room.
Come right in.
Don't you think your mom
and sisters did a great job?
He's starting to smell,
but we had to honor his will
to have you at his funeral.
Now that you're here with your family,
the old man will finally rest in peace.
You'll have a chance to be alone with him,
and pray for him.
Give him a kiss, son!
Let's go to your room. Follow me.
Come on, son.
Don't! You will break it!
No! get out young man,
get out of the car please!
Come in.
Get out of here!
- Outside, quick!
- Get out!
We're putting you in Grandpa's room.
It's the best one in the house.
It's not a luxury hotel,
but we set it up with love.
The sheets are fresh from the laundry.
Here is some soap, a few towels,
and nice clean water
for you to freshen up.
- Do you like it, son?
- It's not bad for a couple nights.
Right, honey?
Don't worry about us.
Since you're both here,
we got you something, I hope you like it.
- What's this?
- It's a tie, Hermès.
A tie! Just what I needed!
Chanel No. 5, the classic.
If you don't like them,
Mari can exchange them.
No, Pancho, I can't.
Maybe you should've bought them yourself.
We'll let you get settled.
- Let's go.
- Thanks, Dad.
- What's that?
- Rest up, son.
- Mom, it's a leg.
- Great-grandpa's leg.
What?
Pancho!
- Have you seen...?
- Oh, I almost forgot!
Later today, we're having
a little welcome party,
to celebrate your homecoming.
Don't let us down.
We'll be there, Dad. Thank you.
- Come on, honey.
- All right.
You don't expect us to stay here, do you?
Not only is this place filthy,
it's your dead grandpa's room!
That's his leg. This is a nightmare!
Should we book a room
in the village Hilton?
Didn't you hear they're
throwing us a party?
Sorry, but I can't insult
my family like that.
Yes, but this is a dump!
- It smells like poor people!
- Listen, María Elena.
I told you I came from a humble family,
and you always said you didn't mind.
Also, don't you forget I know exactly
how your white-trash parents
made their money.
So, please spare me
the aristocrat routine.
Come on, honey.
Don't be silly, stop crying.
Everything will be okay.
It's only a couple days, I promise.
Pancho, it's just...
I'm sorry for all that stuff
I said about your family,
but this is even worse
than my worst nightmare.
I need to tell you something
but don't get mad.
- What is it, champ?
- I need a bathroom.
- So do I.
- Number one, or two?
- Poop, maybe the squirts.
- Me too!
Hurry, come with me before it's too late.
- Run, run!
- Oh God, me too!
All right, kids.
Go that way, pick a tree,
pull your pants down,
and watch out for bugs.
I'll get you toilet paper. Hurry, guys.
- What, here?!
- Yes, here.
Pancho, are you telling me
there's no bathroom?
There's an outhouse,
but trust me, this is better.
Well, since I'm here.
- How you doing, kids?
- Fine!
Good.
Let's hear it, family!
Thanks, Dad!
Pancho, welcome again. Here's to you.
Thanks, Dad. Cheers.
Thank you for this party,
you went all-out.
Cheers!
You and your family deserve nothing less.
Really, we're all so happy
to have you here.
Hang on, Hilario! Wait a minute.
Hold it, guys.
Wait just a second,
I have a few words to say.
Kids, get over here!
Hey there, little guy!
My dear family.
This is a very special day
for your mother and me.
Seeing all of you together,
but especially,
having my son Pancho
and his family with us,
is more than I've ever dared to dream.
Please don't take this the wrong way,
but Pancho has always been my favorite,
and without a doubt the best of you lot.
Cheers, son. Cheers, Mariquita.
One more time, welcome to Prosperidad.
- Cheers, everyone!
- Cheers!
Say something, son! Don't be shy.
No way, no.
- Yeah, come on!
- Speech! Speech!
Do it, Dad!
First, I'd like to thank you
for your kind welcome.
After so many years,
my family and I are ecstatic
to be with all of you
right here in Prosperidad.
In order to keep this short,
let me tell you something from the heart.
This goes especially to mom and dad.
I hope you can forgive me
for not coming sooner,
and for abandoning you all this time.
I'm sorry.
- Cheers.
- Very nice, Pancho!
Still, we're only staying
for a couple of days.
We have to get back
to the capital soon, right?
- Yes, honey.
- Don't worry, son.
First thing tomorrow, we'll bury him.
Afterwards, we'll all get together
including your uncles,
and have the notary read the will.
Sounds great. Grandma Pascuala,
How are my uncles, Regino and Ambrosio?
I wish they were dead.
Unfortunately, those asswipes
are still a waste of oxygen.
I wish you would've invited them, Dad.
No way.
I'd rather die than let those pricks
set foot in this house.
Quiet, Rosendo!
I'm not surprised to see Dolores,
the slut,
coming to the defense of her boyfriend.
Shut up, Doña Pascuala!
Always stirring the pot
with your lies, old hag!
Don't disrespect my mother!
What she said is true.
Everyone knows you were
whoring around with Regino.
Your mother's the whore,
you piece of shit!
Stop her! Come on!
Play something, boys!
It's your song, Mom!
Ready? One, two..!
- Come on, Cati!
- One, two, here we go!
Beat the shit out of this fucking gringo!
Teach him to respect us Mexicans, Cati!
- All right, ready?
- Come on!
Stop that, sis. Put that down.
Try this, I made it for you
with all my love.
- What is it, Rufino?
- It's called Nenepil Norteño.
You won't find a better one
anywhere but Prosperidad.
- Is it very spicy?
- If you don't like it, spit it out.
Forget about manners, we're all family.
What do you think?
- It's delish!
- Delish.
- What is it called?
- Nenepil Norteño.
Next, I'll make you one
with fried chitterlings.
I'll show you how the local meat
is nothing to frown upon.
But first, let me get you another tequila.
Pancho, what's in Nenepil Norteño?
Don't ask, honey.
It's delish, I loved it. What's in it?
Fine, but I did warn you.
Nenepil is made
from the guts, liver, uterus,
and stomach of the pig, cooked in salsa.
It's a local delicacy.
- Delicious.
- Sis!
Another tequila? There you go!
- Pour me some.
- Do you have any lime?
Who wants tequila?
Cheers, boys! Take a quick break.
Don't be snotty! Come dance!
Come dance with us, it's a great song.
I'm not taking no for an answer.
Let's do this!
Bravo!
Let's take a family picture!
- Gather around.
- Wait, I'll go get Grandma.
Come with me, Mom. We're taking a picture.
I'm not doing that nonsense!
- Yes, you are.
- Come on, Grandma!
Fucking bullshit!
- Make room for Grandma.
- Don't push me around!
Say cheese on three. One, two, three.
Cheese!
Pancho, wait up!
Get in there, I'll take another one
so you're also in the picture.
- Thanks, bro. Make it vertical.
- Sister.
Say cheese on three.
- Cheese!
- On three, guys.
One... two...
I spy Rosendito and Lupita
kissing on a tree!
Get out of here, brats!
Go on, scram!
- Get out of here!
- Wait, don't...
The best thing I ever did
was leave this one-horse town,
and move to the capital.
Panchito, is it as nice as people say?
If we could get rid of
all the people there,
Mexico City would be
the nicest place in the world.
Would you take me there
and show me around?
- Well, I...
- Would you?
If we ever get a chance,
I'll show you anything.
Kids, it's time for bed. Go to your rooms.
No!
I'll go get the belt, then.
I'm not joking around.
Come on, quickly!
Go to sleep!
Night, Rosendito.
Why don't we take this
somewhere more private?
- I love a good secret.
- Me too! Let's go.
Good night.
Oh, come on.
- Here you go.
- Yes?
- One last drink.
- No.
What do you mean it's 15,000 pesos
for some pig meat and seasoned turkey?
You're kidding me, Don Pancracio!
Plus, one whole lamb,
nine pounds of Nenepil.
six pounds of cracklings,
ten pounds of guacamole.
Plus, a barrel of pulque,
twenty cases of beer,
and ten bottles of tequila.
Then, there's the tent,
the lights, and the chairs.
Give me a break, Don Rosendo!
Let me see if my children
can chip in, I'll be back.
Excuse me, Dad?
Can we add the boys' fee to the party tab?
- You said it was your treat!
- Only the first three songs.
We owe them for the rest.
See how angry they look?
It's only 7,000 pesos.
- I'll see what I can do.
- All right, Dad.
Come on, honey.
Look at these!
That's right. Get in there, just dive in.
Sorry to interrupt.
Can we talk with you for a moment?
Of course, Dad, certainly.
Good evening, ma'am.
All right, then.
- What's up, Dad?
- Son, we're sorry to ask,
but even after everyone chipped in,
we don't have enough to pay for the party.
Sure, no worries. How much?
Everything, including music,
comes to $25,000 pesos.
- How much do you have?
- After dipping into our savings,
we're still short almost by half.
Dad, that's pretty steep
for a house party.
Let me see.
I'll take this.
If there's anything left,
I'll bring it back to you.
Let's go, honey.
All right.
This is the last one, for real.
I have a question, sis.
Are those killer tits and ass
wholly natural,
or is that surgery?
My boobs, my ass, and my hair.
- Everything natural.
- I'd kill for that body.
- Same.
- Lupe!
My brother mentioned you were pretty,
but the bastard didn't say this much.
Hot damn! You're drop-dead gorgeous!
I'm going to bed.
- Come on, stay a while.
- Excuse me.
If she's leaving, let's call it a night.
- I'm calling it a night.
- Party's over.
- You spilled my tequila!
- Stubborn old drunks.
One more drink, a poem for everyone!
O Sweet Land!
Your surface is the gold of maize.
Your mines, the palace
of the King of Gold.
Herons gliding across the skies,
and the green flash of the parrots!
- And some other--
- Hey, you.
Tell your idiot husband
to shut the fuck up,
and find me some of that barbacoa meat.
- I want one more taquito.
- Sure, Grandma.
I keep thinking about
the way your parents talk.
And the fat mariachis!
And how your brother Rufino
wouldn't stop flirting with me.
Your sisters treat me
like the Princess of Monaco.
See? Not everyone is as lucky as we are.
Do you know who is the luckiest guy
in the whole wide world?
Who, honey?
- Do you want it?
- Yes, please.
Don't wake the kids, hurry up.
Move over.
- Here it comes.
- Hurry.
Keep it down.
- Pancho!
- What?
- Someone's spying on us!
- It's too dark outside.
Run!
Sons of bitches.
All these years and they haven't changed.
Fuck you!
What happened?
Who was it? Oh, no!
Relax, honey. It was only my nephews,
they didn't see much.
- Oh, okay.
- Don't worry.
Where were we?
You were about to fuck me
with those muscles.
- These muscles, sexy?
- Oh, yes!
Oh, that's good.
Keep it down, Pancho.
Dad, can you tell me what's
"Moctezuma's revenge"?
It's what happens to gringos
when they visit Mexico.
- Why, champ?
- I know I'm not a gringo,
- But I think I got it.
- Me too.
Oh, man. Hurry up!
Come on, hurry.
I think I got it, too.
We're going with Socorro if it's a girl.
If it's a boy, Jacinto.
What the hell?
- Life's so unfair, man.
- Why?
How is it that Pancho is doing so well,
while we get fucked day in and day out?
I wonder what Pancho's wife
thought about us.
Easy. That we're lowlifes
without class or manners.
And she'd be right, it's the truth.
Judging by their SUV,
his watch, and those outfits,
they're rolling in it.
Imagine the palace they must live in.
Did you see the jewelry
on that stuck-up bitch?
Those earrings, that watch,
the necklace, the bracelet.
I know these things,
she was probably wearing
around $100,000 pesos.
And her scent, Gloria. French perfume.
Well, that doesn't make them
any less sinful or indecent.
Tell me, Jacinto... Sorry, I meant Jacinta!
How much is Pancho worth?
Just a ballpark guess.
I don't know, but a lot.
Maybe a million dollars?
Don't be stupid!
If he had a million dollars,
why would he come
to this town full of thieves?
Who cares how loaded my brother is?
It's up to us to make sure
we get some of it, right?
- Cheers!
- Cheers to that, bro!
Oh, look.
Uncle Ambrosio!
Good to see you, how are you?
Fine, my son.
Meet my wife, Mari, and my children.
- Nice to meet you, my child.
- Likewise, Father Ambrosio.
Cute children.
- I hope they're baptized.
- Of course they are.
In fact, Toni is getting ready
for his First Communion.
- Right, champ?
- Yes, Dad!
What a nice smile.
So you finally decided to come, Panchito.
I'm glad, because if years of abandonment
had doomed your soul to Purgatory,
missing your grandpa's funeral
would be your ticket to Hell.
How can you think that?
Grandpa always was like a father to me.
Yeah, right.
What brought you here to Prosperidad
was greed for his will,
but we'll talk later.
We better get on with the funeral,
before the smell starts
attracting the buzzards.
Shall we, pallbearer?
- Pallbearer?
- What?
- Good day, everyone.
- Good morning.
Fucking sissy.
Ready?
May God take mercy on his soul.
Let's go.
The Lord has gathered us on this day
to bid farewell to a great man.
Our dear father and grandfather,
Don Francisco Reyes,
is finally at peace
and has risen to Heaven
to be with the Lord.
Yet, his memory and example
shall live on in our hearts.
A man of integrity, generous,
hard-working, and honest.
A good husband, and a better
father and grandfather.
May his legacy be a light to us all.
- A beacon in our path--
- Listen up, Ambrosio.
Cut the bullshit and get on with it.
Your father was
a miserable son of a bitch.
So, wrap it up already
because it's getting hot.
I'm sorry, mother. Let us pray.
For fuck's sake.
Here comes the hurdle.
The last thing we needed
was him and his tramp.
- I'll give him a piece of my mind.
- Calm down, Rosendo!
Francisco was his father, too.
Don't make a scene at his funeral.
Mommy!
- Godson.
- Hi, there.
Excuse you.
I'm sorry I couldn't come sooner.
I can't tell you how upset I was
when I heard the news,
or how much I've cried since then.
Spare me your lies, you shameless bastard.
Your father was sick for a long time,
and he's been dead for three days,
yet you never visited him
or paid your respects.
Stop being a hypocrite.
I need you, your floozy,
and that tumor you call a son
to start praying like the rest of us,
so we can be done with this bullshit,
and we can get to the reading of the will.
Yes, mother. My apologies, again.
I'm so sorry. Really sorry, Granny.
I was also very upset at Grandpa's death.
Get out of my face, you hemorrhoid!
Let us proceed.
Good afternoon, everyone.
Afternoon, counselor.
In accordance with
Don Francisco's final wishes,
I will commence reading his will.
In the town of Prosperidad,
of the same municipality,
Don Francisco Reyes Vargas
appears before me.
He declares he is Mexican by birth,
miner by trade,
and a citizen of this municipality,
where he was born
on the 21st of April, 1897.
Being of sound mind and body,
and expecting you've honored his last wish
of having all his family present
for this solemn occasion,
he manifests and declares
the following testament.
To his great-grandchildren,
great-great-grandchildren,
and further descendants,
whose name he doesn't know,
he hereby bequeaths a 20-peso coin each,
in the hope that, by investing it wisely,
they will forge their own
path through life.
Eat shit!
Everyone out!
To his dear grandchildren,
Rosendito,
Hilario,
Socorro,
Rufino,
Jacinto,
or Jacinta, as she likes to be called,
Reginito,
and Bartola,
he hereby passes on his donkey, his cow,
his turkey, and his three pigs,
so they can split them
however they see fit.
To his daughter-in-law Dolores García,
in appreciation for one
memorable night of passion,
he passes on his precious
Virgin of Guadalupe medal.
To his son Ambrosio,
who, as a good Christian,
and representative of God on Earth,
attributes no value to material goods,
he hereby leaves one Our Father,
and three Hail Marys.
Screw you, Dad.
To his son Regino, who among his children
was the only one
to lead a successful life,
and realized his dream of becoming
a thieving, corrupt,
bloodsucking politician,
he leaves a second-hand, highlighted copy
of the Treatise on Morality,
like the ones the government
handed out in town.
- Let's go.
- To his son Rosendo,
who among the triplets
was the only one
who followed his footsteps
and took up mining,
he passes on his pickaxe,
his shovel, and his cart,
so he can keep pursuing
his ridiculous dream
of finding a gold-bearing vein
in the old Esperanza mine.
To his beloved companion
for so many years,
Doña Pascuala Vargas García,
he passes on nothing less
than his deepest gratitude,
and wishes that her time in this world
isn't prolonged for too long
so she can soon join him.
Fucking Francisco Reyes!
You were a fucking asshole
until the very end!
I hope you rot in hell, you piece of shit!
Say, Mr. Counselor.
If he didn't leave anything to any of us,
who the goddamn fuck is getting the house
and all his belongings,
according to that asshole?
Allow me, Doña Pascuala,
I haven't finished yet.
Lastly,
it his his will to appoint
as the universal heir
to the rest of his assets,
including the house,
the old Esperanza Mine,
with all its tunnels and surrounding land,
as well any movable
and immovable assets therein,
as well as the items that
over the course of his life,
he dutifully stored in his personal safe,
of which yours truly is appointed
guardian, executor, and steward,
to his grandson Francisco,
who among his descendants was the only one
whose hard work, effort, and dedication--
What the fuck?!
You'll have to excuse me, Mr. Counselor,
but I don't believe a word you just read.
Dad wouldn't have fucked us over
and left everything to Pancho!
He hadn't heard from him
in over twenty years!
I'm sorry, Don Rosendo!
Those were Don Francisco's last wishes.
Don't blame me,
I'm just the messenger.
Listen up, fuckers!
Leave Mr. Toribio alone!
Knowing that asshole Francisco,
I'm sure the will is true.
He hated all of us!
All we can do,
is hope that Panchito takes pity on us
and shares his inheritance
with the rest of us.
- More beans, husband?
- No, Lola.
I bet these welfare beans
from the government
have weevils in them,
I always get so gassy.
I'll take some, Mom.
I like those critters.
- I want some too, Grandma.
- Sorry, that's all we had.
Grandma gave away
all the leftovers last night.
You didn't save anything
for Pancho and his family?
You didn't invite them to eat with us?
I did, but as soon as they got back,
they went into their room
and haven't come out.
What can we feed them?
Rancid welfare beans?
Old tortillas?
Your daughter-in-law will have a fit!
What if we slaughter a chicken or a pig?
Are you crazy?! Those are my animals!
I'm saving them
for my wife's 15th birthday.
Curse this misery!
How much worse can things get?
For the millionth time,
don't be a crybaby.
Act like a man!
We've spent years eating
what we can, when we can,
and you've never whined
like a little bitch.
Sure, but I hoped that Dad
would leave us something
that would turn our luck.
You heard the counselor,
the old man had a safe!
He's right, Grandma.
I heard him mention a safe.
I heard it, too.
I wonder what's in it.
Something valuable, for sure.
Who the fuck cares what's in it?
Probably old documents, some photographs.
Nothing of value,
because I'm sure the old bastard
spent every last dime
on whores and booze!
I'll say it again.
How much worse can it get?
May I?
- Come on in, son!
- Excuse me.
- Where are the kids?
- They're asleep.
They got sunstroke after the procession.
I'm sorry, son. There's no more food,
but I can send Bartola
to fetch some tamales.
Don't worry, Mom.
We're still full from the party.
We don't feel so good. Right, Mari?
Are you sure, son?
Doña Pancha's green chili
tamales are the best!
- And we have a tab.
- That's okay, Dad.
All we came here to say
is that we had a long talk,
and we think we understand
how you must be feeling.
We think Grandpa was unfair
in the way he split his assets.
- More than unfair!
- Settle down. Settle down.
Even though I got the house,
the mine, and the land,
nothing will change for all of you.
I told you, fuckers!
Pancho is the best son in the world!
Brayan, Dudinka!
Go and find Don Pancracio.
Tell him to send us a pig
and tequila to celebrate!
Hilario, go get your boys!
We'll need music!
- Right away!
- Tell him I want lamb!
Also some cracklings, but hold the hair.
- Oh, my God.
- Fran, I don't feel good.
It's just a hangover.
Champ, be careful!
Good morning!
- Morning.
- Good morning, all.
Morning, sleepyheads. Did you sleep well?
More or less.
- Where's Dad? And my brothers?
- They're running errands.
They'll be back later to take you to town.
I'm making you a nice breakfast
to cure your hangover.
I'm sure it's a bad one.
I made some menudo, nice and spicy.
Also, some chilaquiles
in a three-chili salsa.
I'm sorry, Doña Dolores.
I don't feel well, excuse me.
Honey, eat something
to settle your stomach!
Doesn't the madame like Mexican food?
Snotty fart-smelling bitch.
That's not it, Grandma.
The food didn't agree with her,
she was up all night.
Let's make her some tea
with epazote, jimsonweed--
Mom, don't bother.
- Morning, son!
- Hi, Dad.
- Ready to go into town?
- I'm ready.
Wait, son! Sorry to bother you,
but can you lend me some money
to give to Doña Cata
to pay for breakfast and today's lunch?
Panchito. Can I get something
for my hemorrhoid cream,
and for my cigarettes?
Thank you!
- I'll keep it safe for you.
- No.
Son, pull over for a second.
- Here?
- Yes, here. Come.
Look, son. All this is now yours.
How far do the lands extend?
- See the house?
- Yeah.
The property line starts here
where the cross is,
and it ends all the way
at the bottom of the mountains.
How come you never grew crops,
or raised cattle to put it to some use?
Son, clearly you've spent
too long in the city.
All that grows here
is a few desert plants,
some prickly plants, and bitterness.
The only animals are
black snakes, spiders,
and venomous scorpions,
isn't that right, Rosendito?
If you and my brothers weren't so lazy,
you would've used this land to get ahead.
See? It's the same as when I left.
No, Pancho.
We haven't been lazying around.
Isn't that right, Rosendito?
We work from sunrise to sundown every day.
I can prove it.
We have a surprise for you.
Remember the old mine?
How could I forget the Refugio tunnel.
I spent my entire childhood
helping Grandpa.
He used to bring you out here
every Saturday.
Well, you own it now.
We've been coming here every third day.
We've been making surveys,
cleaning up, and drawing up plans.
Open the gate, son.
The thing is that, for the longest time,
Grandpa Francisco, Rosendito, and myself,
we've been making plans
to open it up again.
Believe it or not,
I'm sure that behind those rocks,
hides the world's largest
gold-bearing vein.
- Right, Rosendito?
- You said it, Pops!
Dad, forget about those old dreams.
According to Grandpa,
who knew more than anyone,
the gold in this mine
was emptied years ago.
No way, son!
Even the fucking gringos and the Canadians
have been coming around to check it out.
Like a bunch of blond-haired vultures!
What are you talking about? Listen.
As far back as I can remember,
you've clung to this fantasy.
And, look! Twenty years later, and your
laziness has kept everything the same.
I needed a partner
and money to get it going!
But now that you're rich and came back,
We can finally do it!
Listen to me, Dad. Don't take this wrong,
but I'm only back in town
for a couple days
to see about the will
and attend the funeral,
so I better hurry along
if I want to sort everything out.
Why don't we get to town
so I can sort things out
with the counselor and my godfather?
- What do you say?
- Sure, son.
Promise me you'll think about the mine.
I swear we could make
billions off of this!
All right, then.
I promise to think about it.
Come on, let's go.
Come on, Rosendito! Get a move on!
BIENESTAR BANK
Wish me luck, Dad.
I'll see you at the cantina.
- I'll tell you how it went.
- All right, son.
Don't let that asshole Regino
push you around.
He sure loves his bribes
and backroom deals.
Be careful, brother.
Keep an eye on your wallet.
- See you later.
- All right.
- Good morning.
- Morning.
- I'm looking for Mayor Reyes.
- Through there.
Thanks.
- Good morning.
- Morning.
Good day, I'd like to see
Don Regino Reyes.
- Is he expecting you?
- Unfortunately, no.
I'm his nephew, I was hoping he'd see me.
Are you the mayor's relative,
the one from the capital?
The one who got
Don Francisco's inheritance?
Francisco Reyes, at your service.
News sure seem to spread
like wildfire in this town.
Oh, sir.
I'm sorry, but the mayor
is a very busy man.
Still, seeing as it's you,
I'll ask Commander Reyes.
- He's in charge of his schedule.
- I really appreciate it.
Thank you so much.
What's up, Reginito?
Don't you remember me?
I'm your cousin Pancho!
I'm sorry we didn't get a chance
to talk yesterday.
What's up, Pancho? Did you only
come back for the inheritance?
Don't be silly, that's not the reason.
Reginito, do you think
I can see my godfather?
First of all, don't call me Reginito.
It's Commander Reyes, got it?
Sorry, but the mayor can't see you
without an appointment.
I understand, Commander.
Can you tell him I'm here?
I just want to check
the paperwork for the house.
No can do.
I'll check his schedule
to pencil you in for next week.
Meanwhile, take a seat.
I have a lot of work to do.
Thanks a lot.
The apple doesn't fall far from the tree.
Take this to pass the time.
It's going to be a long wait.
Thanks, doll. I appreciate
your help with those gringos.
I'll drop by later tonight
for another English lesson.
Bye, honey.
My dearest godson! I'm so glad to see you.
Same here, godfather.
- Why were you sitting there?
- I was hoping to see you.
- How's the town treating you?
- Just fine.
You know how things work in Prosperidad.
Did this asshole tell you
you couldn't come in?
No, not at all.
I'm in a bit of a rush,
I only have a couple days
to sort out the house and the inheritance.
Listen up, Reginito!
Get this through your head.
Pancho here is like a son to me,
and he's free to walk in, got it?
Of course, Dad!
I've told you over an over
not to call me Dad here.
You'll get me accused of nepotism.
Get lost, check what's out there.
Make sure no one bothers me
so I can talk to my godson.
- Come on in.
- Later, Commander.
Couldn't be more corrupt!
They only admit gringos
and rich guys with connections.
- Have a seat, Godson.
- Thanks.
What have you been up to all this time?
Well, things were rocky for a bit
when I first got to Mexico City.
You know how shitty
those city folks can be.
They treated me like garbage.
Things started to turn around
once I graduated,
found myself a job, and got married.
I have two wonderful kids.
So, now I'm here, back in Prosperidad.
I see that you switched political parties.
Oh, son. Times have changed.
PRI no longer serves this country.
The party was ruined
by corruption and impunity.
Then I tried PAN,
but it was the same thing,
except they're also
God-fearing hypocrites.
And today, at the hands of our President,
the country is undergoing
its fourth transformation.
Things are better than ever!
And he's magically put an end
to corruption and impunity.
Now, I guess you're here and very happy,
because of your grandfather's inheritance.
Honestly, besides coming to visit you,
I was hoping you could help with
the paperwork for the house,
and to get in touch
with the notary to get my stuff.
Don't worry about all that,
I'll gladly help you.
- Thank you so much.
- However,
before you can take possession
and put everything in your name,
you need to be up to date
with all the property's expenses,
settle the mortgage,
and any outstanding utility bills.
How much are we talking about?
That doesn't include interest
or late-payment fees.
Your family hasn't paid bills
or property tax for years.
What? Is it too much?
I'm not sure the house and land
are even worth this much.
Is there any way
we can come to an arrangement?
Francisco, damn it!
I just told you the President
put an end to corruption!
Check this out. Educate yourself.
Plus, you can drop the act.
I can tell you're rich.
Anyway, you've always known
you're my favorite nephew.
That's why I'm going to help you.
Really, Godfather? How?
- I'll give you two options.
- Lay 'em on me.
First option, you settle the debt
in a single payment,
and I'll waive the interest
and the surcharges.
What's the second one?
- Sell me the property.
- What, all of it?
- The house, the mine, the land?
- All of it.
Where would that leave
my parents and siblings?
Of course, I would let them
keep living in the house,
at least until my mother passes away.
After that, those parasites
you call your family
will have to figure it out on their own.
Forgive me, Godfather,
but I can't do that to them.
Think it over, son.
That's all I can do to help.
I'm very interested
in buying that property.
Let me think about it.
With all due respect, you're putting me
in a very awkward position.
You got it. Don't take too long though,
the interest is increasing.
You'll have to excuse me,
but as you can see,
the country needs me
and the noble masses await.
Sure.
Look at this dress! Isn't it pretty?
Do you think she'll mind if I keep it?
She won't even notice, she has so many!
Look, Mom!
This the good stuff, the madame's jewels!
Enough, thieving bitches!
Put everything back!
Put that watch down!
How dare you steal from me!
- And you, fucking lowborn!
- Screw you, cunt!
What did you call me?
I'll teach you not to take
what doesn't belong to you!
THE EAGLE AND THE SNAKE CANTINA
- Cheers, buddy.
- Cheers!
Cástulo, get us a bottle
and beer for everyone!
My son Pancho is treating us!
- Hey, you.
- Sit with us, son.
Are you paying their tab?
It's over 3,000 pesos already.
- It's fine.
- Come on, bring a chair.
Look, my friends.
This is my son Francisco,
the one I've been telling you about.
The best and brightest
of the Reyes family.
- Thanks. Hello.
- Remember him?
Sure, we met earlier at Regino's office.
Right, that was you.
I didn't know it was Pancho. Welcome back.
So, how did it go with that bastard?
I'm not sure.
It turns out that the property
is in a lot of debt,
and I can't take possession
until the debt is paid.
That's the typical bullshit
from that asshole Regino!
You should've paid it all to shut him up.
That's the thing, Dad.
You haven't paid a dime in so many years--
Never mind that, son. We'll talk later.
I was just telling my buddies
you're going to lend me
the money to reopen
the old Esperanza mine.
I heard him say it. I swear to God.
Congrats, Panchito.
I hope you can finally make
your dad's dream come true.
Honestly, Don Rosendo,
you're lucky to have such a great son.
Not only good, buddy. He's rich as hell!
And without a doubt,
the best of my children.
Gathered around an old cantina table,
we find six to eight men,
like a group of hippies!
Here we go!
Come on, son. Tip your brother-in-law.
Also, pay the boys to sing us a few songs.
Fine, Dad.
Cheers, gentlemen!
Stupid Pancho!
There's no service.
Screw this town.
Screw those bitches from hell!
You bitches don't know
who you're messing with!
Wait till you see what hot chicks
are in my son-in-law's whorehouse.
- Hello, Florcita.
- Hi, there.
- Where's my son-in-law and the missus?
- They're upstairs.
I'll add the girls to your tab.
You can square up with the boss.
All right.
Come on, sweetheart. I'm feeling romantic.
Listen up, girls.
I want you to take care of my son Pancho.
Show him a good time.
Catrina, make sure he's happy
because he's paying for this.
- Isn't that right, son?
- Sure, Dad.
Why hello, Panchito.
Which one of us tickles your fancy?
Or would you prefer a ménage à trois?
Don't worry, ladies.
I'll just wait for those two.
Have a seat, I'll treat you
to some tequila while we wait.
Oh, Panchito! such a party pooper.
It's like you're not one of the Reyes.
Yes, thankfully.
Have a seat.
Manuela, bring some beer!
Stop crying, baby.
Those big, beautiful eyes
are going to get puffy.
I assure you that my girl
meant nothing by it.
No one had ever called me
something so awful, Rufino.
Besides, Pancho left early this morning,
and I think he's forgotten all about us.
Come on, now. Have some more tequila.
Drink this, and look, forget about Pancho.
He probably ran into an ex
and is having some fun.
You think Pancho is capable
of cheating on me, Rufino?
Jeez.
I don't know if my bro is still a player,
but when he was young,
that son of a bitch slept
with every single girl in town.
Oh, no!
Hey, hey.
None of them were as beautiful as you.
None of them had such pretty eyes.
- What?
- Yeah.
- Or such a smoking body.
- Do you mean it, Rufino?
Do you really think I'm beautiful?
Like an angel.
Not like an angel.
You're more beautiful
than the Virgin Mary.
Oh, Rufino.
Sure, I can get you a job
at a strip club in the city.
It's a classy joint.
Fucking Jacinta!
I told you, clients can't leave
without paying first!
Stop hitting me, Lupe!
He said he was taking a leak,
but he climbed out the window.
I'm not buying it!
You're a common slut who flirts
with every guy who walks in!
Take this!
- You bitch!
- Are you okay, bro?
You listen to me, Lupe.
That's no way of treating
my brother, back off!
Is that so?
Turns out the little lord
has some balls after all!
I can throw a punch.
Come at me, then!
I thought you had balls!
Let's see if you can dance.
Enough, Guadalupe! Don't be such a beast.
Pancho is going to think
we're a bunch of animals.
Look, why don't I get you
a nice shot of tequila,
so you can settle down
and drink with old friends?
- How's that?
- All right.
- Thanks, bro.
- Sorry about that.
If I'm not tough on them,
the business is fucked.
No worries, Lupe. No big deal.
- Cheers, then.
- Cheers.
Cheers bro.
Enough about this.
But listen to me, though.
Just so we're good,
I think you should pay
for the drinks and the girls.
Yes, of course.
What's up, son? Everything good?
- You having fun?
- Sure thing, Dad.
Now it's a party!
That's good, son.
Shit, hold on!
Come on, son.
Let's ask your mother
to make us some dinner.
- We'll sleep better.
- I'll catch up.
First, I have to check on
Mari and the kids.
I've told you to act like a man,
don't be such a wuss.
- That's how you spoil a woman.
- I'll be right there.
- I'll see you in a sec!
- All right, Pancho.
- Who is it?
- Who else, my love?
It's me, Pancho. Your husband.
- Open up, María Elena.
- I'm coming.
- Pancho!
- What's with that stick?
We have to leave this place.
I had the worst day.
I hate your family more each day.
Honey, what's wrong?
Your mom poisoned me with some tea
and I was passed out all day.
Then, the women came in
to steal what they could.
They touched all my stuff
and I was so angry
that I got in a fight
with that slut Gloria!
- What do you--?
- Pancho!
There's something else
I don't want the kids to hear.
- Oh, Pancho...
- What is it?
Your brother Rufino came into our room
and tried to force himself on me.
Honey, honey. You're drinking too much.
I think it's the booze
because hear me out.
My family might not have the best manners,
but stealing, poisoning,
and seducing you by force?
I'm sorry, but that's not who they are.
You're wrong, Dad! Mom is right.
Our cousins stole and broke our iPads.
It's true! Those rude kids
cut my doll's head off.
Look!
They tore up my teddy bear!
Oh, my goodness.
I'll have a serious talk with them.
This is completely unacceptable.
My family is sick of you. They're scared.
No one here would ever hurt your family!
We're so happy you're here!
Isn't that right, everyone?
- Yes, of course.
- So happy.
I have to believe Mari and my kids.
It's probably a culture clash.
Your wife and children
are rich and spoiled,
they're not used to our country ways!
I'm sorry to be blunt,
but your wife has
a serious drinking problem.
- She's drinking like a fish!
- Wait, Mom.
I've been married to her for 15 years!
In all that time, she's never been drunk.
Let me be clear, as soon as
I sort things out with the notary,
hopefully tomorrow, I'm going back
to the city! Do you hear me?
Mr. Panchito, this is so hard for me,
but before you go back,
I need to ask you a favor.
- What is it?
- See, Hilario and I,
we want you and Mrs. Mari
to be the godparents to our kid.
Are you crazy, Pánfila?
If anything, Panchito will be
the godfather to my twins.
Both of you are fucking delusional.
I spoke with Uncle Ambrosio
and reserved the church,
so that Pancho can baptize my kids.
Quiet, you shrews!
Don't talk to my wife like that!
Besides, Pancho agreed
to produce my album.
Can you buy me a few cows first?
Screw that! Lupe and I need money
to hire more girls for the brothel.
- Pancho promised already.
- Over my dead body!
He's lending us the money
for a truck and a real gun.
- Put that down!
- It's fake!
For fuck's sake!
If you can't be civil about this,
you can all fuck off.
Thanks, Dad.
You're acting like vultures,
circling a carcass.
Pancho is only helping me
to open the old mine back up.
- He already promised, didn't you, son?
- What did you say, Dad?
Fucking Panchito!
Don't be a fucking moron.
Tell everyone to fuck off.
If you were any smarter,
you'd leave this very night.
If you don't, before you know it,
this sorry group of bloodsucking pests
will take the fucking clothes
right off your back!
- Ignore her, she has dementia.
- Grandma Pascuala is right.
I made a huge mistake coming back here.
I'm leaving! I'm fucking leaving!
I told you, fuckers.
I hope we didn't kill the goose
that lays the golden eggs.
- We're finally home.
- Thank God, Fran.
I thought we'd never leave
that goddamned town.
I hear you, honey. We're never going back,
and we'll never have to see
my dreadful family again.
Surprise!
What's up, Pancho? What took you so long?
I hope you don't mind, but we felt like
making a nice lunch
to welcome you, sit down.
Praise the Lord you got home safe!
You see, Panchito?
I told you you'd never
get rid of us, fucker!
- Fran? Fran!
- No! What?
Wake up! There's a police car outside.
I'm too afraid to go out.
- Go see what they want.
- All right.
Oh, my goodness.
What's going on?
What's all this fuss about?
Sorry to bother you so late, but...
- We really need your help!
- What happened?
They caught that idiot Rufino
selling drugs in the square,
and your cousin Reginito
wants to put him in jail.
Panchito, the trouble is
this is his sixth offense.
That orangutan wants
to take him to a federal prison.
If he does, no amount of gold
will be enough to get him out.
Let me talk to Reginito.
Give me a fucking break.
God bless you, son!
God bless you!
I'll be right back, honey.
You're such a good man, bro.
He's a hard-working man,
what's the charge?
Evening, Commander.
What's up, Pancho?
Did your parents tell you
what your brother did?
Yes, they did. That's why I'm here.
Is there any way we can
get all this cleared up?
Look, Pancho. Your brother's been charged
with very serious crimes.
I can't cut him loose
for less than ten grand.
Brother! My soul brother!
You're such a good man,
pay him what he wants,
I promise to pay you back.
I only have three grand,
so it's up to you.
- Take it or leave it.
- Damn it, Pancho.
You take advantage of me
because we're relatives.
Fine, let him out.
Thank you, bro.
Seriously, thank you.
You're an angel, man.
I promise to pay you back.
I'll give you double! Double!
Come on, boys!
MUNICIPAL POLICE
Morning, sleepyhead. Why so late, huh?
What do you mean?
It was you guys who didn't let me sleep.
Let me make you some breakfast.
Huevos rancheros? Chilaquiles?
I don't want anything.
Tell this to the others,
I ask nothing of you,
so you ask nothing of me.
Once I settle the papers with the notary,
I'm leaving forever, did you hear me?
Morning, son!
What's gotten into him?
I bet it's something he ate.
I have an idea to cheer him up.
Follow me, son.
Damn it.
Sorry, bro! I'm so embarrassed.
- I didn't know you were here.
- Don't worry, I'm almost done.
So, listen.
We're so very grateful
for what you did last night.
Rufino and I would like
to show you our gratitude.
Don't worry, with some luck,
he'll pay me back one day.
Why wait?
Rufino sent me to give you an advance.
- Oh, my God.
- You like?
Well, fuck it. It's the only payment
I'm going to get.
Come here.
- Come on, do it!
- Hold on.
Hurry.
Yes, yes!
Just like that! Give it to me.
What is it, honey?
Can't you go to him?
We've been waiting all day.
Go where, exactly?
It's going to get dark,
and the roads aren't safe.
Remember your friend Mapache and his men?
- I'll be waiting.
- Okay.
There he is! That's him pulling in.
Kids, get your things.
Help me with the luggage, Lupita.
The safe is here!
- Lupita...
- What's that?
Afternoon, Mr. Reyes.
Good afternoon, sir.
I'm glad you finally made it.
Sorry about the delay.
To be straight, it's not easy
to move this monstrosity.
I see that, it's huge.
- Can I see some ID?
- Of course.
Let's see here.
- Here, it's all in order.
- Thank you.
Aside from the safe,
I'm going to deliver the deed,
as well as a letter
Don Francisco left you.
- Is there somewhere we can sit?
- You can take the dining room.
No thanks, Dad. We need privacy.
- This way, sir.
- Boys, unload the safe!
Have them take the safe
into our room, honey.
It's too big for the car,
but we'll figure it out.
- Yeah, okay.
- Follow me, sir.
Gentlemen? Follow me, please.
This way, thanks.
Kids, move.
Rufino, Hilario, Rosendo!
Let's give them a hand.
What do you think is in that big safe?
I have no idea, honey, but I won't go
to my grave without finding out.
Get out of the way, Cruz!
You're not helping!
Maybe we can strap it
to the roof of the car?
- The roof would collapse.
- Here it comes, guys!
- How will we take it home?
- Careful with the boards!
It's barely on the edge.
There you go.
Come on, Rosendo!
- Thanks, boys.
- May I borrow your pen? Thanks.
- Here's the full file.
- Thanks.
- Your grandfather's letter.
- I appreciate it.
- Your pen.
- Right.
I hope you don't mind a piece of advice.
In my experience,
it's best that you protect yourself.
If you only knew half the stuff I've seen,
or what some families can do
over an inheritance,
- you'd take note of my advice.
- Thanks, counselor.
I'll leave you to it.
- Excuse me, ma'am.
- Go ahead.
- Please!
- Clear the way.
Lupita, would you mind giving us a moment?
- Need a hand, bro?
- No, thanks.
- Wait, Pancho!
- Step back, thank you.
Give us a moment.
They're such pests!
Kids, close the windows.
Make sure no one sees.
Yes, Dad!
- Watch out, kids.
- Sure, Dad.
"Dear Pancho, if you're reading this,
I'm probably dead and burning up in Hell."
"If that bastard Buendía
followed my instructions,
you know my whole estate is now yours."
"At this time, you must be
standing before the safe."
"Here are the instructions
to crack it open."
"Follow them exactly and prepare yourself
for what you are about to find."
Will you help me?
"Left, 42."
"Right, 84."
"Left, 10."
Left, 10.
"Right, 31."
Nothing but trash.
That's trash. Grandpa's leg.
- Oh, God.
- It stinks.
Dirty old man.
Give me that.
That's trash.
Grandpa's gun.
How many did he kill?
We should keep it safe.
I'll take that.
- Check it out! Some wristwatches...
- Wristwatches!
...and his old medals,
we could sell all these.
Hear that, Mari?
Fucking Grandpa.
I knew he had something,
but I never expected this.
Mari... Mari!
Pancho!
It's beautiful!
Fucking Grandpa!
It's the most beautiful thing
I've ever seen!
How much is this worth?
The coins alone are worth
some twenty million pesos,
and the ingots probably 1.5 million each.
Mari, we're rich!
Not rich, Pancho. We're millionaires!
We can pay our debt
and buy a house, a car.
- We can change our lives.
- Not only that, honey.
We can finally change our social status!
Honey! What are they doing?
They're freaking out,
the safe was full of gold!
They're putting it back in the safe.
- Are we rich, Dad?
- Yes, son! We're rich!
Try to get a count on the ingots.
Twenty or so.
Plus, a bunch of nuggets,
maybe two pounds each.
Also, coins! Lots and lots of coins.
Are there enough coins
for every one of us?
Most definitely. Enough to go around!
"Anyway, dear Pancho,
I bid you farewell, wishing you the best
and hoping you continue
honoring the Reyes name."
"With all my love, Grandpa Francisco."
"P.S. As a token of love and appreciation,
I hope you build me a bigger
and better mausoleum
than the one they built
for Benito Juárez."
"Be careful with your relatives."
Put it all in the safe.
I'll go talk to them.
Pancho's coming! Act natural.
Wait for him to tell us the news himself.
Hurry up, kids. Everyone sit down.
Is that everyone?
What's going on?
Why do you look so serious?
It's nothing, son. We were just talking.
We're all broken up about
how we've been acting,
so we wanted to apologize
before you leave.
- Right, guys?
- Yes.
- You're family.
- I'm so sorry, Pancho.
Don't worry, Dad.
Time and distance will heal this wound.
So, we're definitely leaving.
Tomorrow before dawn.
Son, stay a few more days.
I promise we won't bother you.
I'm really sorry, Mom.
I've made up my mind.
Believe me, I deeply regret
how everything turned out.
Mari and the kids send their love,
and thank you for your hospitality.
From the bottom of my heart,
thanks for everything.
Thank you, and best regards.
- Uh, son...
- Hey, Panchito!
Just so I don't take
the curiosity to my grave,
what did you find inside
your grandpa's safe?
Just as you guessed, Grandma.
Old letters, photographs,
underpants, a brassiere,
and a few trinkets.
Don't worry, I'll leave it open
so you can go through it.
Sounds good, dear.
- Safe travels.
- Thanks, Grandma.
- God bless, son.
- Bye!
- Bye, kids!
That two-faced snake!
Just as petty and miserable
as his grandfather!
All right, fuckers. So, what?
Are we just going to sit here
while Pancho takes our gold?
No!
In that case, let's show him
what the Reyes are made of!
- Yeah!
- That's right!
Mr. Pancho!
Mr. Pancho, come quick!
Your car is burning!
Hurry up, sir!
I'm coming! I'm coming!
- What's going on?
- Your car's on fire!
I don't know what happened!
The car! Pancho!
Kids, stay with me.
- Lupita, did you see anything?
- No, sir.
I was asleep in the barn.
The animals just went crazy.
I started smelling smoke,
so I went outside
and I saw your car going up in flames.
That's when I ran to tell you.
Are you lying to me? Look me in the eye!
I swear I'm not lying!
Motherfuckers!
They'll be sorry for this!
I'll put them all in jail!
Mari, check over there.
I'll check the house.
- Selfish fucks!
- For fuck's sake!
Get out here! Where are you?
Jealous bums!
- Fuck this shit!
- There's no one here.
They're gone!
Those bastard are hiding,
they're up to something.
- Honey, come with me.
- Okay.
Lupita, stay here. If you see
anything strange, come get me, quick!
- Fucking run!
- Yes!
I'll be right back, sweeties.
Don't be afraid.
- Hurry, let's go!
- Be careful, sir.
Burning his car was a great idea.
Here's what I'm thinking.
Why don't we kidnap Pancho's children,
and demand the treasure as ransom?
- I could look after the kids.
- Don't be stupid, Ambrosio!
If we kidnap my grandkids,
they'll know it was us.
We came to you because
you know your Bible,
and that thing is full of fucked-up ideas!
We could poison them like Saint Elisha
poisoned his sons by the River Jordan.
Or rake them over the coals
like Saint Lawrence.
What if we ask Regino?
He might have ideas.
Are you crazy, Lola?
If Regino finds out about the treasure,
he'll find some way
to keep it all to himself.
No matter what we decide,
we have to do it today.
With that fortune, Pancho can buy
himself a hundred new cars!
Fran, how are we taking this
back to Mexico City?
Not only does it weigh a ton,
we can't get on a bus
and risk this fortune.
Please, honey. We're not taking a bus.
We have to hide the treasure
from those vultures.
- Okay, and then?
- Tomorrow,
we'll go into town, buy a new truck,
retrieve the gold, and go back home.
But, where can we hide it
without anyone seeing?
Mari...
Mari, I have a plan.
I'm going to take this, just to be safe.
I feel sorry for any of my piece-of-shit
relatives if they try something.
Like Grandpa Francisco would've said,
I'll put a bullet through their skulls.
All right, let's go.
- Lupita.
- Yes?
Keep the door locked
until we return, got it?
- Yes, sir.
- Be good, kids.
Listen to Lupita. Let's go.
I promise you, honey.
We're never coming back,
and we won't see my hideous family again.
What if we burn their feet,
like Cuauhtémoc?
Would it be in bad taste
if we just kill them
and bury them behind the house?
- Don't kill them, Dad!
- Not even as a joke, Rufino.
Pancho and his family share our blood.
Anyone who hurts them, will answer to me.
What should we do, then?
You're all a bunch of fools.
We'll settle it the old way,
like they did in the Revolution.
We're part of the noble masses,
and we vastly outnumber
those stuck-up shits.
We'll go into Pancho's room
and take the safe.
If he catches us,
we'll say we just wanted
to look at Grandpa's photos,
because we miss him so very much.
- How's that?
- Mother, you're a saint.
Oh, Mom!
From here to that dry log,
it's exactly 27 steps
heading to that lamp post.
- Are we leaving it here?
- Yes, honey.
Seeing as my family lost their minds,
it's best to remove
the temptation altogether.
If they burned our car,
they're capable of anything.
We're done here.
Let's go.
- Are you okay?
- Yes.
Are you okay?
What happened here?
He shot me! He really shot me!
Lupe!
He shot me in the arm!
Lupe?
Lupe!
Get up, Lupe.
Oh, Mom!
He's dead.
Murderer!
Screw you, Pancho!
You killed my Lupe, you bastard!
Murderer!
Pancho!
Everything will be okay, honey!
Everything will be okay!
It's going to be fine!
I'm sorry, Pancho. You're fucked.
No amount of money
will get you out of this mess.
They broke into my room!
I acted in self-defense.
Remember I already read you your rights,
so anything you say
can be used against you.
We'll take your statement
in a little while.
No, no...
No. No!
One more!
That's enough, let me try again.
You got it, Dad. Put your back into it!
Come on, Dad.
This fucking thing can't be opened.
Have you checked to see
if the safe is unlocked?
I told you!
Any other guns in there? Maybe a revolver?
Nothing! Fuck!
I knew Pancho was smarter
than the rest of us.
God is punishing us.
That's what we get for being greedy.
So much tragedy!
If the treasure's not here,
where did Pancho hide it?
Who knows?
And after last night, he'll never tell us.
What now?
We should try to be there
for Jacinto, I mean, Jacinta!
They must've released Lupe's body by now.
He shouldn't be alone. I mean, she.
Or they?
- Let's go!
- Okay.
Mom, are you coming to the cemetery?
Why would I go to the funeral
of that piece of shit?
If there ever was a silver lining.
I say Pancho did us a favor
when he killed that pimp.
He clung to this family
worse than gonorrhea.
Watch the kids, then.
It's not good for them
to see all this drama.
Give Jacinta a hug for me.
Sure thing, Mom! Let's go, everyone.
I swear it was self-defense.
I believe you, Godson.
The thing is that homicide,
despite extenuating circumstances,
is fully prosecuted.
- How long will the trial last?
- Well, son...
In this town, six to eight months
before we get a court date.
I see.
If they find me guilty,
how much time will I get?
Depends on the judge, son.
In my experience, though,
probably a minimum of three to five years.
Three to five years?
That's not counting the other wounded.
No one will believe it was an accident.
I can't do this. Please, Godfather!
I'm begging you to help me
get out of here.
- Godson, you know I love you.
- I do.
There's nothing in this country
that can't be solved
with a lot of money.
How much do you think
Grandpa's estate is worth?
Including the contents of the safe.
Did you also hear about
Grandpa's treasure?
In this town, there are thieves,
but no secrets.
I know it's a fortune.
Well...
To be honest with you, it's hard to say.
I found some gold nuggets,
and some assorted coins.
The full value must be around three, four...
five million.
- Is that it?
- Godfather.
- I swear to God.
- I'll take your word for it.
Tell your wife, who is waiting outside,
to bring it here as soon as possible.
Meanwhile, I'll pull some strings
to see if I can get you out.
The whole treasure?
I thought the President
rooted out corruption.
Godson, you insult me!
It's not for me!
There are plenty of people
who haven't committed
to the transformation of the country!
I'm going to have to bribe the judge,
the district attorney,
and the state prosecutor.
By the end, you might
end up owing me money.
I'm sorry, Godfather.
I swear I'll give you the whole treasure,
but you need to help me
get out of this place.
Very well, then.
Tell your wife to bring it over,
and I'll call in some favors
to get you out of here.
- Thank you, Godfather.
- God bless.
Watch him.
Fucking hell.
I'll open the gate.
Come on! Try a little!
Do something.
- Why not here?
- No way!
- Pancho!
- Pancho...
- You have a visitor.
- My love!
- How are you, love?
- Honey!
- I'm worried, desperate.
- What should we do?
Why not hire a lawyer to handle this?
Imagine the kind of lawyer
we'll find in Prosperidad.
So, what's the plan?
I have to turn over the gold
to Uncle Regino.
- What?
- I know. I know.
I don't like it, what if we do it
and he keeps you here?
I can't stay in this hellhole
for five years, Mari.
We have to risk it.
I hope you're right because
I'm not staying here that long.
I know.
Get the shovel and dig out the treasure.
You're only taking out one of the bags.
Leave the rest where it is.
This is very important,
be very careful with those vultures.
Pancho!
The rules say no whispering. Cut it out.
- Where are the kids?
- Outside, waiting with Lupita.
They wouldn't let them in,
visiting hours are over.
I mean, please.
- Well, do what I said.
- Sure
If you don't take too long,
I could get out today.
- Sure, my love.
- I love you.
- It's a good plan.
- Be careful.
- Please be quick, don't take too long.
- No, my love.
Hi, there!
How many years in the can
are they giving my murderous grandson?
Old hag.
Help me, kids. You too, Lupita.
We're taking a few things.
Brayan!
Come here.
- What is it, Grandma?
- Go see where they go.
Come on!
...16, 17, 18, 19, 20, 21
22, 23, four, five, six, and seven.
Facing the lamp post.
I hope this is it.
Give me a hand, Lupita. Bring the pickaxe.
- Yes, ma'am.
- Kids!
- Find something to help me.
- Yes, Mom!
- What are we looking for?
- Don't ask, just help me.
Mom!
- Your turn.
- Yes.
- Here it goes.
- That's better.
The soil is too hard.
Try the pickaxe.
- Again?
- Yes.
We need to loosen it.
Come here, kids.
Keep going.
Help me find... something.
If we do it,
I'll give you one dollar each.
Do it again.
- Hold on.
- Keep digging.
You, too.
The madame is going crazy,
digging holes everywhere?
I think she's looking for
Uncle Pancho's treasure.
Run to the cemetery and tell your grandpa.
Don't let anyone else hear you!
- Run like fuck, son!
- Yes, Grandma.
You should all learn
from what happened here.
The Lord always works in mysterious ways.
Like with Sodom and Gomorrah,
God has punished your greed.
Let us pray.
Hey, Ambrosio! Where's the eulogy?
For that pimp? Who's paying, Rosendo?
You should be grateful
I came to pray the rosary.
Oh, Lupe!
- Take me with you!
- Girl.
Hey, girl!
Let us fucking pray!
They're digging out the treasure.
Run back. Son?
They're looking for the treasure.
Hurry up.
- They're getting the treasure.
- The treasure!
- What is it, Mom?
- It's the treasure!
What's this, now? Where is everyone?
I apologize for my family,
but Mari is supposedly
looking for the treasure.
- That's why they left.
- Rest in peace, amen.
My daughter, that's all from me.
Stay with your man, I have to run.
I want to prevent another tragedy!
- Uncle!
- God bless.
See you later, Jacinta. God have mercy!
- Don't go, girls.
- Bartola, help me!
Wait for us, Uncle!
Baby, I'll be back soon.
You know these assholes,
if I don't hurry up, they'll take it all.
In the name of the cross.
Wait for me!
What's this, Mariquita?
Can we help?
Oh, Don Rosendo.
We buried the treasure here,
but I can't find it!
If we don't give it to Regino today,
he won't let Pancho get out of jail.
My goodness.
Why didn't you mark the spot?
We did, but I can't find it.
It was too dark, I couldn't see.
Everything looked different,
I'm not sure anymore.
Don't worry, we're here to help.
If we all pitch in,
we'll find it in no time.
Everyone, get to the house
and bring shovels, pickaxes,
hoes, and wheelbarrows.
My daughter-in-law needs help!
- Yes, Dad.
- Hurry up!
Let me help you, you take a break.
One, two, three, four, five, wait, no.
Mari, my love!
- What took you so long?
- Oh, Fran!
It was a nightmare finding the treasure.
At first we couldn't find it.
Thank God your family helped,
so we finally found it.
At least you're here now
and this will be over soon.
- I know, my love.
- Let's see.
Mari...
Mari, where's the gold?
These are just rocks.
Oh, Fran.
Forgive me, but I've decided
what to do with the gold.
What I've always dreamed of.
I'm buying houses, cars,
jewelry, yachts, clothes.
Mari, don't do this to me!
Please forgive me,
but an opportunity like this
only comes once in a lifetime,
and this is mine.
- Bye!
- Wait, Mari.
Mari, please don't. Don't do this to me!
Mari, please don't do this!
No, no!
What kind of dream was that?
You were screaming.
It was nothing, officer.
Any news from my wife or my relatives?
No, sir, nothing.
Thanks.
- What's going on?
- You didn't hear?
It seems Rosendo's son
buried a huge treasure
here in the property.
Whoever finds it first is getting half.
What if someone finds it and keeps quiet?
Well, then... I guess they'd keep it all.
- What are we waiting for?
- Let's do it.
Let's see who finds it first.
- Do it right, babe!
- What the hell?
- Sorry about that.
- I thought you were hurt.
Grab a shovel, then. Come on!
- Did you find anything, dear?
- Nothing yet, Don Rosendo.
With all these new holes,
we may never find it.
- This place is unrecognizable.
- Don't worry.
We know all these folks,
they're honest people.
I'll make sure we don't stop
until we find that treasure.
Mari, my dear.
I brought you food and water.
What if we don't find it,
and Pancho is stuck in jail
for five years?
Oh, my God. He must be desperate.
I'm going to find the spot right now.
Right now!
- Any news from my wife?
- Nothing yet.
- My dad is getting pretty mad.
- What's taking her so long?
Rumor has it, the treasure's lost.
They can't find it anywhere.
What if you break me out
so I can find it myself?
What if you never come back?
In your dreams!
Could you run it by my godfather?
I did, he said if in 24 hours,
the treasure doesn't turn up,
I should take you straight
to the state penitentiary.
You've been warned.
For fuck's sake! What could've gone wrong?
Here's something!
Let me see, son.
All right, Rosendo. Give it here.
It's Fulgencio's skull.
- Look at this.
- How can you tell?
- It could be anyone!
- What about this?
I was there when your father
shot him in the head.
It still smells like him.
Who was this Fulgencio?
Why did my dad shoot him?
I dated him once.
One day, your father caught us cheating,
so he shot him eight times,
but this one was the one.
This was the one that killed him.
Right here.
- Where are you going, Mariquita?
- This is insane, Don Rosendo.
We didn't dig that deep.
We won't find it soon, maybe not ever.
I should go see Pancho,
tell him what's going on,
and come up with a plan.
Don't you worry, dear.
As sure as I'm Rosendo Reyes
I'll keep digging until I find it,
even if it takes me a thousand years.
Let's go, kids.
Come on.
Wake up, fuckers!
We're only getting started!
Come on, Rufino, Hilario,
Socorro, Jacinta!
You too, Bartola! Let's get to work.
We're exhausted, Dad!
I'm at my wit's end, Pancho.
I can't stay with your family.
They're the worst, Pancho.
Just take the kids and go back home.
And leave you here? Don't say that!
If you return to the city,
we'll have more options.
We could get a loan, pawn something off,
or hire a good lawyer.
One more thing,
I need you to tell Don Jaime
what's going on.
The last thing I need is to lose my job.
Pancho, I can't just leave you here.
The kids won't be happy
to go home without their dad.
All right, kids. What do you want?
Do you want to go home
with Lupita and Mom?
Or stay at your grandparents'
and wait for Dad to get out.
- I want to go home, Dad.
- I hate this stinking town.
- See, honey?
- Pancho, step back.
I'm going to let you say your goodbyes.
Make it quick.
Don't forget how much I love you.
- Time's up.
- Don't forget.
- I won't.
- Bye, kids.
- Bye.
- Bye, Dad.
Goodbye, my love.
Goodbye, Don Rosendo.
Farewell, Doña Dolores.
Give my regards to everyone,
and I beg of you,
never ever abandon my Pancho.
Don't worry, dear.
- Let's go, Lupita.
- I'm sorry, ma'am. I have some news.
Guess what? I'm staying here.
Rosendito proposed and I said yes!
- Have you thought this through?
- Of course I have.
So... does that mean we'll be related?
- Oh, yes.
- Well, congratulations.
Thank you, sis.
We'll send you an invite soon.
As soon as we set a date. Safe travels!
Bye, Cati.
Bye, Toni. Come visit, okay?
- Be good to your mom.
- Let's go, kids.
- Bye.
- Hey, Mom?
- Is Lupita our aunt now?
- Is she, Mom?
Don't even joke about that.
You're dead if you tell anyone.
Godson, I'm truly sorry
you're in this situation.
I already talked to the judge.
He said no money, no dice.
I've been locked up for over ten days!
My family hasn't stopped
looking for the treasure.
Just let me out of here.
I swear I know where it is.
I wish I could!
These are no longer the good old days.
If the judge finds out
my relative got special treatment,
we'd both be fucked.
I'm begging you, Godfather.
Just name your price.
Anything at all! Just get me out of here.
Are you sure, Pancho?
Anything, Godfather.
I'd sell my soul to the devil
to get out of this place.
Officer, send in the notary.
Tell him to bring the contracts.
Look, everyone!
Uncle Pancho's here! They cut him loose!
Grandpa, Grandma!
They released Uncle Pancho!
Pancho Francisco Reyes!
It's good to see you free.
- I'm so glad to see you!
- Oh, Pancho.
You're nothing but skin and bones!
Can I make you something?
No thanks, Mom.
Why aren't you back in the city?
Well, sir, I've moved in with Rosendito.
We're engaged, and we're expecting.
God makes them and the devil pairs them.
What happened, Panchito?
Did you drop the soap back in prison?
Or, did you manage to save
the family's honor?
Come on, fucker.
Kids, get dressed!
Get shovels and pickaxes.
Let's help Pancho!
...23, 24, 25, 26 and 27.
See? My dear Mari was right!
This is the right spot.
Grab your shovels, and let's help him--
You know what, Dad?
I'd rather do it alone.
If you start digging wherever you please,
I won't find anything in this mess.
Mind if we stick around
to keep you company?
You know, for moral support.
Afternoon, Grandma.
- Did Pancho find the treasure?
- Nothing yet.
I think that the gold is lost forever,
and that sucker is just
completely deluded.
Don't say that, Grandma.
His heart is set on it.
God willing,
he'll find it one of these days.
What Pancho ought to do
is give up on the whole thing,
go back where he came from,
and leave us alone.
- We were better off without him.
- You're so mean.
- Don't you fear God?
- You're the ones who should fear Him!
Instead of working your way up
like decent people,
you're sucking up to him,
to see if he throws you a bone.
Come on, girls.
Beans don't cook themselves.
"Look at me. Beans don't cook themselves."
Son, it's getting late.
Get some sleep,
you'll take it up tomorrow.
No, I'm not leaving
until I find that treasure.
I have a feeling I'm getting close.
- I'm very, very close.
- All right, son.
See you tomorrow, and good luck.
Son, please stop!
Hail Mary, full of grace.
The Lord is with thee.
Blessed art thou among women,
and blessed is the fruit of thy womb.
Holy Mary, Mother of God,
pray for us sinners,
now and at the hour of our death. Amen.
Grant him eternal rest,
and let perpetual light shine upon him.
May our Pancho's soul
and those in Purgatory
forever rest in peace. Amen.
Amen.
Ambrosio, isn't it a bit much
to take him for dead?
He's still alive.
I'm not taking him for dead, God forbid!
Pancho, just like St. Anthony,
has got the devil in him.
It's up to us to do what we can
to save his soul.
The doctor said there's still hope.
Oh, Dolores.
Twenty days and nights
without food or sleep,
digging that hellish hole.
Lying there another ten days
like Saint Simon.
Do you really think he's going to wake up?
What about a miracle?
Don't you believe in those?
Rosendo, don't be naive.
God grants miracles to good people,
and in this family,
maybe just one of the kids
will be spared from Hell.
You shut your mouth, bird of ill omen.
Oh, my God. So much tragedy.
Why did this happen to us?
God, please, grant us a miracle.
I'm leaving.
I'm getting out of here
and going back to my family.
It's a miracle!
- Goodbye, brother.
- God bless.
Thanks for everything. You're a good man.
See you, brother.
Give our love to your family.
See you at the wedding. Right, Lupita?
Mr. Pancho, sorry I let you
and Mrs. Mari down.
I called my sister in San Pedro
to fill in for me.
No need, sis.
Mari and I will figure it out.
Pancho, God help you and keep you safe.
Tell Mari about the miracle
so that she knows He exists.
The dark swallows shall one day return!
Bye, Pancho.
If you're ever in town
and you're feeling sad,
I'll be around.
My brother. My soul brother.
I wish you luck.
I hope you rebuild your life.
Pancho, thank you for getting rid of Lupe.
This is all I could recover
from your things.
I love you very much,
and I'll fucking miss you.
Give my love to my niece and nephew.
I'm finally leaving, Grandma.
I guess you're happy
to get rid of my snotty self.
I may have won the battle,
but I lost the war.
Just for today, let's make a truce.
Give me a kiss, as I'm sure
we won't see each other again.
Bye, Grandma.
God bless you, son.
Don't hold a grudge against us,
and come back soon.
Don't worry, Mom. It's all forgiven.
Goodbye, Dad.
I sincerely wish you all the best.
I hope you'll forgive me one day
and hold no grudge.
What's there to forgive?
We're blessed to have a son
as good as you.
I promise you that,
even if it costs me my life,
I won't give up
until I find your treasure.
Even if it takes me forever and a day.
Forever and a day!
Goodbye, Dad.
Goodbye, kids!
- Bye, kids.
- Goodbye.
Goodbye, son.
Pancho...
Fucking Grandpa.
I'll always wonder
if you did this on purpose,
or if you ruined our lives
out of sheer bad luck.
But knowing you as well as I did,
I'm sure than none of this
was a coincidence.
Wherever you are,
I'm sure you must be laughing your ass off
as you watch our lives crumble around us.
In honor of your memory,
and better than the mausoleum
you wanted so badly,
I'm going to do something
that will make you proud.
Something you will never,
ever forget, Grandpa.
What's this, Pancho?
You're leaving without saying goodbye?
It's time I leave, Godfather,
hopefully for good.
Did you find anything?
No.
What a shame,
but I'm glad you gave up such madness
and recovered your reason and your sanity.
Here's a copy of the contract,
certified by the notary.
- Check it before you leave.
- No need, Godfather.
All I ask is that you're not
too tough on my family.
Who do you take me for?
Pascuala is my mother.
Your father shares my blood,
and I adore your siblings.
- See you, Commander.
- Bye, Pancho!
This is goodbye, Godfather.
Look after my family.
I told you, get that out of your mind.
The administration's priority
is the well-being of the poor.
Luckily, your family falls
on the right side of history.
They are part of the noble, wise masses.
Godspeed, son.
- Godfather.
- Yes?
Don't take this the wrong way,
but this government reminds me
of all the previous ones.
You're wrong, listen...
Spoiled, renegade brat.
The nation will square him up
and put him in his place.
Reginito.
Let's pay a visit to the family
and tell them to leave immediately.
Yes, sir.
Hey, Dad! Lunch is ready.
Shall we wait for you
or go ahead without you?
Let's go, son.
- No luck?
- None, my girl.
If we keep digging,
we'll reach China one day.
Let's go!
Careful.
Lazy, good-for-nothing sons of bitches.
Hell!
Don't mind him.
Morning, Mom.
- Is this all that's left?
- Good thing they ate,
because we have nothing for tomorrow.
Don Rosendo,
I can get some cactus for you.
Okay.
Fuck you a thousand times,
Francisco Reyes!
This is all your fault.
You better be rotting in Hell.
And I hope your shitty grandson
joins you soon enough.
What's the point of crying?
Don Rosendo, come quick! We're screwed!
Come on, this is serious!
The police are here!
That must be Regino, trying to evict us.
Mom, give me that. Son of a bitch!
Uncle Rosendo,
surrender, please, without resistance.
Come on, kids. Let's face this fucker!
Please, surrender without resistance
I have a judge's order
to evict the property immediately!
Fuck that, Godson.
You'll have to kill us all
before your jerk of a father
takes our house!
Evacuate the property!
Don't make me take action.
I repeat, Godfather!
Surrender yourselves or I'm going to be
compelled to use the public force.
Don't be stupid, Rosendo!
Don't endanger your family.
Evacuate the house
or I'll send in the cops
and knock down the house on top of you!
Fuck you.
Fire!
Advance! Advance!
Motherfuckers!
Let go of me!
Get the hell out of my house!
Motherfuckers!
Screw you, Regino!
I swear on Dad's memory
you'll pay for this.
You and that traitor Pancho
will answer for this!
Come on, son.
All this is finally ours.
Let's get to work.
Mr. Reyes. Good news.
Come with us. I think we found it.
I knew Pancho's treasure
would turn up sooner or later!
Your nephew came so close to finding it.
He was wrong by less than two feet.
- Some people are born unlucky.
- Agreed!
I have even better news.
I doubt it's better than this.
Look what your nephew was about to find.
A gold-bearing vein
in the old Esperanza mine.
Rosendo was right all along.
It's one of the largest veins
ever discovered.
Praise God!
Rosendo and Pancho, you did it!
God bless you both! God bless you!
Sorry, but I also have some bad news.
What?
You are forgetting the contract
you signed with us.
All this is ours.
No!
I didn't sign anything! Not a thing!
This gold is mine.
I'm sorry, sir. But the law is the law.
You signed the contract.
I'm getting an injunction!
The gold is mine! I'll get an injunction!
It's mine, all mine!
How much longer will they keep us here?
- It's been over two months.
- Who knows, Lola?
I guess Regino and Reginito
forgot all about us.
- We might stay here forever.
- Stop whining.
At least we're getting three meals a day!
Listen, family.
- Get your things, you're free.
- Praise the Lord.
Why did your shitty father
keep us here for so long?
Please don't disrespect me
and don't mention my father.
He's at the hospital, it's very serious.
I'm the temporary mayor,
I'm in charge now.
Better hurry up,
before I change my mind
and add two more months.
And you, Ambrosio? Where's your cassock?
I heard God's voice again,
like when I was a kid.
He told me the Roman Church
is morally bankrupt,
but the Bible has always
contained the answer.
Jesus Christ is our savior.
The end of days are coming,
so take this opportunity
granted by our brand-new mayor,
and go out into the light
before he takes it back.
Out, sinners!
Once again!
This family is worse than the plague!
NO TRESPASSING
US-CANADA MINING CO.
Look, Dad. You were right.
Grandpa's mine held a mountain of gold!
What's next, honey?
Poor Mexico.
So far from God, and so close to the U.S.
Fuck you, Pancho Reyes!
We have no house, no dreams, no hope.
Meanwhile, that bastard
is living like a king!
Francisco Reyes,
your presence is requested
in the director's office.
Francisco Reyes,
your presence is requested
in the director's office.
Come in!
Come in, Pancho. Come on in.
Hello, Don Jaime.
Hello, Normita.
What is it, Pancho? Normita was telling me
you've been trying to meet with me. So?
First, I'm very grateful
you agreed to see me.
I'm also grateful for the chance
to keep working here.
No need. Normita thanked me already.
She finally let me unbury her treasure,
and convinced me not to fire you.
Thank you, Normita.
- Is that all?
- I also wanted to ask,
If there's any chance
I can get my old job back.
Don't give me that bullshit.
Be grateful I didn't fire you
like you deserved.
After walking away from your job,
you deserved to have
my shoeprint on your ass.
Luckily, I sold the company
to the fucking gringos.
They'll decide what to do with you.
Could you recommend me
to the new management?
Maybe ask your mother!
Or that commie President,
who loves poor people like you.
Good thing I'm emigrating
before he ruins the country,
and turns it into Cuba or Venezuela.
If that's all, fuck off!
Neither the gringos
nor I pay you to stand around.
Thank you for the opportunity.
Thank you, Normita.
You're welcome, engineer.
My goodness!
Don't blame the pig,
blame those who feed it.
What's happened sir?
See where you ended up?
What comes up, eventually comes down.
- So, what?
- What?
Well, so what?
- Fuck you!
- Motherfucker!
GIVE IT UP FOR THE POOR!
AMLO FOR PRESIDENT, AGAIN!
- Family, I'm home!
- I'm so glad.
The ceiling caved in, and we have leaks.
- How did it go?
- Not great.
I met with Don Jaime,
but he rejected my promotion.
- Damn it.
- Oh, well. That's life.
- I have a surprise, right?
- Yeah.
Surprise!
What's up, Pancho? What took you so long?
I hope you don't mind us
getting comfortable.
We're moving in with you!
Thank God you made it home safe!
- Cheers, Pancho!
- Drink some tequila.
Let's give your family a proper welcome.
See, Panchito?
I told you you'd never
get rid of us, fucker!
Come on, Pancho! Don't be snotty!
Celebrate with your family,
because for us,
your failure is our happiness.
Cheers to that
and long live Mexico, fuckers!
Hurray!
Pancho.
Pancho!
Pancho, wake up!
You were having a nightmare.
I had the most terrible, dreadful dream.
I keep telling you to see a doctor,
this isn't normal.
Let me sleep, for fuck's sake.
I have one hell of a hangover.
Oh, man.
Jesus.
Pancho, please! Don't be inconsiderate!
You're making so much noise
while we're trying to sleep.
I mean, fuck.
Subtitle translation by: Michael Evans