(OMINOUS MUSIC PLAYING)
(MUSIC INTENSIFIES)
(TOWNSPEOPLE SPEAKING IN ITALIAN)
(AMORTH IN ITALIAN)
That's a beautiful pig.
(IN ITALIAN)
Only the best, Father.
This way, Father.
(IN ITALIAN) The boy is showing
all the classical signs of possession,
Father Amorth.
Has the family consulted a doctor?
Many, many doctors.
What are the signs of possession?
He converses in English, Father.
- (BOY YELLS)
- (THUDS)
Has he spoken English before?
Never. Not once before.
Do they own a television?
Yes, I believe so.
Okay, thank you.
(BOY YELLING AND GROANING)
AMORTH: Ah...
What are you drawing?
A bird.
That's good, kid.
(YELLING CONTINUES)
I have a very important job for you.
Do you know the Our Father?
- Yes, Father.
- Good.
(THUDS CONTINUE)
You can help your brother.
Repeat the Our Father, over and over.
Don't get distracted.
Relentless. Understood?
Yes, Father.
Good.
Our Father, who art in heaven,
hallowed be thy name...
Bring me the pig.
- (OMINOUS MUSIC PLAYING)
- (SCREAMING CONTINUES)
(GASPING AND GRUNTING)
(IN ENGLISH) I am legion.
I am Satan.
I am foul-mouthed behemoth.
(IN ITALIAN) Difficult to believe.
You doubt me?
If you are Satan, what is my name?
Describe hell.
You will find out soon enough.
Are you avoiding my questions?
You mock me?
(DRAMATIC MUSIC PLAYING)
Answer me, Satan.
Why possess this boy?
Why not someone more influential?
I can possess anyone I choose.
Ah.
Could you possess Father Gianni?
A bishop?
- Anyone! Anything!
- (SPEAKS IN ITALIAN)
(IN ENGLISH) I do not believe you.
I don't believe
you could even possess this pig.
Can you do it? You have the power.
Could you possess the pig?
- Yes, I can.
- Come on, Satan.
BOY: Watch me!
AMORTH: Possess the pig.
Show me you are the Prince of Darkness.
(SPEAKS IN ITALIAN)
(IN ENGLISH) Show to me your power.
Have you done it?
(IN ITALIAN)
Have you possessed him, Satan?
(SQUEALS)
Have you possessed it, Satan?
(PIG SCREECHES)
(GASPING AND WHIMPERING)
Be calm.
God blesses you.
(IN ENGLISH) You can sleep now, my son.
The demon has gone.
God is with you.
(HAUNTING MUSIC PLAYING)
("SHE SELLS SANCTUARY" PLAYING)
♪ Oh, the heads that turn ♪
♪ Make my back burn ♪
♪ And those heads that turn ♪
♪ Make my back, make my back burn... ♪
(SONG CONTINUES OVER HEADPHONES)
Amy, we're not in America anymore.
You can't dress like that.
Why?
Because there's gonna be
construction workers everywhere.
(SCOFFS)
How you doing back there?
♪ The world and the world... ♪
(OMINOUS MUSIC PLAYING)
(CONSTRUCTION WORKERS
CHATTERING INDISTINCTLY)
So we left everything for this?
Amy, please. Don't start.
- You know exactly what I'm gonna say.
- Yes, and I don't wanna hear it.
What do you think? Pretty cool, huh?
Yeah, I know.
- (SOFT CHATTERING IN ITALIAN)
- (CHURCH BELLS RINGING)
Cuckoo!
(LAUGHING)
- (MIMICS ROAR)
- (GIGGLING)
Ah... Gabriele.
(IN ITALIAN)
Why do you think Saint Michael
didn't kill Satan when he had the chance?
(IN ENGLISH)
That is a question of theology.
(IN ENGLISH) No shit.
Perhaps it was his mercy
that stayed Saint Michael's sword.
The only thing that arrests God's love
is a person's freedom to choose.
But God cannot be God
unless he allows for this choice
even for the damned.
Saint Michael, he knows this.
We will all be judged.
We will all be judged
by how much we love.
LUMUMBA: Hm.
Do not worry, Gabriele.
I will defend you.
Defend me?
Mm.
My faith
does not require defense.
(HAMMERING)
(INDISTINCT CHATTER)
JULIA: Oh-ho!
Wow.
- What do you think, guys?
- Cozy.
JULIA: Oh, come on.
Give it a chance. This is awesome.
- Señora Vasquez.
- Carlos, hi!
So nice to put a face to the voice.
Um...
Padre... Father Esquibel...
- Pleasure to meet you, Miss Vasquez.
- Uh, Julia, please.
- Carlos was giving me a tour.
- JULIA: Oh, great.
I just wanted to stop by and welcome
you and your family to the diocese.
- CARLOS: I'm sorry.
- Oh, no, no, no, please. Go for it.
I'm glad to see you made it safe.
AMY: All right. Go find your room, twerp.
- (SAW BUZZING, THEN METAL CLANKS)
- (CONSTRUCTION WORKERS CHATTERING)
Hey. Can I get one of those?
(IN ITALIAN) Yes, of course.
ESQUIBEL:
This property has been in disrepair
- for as long as I can remember.
- Thank you.
So it's a wonderful thing you're doing,
restoring the abbey.
We are being very respectful
of the existing architecture.
This has actually been
in my husband's family for generations,
and we just inherited it.
Is Mr. Vasquez here or...?
Oh, uh, he passed, actually.
About a year ago.
- I'm sorry for your loss.
- It's okay.
If you need anything,
please, hm, don't hesitate.
Okay.
I will remember him in my prayers.
Oh, that's very kind of you.
Thank you. It was nice to meet you.
Okay, Carlos, talk to me.
What's up? Where are we at?
The basement excavation
is very complicated.
JULIA: More expensive, you mean?
- CARLOS: I'm afraid so.
- JULIA: All right.
I'll take another look at the plans.
If you could just show me what the
basement looks like, maybe I can wire...
Amy, get off of there
before you break your neck.
Is that a cigarette?
Put that out right now, please.
- Fine.
- No! Oh, my God.
(PLUMBING GROANING)
(RHYTHMIC KNOCKING)
(OMINOUS MUSIC PLAYING)
(MUSIC FADES)
Cute.
Get out of my room.
(RHYTHMIC KNOCKING)
("GONE DADDY GONE"
PLAYING OVER HEADPHONES)
♪ Beautiful girl, lovely dress ♪
♪ Where she is now, I can only guess ♪
♪ 'Cause it's gone, daddy, gone
The love is gone ♪
♪ Yeah, it's gone, daddy, gone
♪ Yeah, it's gone, daddy, gone... ♪
(HAUNTING MUSIC PLAYING)
(MAN SPEAKING IN SPANISH)
(THUMPING)
- (MASONRY CLATTERS)
- (GASPS)
(INDISTINCT DEMONIC WHISPERS)
(STONES CRACKLING AND CRUNCHING)
("WE CARE A LOT" PLAYING OVER HEADPHONES)
(KNOCKING ON DOOR)
Hey, have you seen your brother?
Amy.
Look, I really can't handle
the silent treatment from both my kids.
- I know you don't wanna be here.
- Yeah, no shit.
Amy.
Please, I need your help.
This abbey is the only thing
your dad left us.
We don't have an income anymore.
Once we fix it up and sell it,
we'll go home. Okay?
Maybe if you could just
at least watch your brother.
Maybe try and get him to talk.
How? He hasn't spoken in almost a year.
Can you try for me?
So you want me to be a mother for you?
Please just keep an eye
on your brother. Okay?
(MOUTHS)
("WE CARE A LOT" CONTINUES)
♪ Whoa, whoa ♪
♪ It's a dirty job
But someone's gotta do it ♪
♪ We care a lot ♪
(SONG ENDS)
(IN ITALIAN) Hold this.
(CHURCH BELLS RINGING)
Father Amorth, caffe latte?
At this time of the day? Are you crazy?
Double espresso, Sister.
Thank you.
(IN ENGLISH) Sugar?
Sugar is the work of the devil.
No, thank you.
Thank you very much.
Let's get on with this already.
(IN ENGLISH) This is a formal hearing.
And as agreed,
proceedings will be undertaken in English.
Ah. All right, let's go.
On the night of June 4th,
in the town of Tropea,
you performed an exorcism
without the approval
of the Reggio Calabria bishop.
It wasn't a...
In English, Father Amorth.
(IN ENGLISH) That was not an exorcism.
From Father Gianni's description,
what occurred in Reggio Calabria sounded
exactly like an exorcism,
complete with animal sacrifice, no less.
The boy was maladjusted.
A temporary mental illness.
I use primitive psychology.
The power of suggestion.
You addressed the subject as Satan,
called for him to display his power.
- Do you deny this?
- No.
- That's what I did.
- And why would you do that?
Exorcism is my job,
but the vast majority of the cases
to which I'm assigned
do not require an exorcism.
They just need, uh, a little conversation,
a little understanding,
and sometimes...
a little theater.
Cardinal Sullivan, in my observation,
98% of the cases
that are assigned to Father Amorth
are then further recommended by him
to doctors and psychiatrists.
And the other 2%?
AMORTH: Ah, the other 2%.
This is something
that has confounded all of science
and all of medicine for a very long time.
(OMINOUS MUSIC PLAYING)
I call it...
evil.
LUMUMBA: Your Eminence,
with hundreds of successful exorcisms,
- Father Amorth has been very effective...
- One moment, Bishop Lumumba.
You do raise an interesting point, Amorth.
You are not a doctor,
but these practices of yours
could have damaging effects
on these people.
You are right.
I am not a doctor.
I am not a psychologist.
But I am a theologian, I am a lawyer,
I am a journalist,
and I am a practical man.
I was also a partisan in the war,
so I know a firing squad when I see one.
So, what is this about?
The Congregation
for the Doctrine of the Faith
has recommended to this panel
that the position of chief exorcist
be formally vacated.
So, what you are saying
is that evil does not exist?
The Church is under constant pressure
to sharpen her relevance.
It's time we move past
these outdated beliefs.
Explain to me please, Your Eminence.
If evil does not exist,
what, then, is the role of the Church?
I think we all have to be careful of the
Congregation of the Doctrine of the Faith.
Sounds to me
like they want us all out of a job.
We have more questions for you,
Father Amorth.
How is it that I am suddenly worthy
of the time and attention
of all you powerful men?
I ask you again...
what is this about?
Due process, Father.
So this is not about the dead girl,
Rosaria Velendez,
that I write about
in La Madre di Dio magazine?
What is your due diligence
and process on this?
- Please, cardinal.
- I warn you! I warn you! Father Amorth,
show respect to your superiors.
I do!
I am the chief exorcist of the Vatican.
My position was appointed by my bishop.
My diocese is Rome.
My local bishop is the pope.
If you have a problem with me,
you talk to my boss. Okay?
The pope is infirm.
Father Amorth,
you have not been dismissed.
- Cuckoo.
- Father Amorth!
- (CRICKETS CHIRPING)
- (FIRE CRACKLING)
(SIGHS)
(THUDDING)
- (OMINOUS MUSIC PLAYING)
- (WIND WHISTLING)
(CLANKING AND THUDDING)
(SHIVERS)
(CLOCK TICKING)
Hello?
Anyone there?
- (FLOORBOARDS CREAK)
- (GASPS)
(HEAVY METAL MUSIC PLAYING INDISTINCTLY
OVER HEADPHONES)
(WALKMAN CLICKS, THEN MUSIC STOPS)
(OMINOUS MUSIC INTENSIFIES)
(MAN IN SPANISH)
I can't wait to finish this job.
This place freaks me out.
(MASONRY CRUMBLING)
(INDISTINCT DEMONIC WHISPERS)
What is it?
I don't know. Can't see anything.
(YELLS)
- (HAUNTING MUSIC PLAYING)
- (INDISTINCT RADIO CHATTER)
CARLOS: They hit a gas deposit.
We can't continue working here.
I'm pulling my team from this place.
(IN SPANISH)
Come on, let's go. Come on, everybody out.
JULIA: Wait.
MAN: Quick, quick.
(HAUNTING MUSIC CONTINUES)
(DEMONIC SNARL)
AMY: Henry?
No. Henry!
Mom!
JULIA: Oh, my God!
Henry! What is happening?
I don't know,
he was like this when I came in.
Henry? Henry, it's Mommy.
Talk to me.
- Henry.
- Mommy.
He's talking.
- Henry.
- Mommy.
You're all going to die.
JULIA: Henry! What are you doing?
- Henry! Henry!
- AMY: Henry! Henry!
(MRI THUMPING)
WOMAN:
X-rays, blood tests, even the spinal tap
and MRI show no results
of ischemia or hematoma.
What does that mean?
(BOTH SPEAKING IN ITALIAN)
(IN ENGLISH) All of his vitals
and brain functions seem to be normal.
Wait, normal? What do you mean?
He was convulsing.
(SPEAKS IN ITALIAN)
Has he been through any trauma recently?
(SOBS) Um...
Yeah, uh, his dad died about a year ago.
(BOTH SPEAK IN ITALIAN)
(WOMAN IN ENGLISH) And how did he react?
Uh...
He hasn't spoken since.
(BOTH SPEAK IN ITALIAN)
Wha... Psychosis?
No, that's not possible.
He's just a little boy.
(IN ENGLISH) Ma'am,
there is nothing that we can do now.
- But he can recommend a good psychiatrist.
- JULIA: What is this?
(SPEAKS IN ITALIAN)
If your son continues
trying to hurt himself,
- you can administer him this sedative.
- No.
- Mom.
- I'm so sorry.
Baby.
Oh, my God.
JULIA: No, I don't think you understand.
But this is an emergency, please.
No, I need to talk to someone
at the consulate who can help me.
I need a specialist.
Okay.
Yes, please.
(OMINOUS MUSIC PLAYING)
(BED CREAKS)
JULIA: Baby.
Hey.
My love, come here.
- (CLATTERING)
- (MICE SQUEAKING)
(ELECTRICITY CRACKLING AND HUMMING)
Fuck this.
- Henry, no.
- (GROWLS)
Henry, stop!
This baby's hungry, you fat cow.
What? What are you saying? (GASPS)
You never breastfed me, Mommy.
- What?
- AMY: What the fuck?
- (JULIA GROANS) Ow!
- (GROWLS)
What the fuck is that?
Bring me the priest.
- JULIA: Can you help us?
- ESQUIBEL: Yes.
I'm here to help, Julia.
Okay.
(SUSPENSEFUL MUSIC PLAYING)
- (HENRY ROARS)
- (ESQUIBEL GRUNTS)
(BOTH SCREAM)
(IN DEMONIC VOICE) Wrong fucking priest!
(ROARS)
- (IN ITALIAN) Is that you, Gabriele?
- (IN ITALIAN) Yes, Holy Father.
They tell me you are sick.
Yes, they hope so.
They wish to see me weak.
But, no, they are.
(SIGHS)
- Help me.
- Yes.
Perhaps we've done our jobs too well.
Cardinal Sullivan
and the younger generation,
they don't believe in the devil
as we understand it.
It's only an idea for them.
For us, it is very real.
Two hundred fallen angels,
expelled from heaven, driven beneath
the soil where God is not welcomed.
It is not a fairytale.
Your search for truth
is delightful, Gabriele,
but pay attention
to your desire to educate.
Pride manifests itself in different forms.
Pride? Me?
(CHUCKLES)
(IN ENGLISH)
There's a case that needs your attention.
A boy in Spain.
Something about it disturbs me greatly.
(PENSIVE MUSIC PLAYING)
This boy's possession
is progressing very fast.
The incident took place
in hallowed ground,
San Sebastian Abbey in Castile.
This place
has given the Church problems before.
I sense a great evil coming from there.
Something dark
that only you can help solve.
I have requested the abbey's records
be brought to you in the library.
Look into it.
I will continue investigating
while you're on your journey.
(IN ENGLISH) "Our sins...
will seek us out."
POPE: Gabriele.
Go to Spain, and help this child.
But be careful,
this demon sounds dangerous.
(OMINOUS MUSIC PLAYING)
AMORTH: Hello?
(MUSIC FADES)
(BIRDS SINGING AND INSECTS CHIRPING)
(DOOR CREAKS, THEN CLOSES)
(IN SPANISH) Father.
Good morning.
I'm Father Tomás Esquibel.
- (IN ITALIAN) Spanish?
- Yes.
I am Father Amorth. Italian.
- (IN ENGLISH) Wait. Father Amorth?
- Yes.
Ah. I didn't expect them to send you.
(IN ENGLISH) You know me?
- Yes. I have read all the articles.
- (CHUCKLES)
- And the books?
- No, no. No, not the books.
The books are good.
- I will read...
- Okay. I'll just get my bag.
You, uh... (CLEARS THROAT) Whiskey?
No, no, no. Thank you.
(CLEARS THROAT)
Yeah, this sore throat, the dust.
Julia, we have been extremely lucky.
The Church sent someone.
An expert in these matters.
Gabriele, please come in.
(IN ITALIAN)
Good morning, good morning, good morning.
I am Father Amorth.
(IN ENGLISH) I have come from Roma.
(IN ITALIAN) Gabriele, how are you?
I'm sorry that you came all this way,
but I don't even know
why the Church is interested in this.
I just want my son to be well.
AMORTH: Yes, yes.
(IN ENGLISH) Tell me something,
have the doctors given you any answers?
Any comfort?
If you would at least...
just let me see your son.
I can give you my opinion
and you can do with it what you will.
It's worth a shot.
Okay. He's upstairs.
(IN ITALIAN) Very nice, this.
(IN ENGLISH) Hello, my friend. (CHUCKLES)
Henry.
Are you awake?
(OMINOUS MUSIC PLAYING)
(IN ITALIAN)
Our Father, who art in heaven,
hallowed be thy name.
Thy kingdom come, thy will be...
(IN ENGLISH DEMONIC VOICE)
Your prayers are worthless here.
(GROWLING)
(IN ENGLISH) Who are you?
Your worst fear. I am your demise.
Why are you possessing this boy?
Because it feels so good
to ruin such innocent flesh.
But I prefer the challenge
of an exorcist's soul.
You only serve to diminish yourself.
Don't lecture me, priest.
What is your purpose?
I'm here for you.
Then you must know my name.
I know your soul and every shameless sin.
Tell me one of my sins.
(GROWLS)
You cannot.
Because my sins have been absolved
by the one true master,
- the Lord Jesus Christ.
- Do not speak of him.
Are you afraid of him?
Are you afraid of Jesus Christ?
(IN LATIN) God is not here.
(IN LATIN) God is everywhere.
(IN ENGLISH) Whatever you do...
you only do because God allows it.
Did he allow that?
This is just the beginning.
You don't know who you're dealing with.
Then tell me. Tell me your name.
Unless you are too afraid.
I'm not some stupid fuck
you convince to get into a pig.
So you won't tell me your name.
My name is blasphemy.
My name is nightmare.
Ah.
My nightmare...
is France winning the World Cup.
You prideful fool.
You can't hide
behind your jokes forever...
Gabriele.
I know your nightmares too.
(DISTANT GUNFIRE)
(TENSE MUSIC PLAYING)
(GUNSHOT)
(DEMON LAUGHS)
(IN GERMAN) Show yourself, coward.
(IN GERMAN) Show yourself.
Coward.
Show yourself, coward.
(LAUGHS)
(RETCHING)
(HAUNTING MUSIC PLAYING)
(GROWLS)
(IN ENGLISH)
Beware, your sins will seek you out.
I'll be waiting for you, Gabe.
Did you mention my name
to anyone in this house?
Maybe, I'm not sure.
This demon, it says things
that it could not know.
So it's real?
What do you know about demons?
Only the basics,
that they are fallen angels.
One serves the other in a hierarchy.
(IN ITALIAN) Yes.
(IN ENGLISH) The higher the demon,
the more access it can have.
So why is it possessing the boy?
This is a very good question.
I'm going to talk to the mother.
I need to work out
why this demon has chosen Henry.
What I am about to say may be difficult.
Confronting.
Your son is under the influence
of a very powerful demon.
Removing the boy
from this place could be fatal.
I say to you now...
the only way your son
comes back to you is through faith.
(OMINOUS MUSIC PLAYING)
Mrs. Vasquez,
did anything happen to Henry?
He was in the car accident
that killed his father.
He saw his father impaled.
(CAR HORN BLARING)
That memory, that's his demon.
I give you my word,
I will not walk away from you,
or your son.
Trauma such as you describe
can be a gateway for the devil.
Suffering can make a soul
desperate for connection.
It can make the innocent more vulnerable.
You must have loved your husband
very much.
You have no idea.
He was your soul connection, sì?
He was everything.
And you have two beautiful children.
A mother's love is the closest thing
we know to God's love.
Tell me, Julia.
Have you ever believed?
Uh, when I was a little girl...
I used to think that
my guardian angel walked me to school.
You should pray to that guardian angel.
("I'M STRANDED" PLAYING OVER HEADPHONES)
♪ I'm stranded on my own ♪
(RHYTHMIC KNOCKING)
♪ Stranded far from home... ♪
(OMINOUS MUSIC PLAYING)
(RHYTHMIC KNOCKING)
Henry?
(SNORING)
(RHYTHMIC KNOCKING)
(HAUNTING MUSIC PLAYING)
Amy.
(GROWLS)
I'm in hell.
(AMY WHIMPERS)
(YELLS)
(GASPING)
(TELEPHONE RINGING)
MAN: Amy, honey, it's Dad.
You have to listen, okay?
Daddy?
DEMONIC VOICE: You're all going to die.
(SCREAMS)
Mom! Mom!
Mom, it was Daddy. It was Dad.
I heard Dad's voice.
I heard his voice on the phone.
- He said that we're all gonna die.
- What?
- He said that we were all gonna die.
- Oh, my God.
(AMY SOBBING)
Shh.
What do we do?
Coffee.
The demons,
they grow more strongly in the night.
I'm going to need my energy.
But you should try to get some rest.
(AMORTH IN LATIN) And may the souls
of all the faithful departed,
through the mercy of God,
rest in peace.
- Amen.
- (IN ENGLISH) How long will this take?
(IN ENGLISH) That is hard to say.
Hours.
Days, maybe.
This demon is very strong.
The boy won't last long.
What we need to do is to find out its name
in order to exorcize it.
That is the only way we can save the boy.
How do we do that?
With prayer.
Constant prayer.
The demons, they are self-preserving.
They do not understand suffering.
Eventually, he will give himself up
because he cannot stand
the pain of the prayer.
You understand me?
- Yes.
- Good. Good.
- Now, you must confess your sins.
- Now?
The demon can smell your sins
if they are not absolved.
Come. (SPEAKS IN ITALIAN)
(IN ENGLISH) We begin.
Forgive me, Father...
for I have sinned.
It has been, uh...
- eight months since my last confession...
- Padre, no.
Did you just say eight months
since your last confession?
- Yes.
- I...
Okay, we just have to get this done.
- You are a man of God, simple enough, sì?
- Yes.
And you are very, very sorry
for all of your sins.
- Yes.
- Okay.
May almighty God have mercy on you,
and having forgiven your sins,
lead you to eternal peace. Amen.
What rites of the exorcism do you know?
- None.
- None?
It has never come up.
What prayer do you know that you could say
over and over, even under pressure?
The Hail Mary.
(SPEAKS IN ITALIAN)
But if it is under pressure,
I would prefer to say it in Spanish.
(IN ENGLISH) That's fine.
Your job is to pray.
Do not engage with the demon.
Do not respond
to anything it says or does.
Your job is to be implacabile.
Relentless. Okay?
Good boy.
- You know any jokes?
- Eh... no.
You should learn some.
The devil does not like jokes.
(AMORTH CHUCKLES)
Bring the books.
(AMORTH IN ITALIAN) The scent of heaven.
DEMON: I see you've brought your friend.
He looks a little scared, Gabe.
Mind if I call you Gabe, Gabe?
Readying for battle?
You ran out on me last time,
like the coward you are, soldier boy.
Not very becoming of the chief exorcist.
(IN ENGLISH) Who do you want to be
vanquished by today, Jesus or his mother?
Fuck the Holy Mother.
Are we going to talk all night,
or do you want to battle?
Know what I'm going to do
to you, Gabriele?
I'm going to fuck you.
You'll sense yourself coming.
And you'll hate yourself
for the release you feel when I fuck you.
And now we pray.
(GROWLS)
I command you, unclean spirit,
whoever you are,
along with all of your minions
now attacking the servant of God, Henry,
by the mysteries of the incarnation...
- Fuck you and your incarnations.
- Passion, resurrection
and ascension of our Lord Jesus Christ,
by the descent of the Holy Spirit,
by the coming of our Lord for judgment,
to tell me by some sign
your name and the day
and hour of your departure.
Tomás, pray. Pray.
I command you,
moreover, to obey me to the letter,
I who am a minister of God,
despite my unworthiness...
(CRICKETS CHIRPING AND WIND WHISTLING)
Rosaria?
- Your sins will seek you out.
- (HAUNTING MUSIC PLAYING)
My sins have been forgiven.
But you can't forgive yourself,
can you, Father?
Not for me, the girl you let die.
Why did you do nothing?
Why didn't you believe me?
Now I am in hell.
Deceiver.
Her soul rests in peace.
(IN DEMONIC VOICE) My soul rots in hell!
(MUSIC INTENSIFIES)
How touching.
Is that all you got?
And how about you, panty sniffer?
(INHALES)
You didn't tell him, did you?
About your little whore?
Your little sweet treat, Adella.
After you stood before your congregation
like you're better than them,
when you're fucking their daughters.
Maybe you aren't so sorry about that sin.
- Hm?
- Shut up.
Tomás. Tomás.
Do not speak to it.
- Pray.
- Run away.
You don't want to be here, Tomás.
You'd rather be fucking that little whore.
Tomás! Tomás!
No! No, no! That's what it wants!
Ah!
(GROWLING)
You've been played, Amorth.
You took the bait.
And I'll destroy you.
Your holy Church
will crumble from the inside.
(OMINOUS MUSIC PLAYING)
(DOOR CREAKS OPEN)
(MAN IN ITALIAN)
The abbey's records, Your Holiness.
She was the love of my life.
A promise was made.
(POIGNANT MUSIC PLAYING)
She wanted me to...
leave the priesthood for her...
but I had...
no intention of doing that.
So I just told her what she wanted.
My love for God...
it outweighed my love for her.
Are you sorry for your sins?
Yes.
May almighty God show you mercy.
And having forgiven your sins,
may he lead you to eternal life.
Amen.
Who is...
Rosaria?
She is a girl that I should've helped.
The demon
is using her memory to deceive me.
How does it know these things?
It can sense our guilt,
and it uses it against us
as a distraction.
That boy,
he does not have long before he expires.
We need to find out
the name of this demon.
Knowing its name, it weakens them.
I didn't mean to hurt him.
I understand.
See here.
I have marked this page for you.
Learn that.
But it is in Latin.
Close enough to Spanish.
Prayer has more power in Latin.
(HAUNTING MUSIC PLAYING)
(THUNDER RUMBLES)
"You have taken the bait."
- What?
- What it said to me.
"You have taken the bait, Amorth."
This is not about the boy.
It has a bigger plan.
I need to check something
I saw in the garden.
Go. Take this. Be outside his door.
He is still in danger.
We must protect him at all cost.
Do whatever you have to.
(THUNDER RUMBLES)
(THUNDER CRASHING)
(INTENSE MUSIC PLAYING)
The seal of the Vatican.
POPE: This place
has given the Church problems before.
(PRAYING INDISTINCTLY)
(OMINOUS MUSIC PLAYING)
(IN LATIN) God, by your name...
save me.
- (HENRY IN NORMAL VOICE) Help me.
- (THUMPING)
Henry?
- (RHYTHMIC KNOCKING)
- (GASPS)
(SUSPENSEFUL MUSIC PLAYING)
Henry?
(ESQUIBEL YELLS)
(IN DEMONIC VOICE)
No one's getting out of here alive!
(LAUGHS) No one.
(THUNDER RUMBLING AND RAIN PATTERING)
(SCREAMS)
(RHYTHMIC KNOCKING)
- (KNOCKING)
- (WHIMPERING)
- (KNOCKING CONTINUES)
- (SCREAMS)
- (DEMONIC GROWLING)
- (THUDS)
(HAUNTING MUSIC PLAYING)
(SCREAMS)
(KNOCKING CONTINUES)
(MUFFLED SCREAMING)
Let's see what secrets you are hiding.
(HAUNTING MUSIC PLAYING)
- What happened?
- (JULIA SCREAMING)
(AMY SCREAMS)
Go!
- (INTENSE MUSIC PLAYING)
- (MUFFLED SCREAMS)
(GASPING)
(AMY SCREAMING)
(DEMON GROWLS)
(AMY SCREAMS) Help me!
Amorth!
AMY: Help me!
Help!
JULIA: Amy!
(IN LATIN)
In the name of Christ, let her go.
- (AMY SCREAMS)
- JULIA: Amy!
AMY: Help!
AMORTH:
In the name of Christ, let her go.
It's me. It's me.
Oh, my God. Oh, Amy.
AMORTH: In the name of Christ,
go away, Satan, go away!
(DEMON GROWLS)
(OMINOUS MUSIC PLAYING)
It's one of her nails.
(AMORTH IN ENGLISH)
Tomás, take them to the chapel.
(OMINOUS MUSIC CONTINUES)
Everything is redacted.
"Our sins will seek us out."
- Are you okay?
- Yes.
You don't get to stay handsome
in this business for too long.
Please. Hm? Don't.
I once have a demon
try to put a crucifix into my eyeball.
You're always talking and talking. Enough.
- Please.
- (SHUSHING)
They're sleeping.
No more stories.
Did you consider why the demon does this?
To scare us, hm?
For what benefit?
Chaos.
Distraction.
The devil is the great deceiver.
He can make you see things from your past.
Apparitions, memories,
always trying to deceive us.
So we never know what he's thinking,
what he's planning.
If you do not believe me...
just ask my friend.
Come, I'll show you what I found.
Amorth!
AMORTH:
I noticed this when I first arrived.
What is this?
You recognize this?
Yes, it's the seal
of the Spanish Inquisition.
Sì. The darkest time
in the history of the Church.
And they are...?
The victims.
The ones who would not convert.
There is something underneath this place.
Something is hidden here. Come.
(OMINOUS MUSIC PLAYING)
Hold this.
Two crossed keys.
Do you recognize this?
- It's the Vatican seal.
- (SPEAKS IN ITALIAN)
- Is it gas?
- (IN ENGLISH) A little gas.
A little sulfur. A little death.
So no smoking, huh? (CHUCKLES) Stand back.
- (HAUNTING MUSIC PLAYING)
- (GROWLS)
It's a door. Push with me.
Okay.
Catacomb.
This is how they would bury the dead.
I understand the Vatican
sealing this place off.
But why would they leave someone?
AMORTH:
The ring of the cardinal protector.
He was the final hope, the last protector.
It looks like he's a prisoner,
but he's not.
The cage is for his own safety.
They do this when an exorcism fails.
To protect against a demon's escape,
to trap something
they need to remain hidden.
Tomás, see if you can open this gate.
(IN LATIN) "Your cardinal protector writes
to inform you of our worst fears.
A great evil has taken hold
of San Sebastian Abbey.
It must be buried here forever."
It's locked.
Then our friend here...
must have a key.
Where did you hide your key?
In the stomach.
Forgive me.
- (GAS HISSES)
- (GAGS, THEN COUGHS)
Try this.
Go.
"All attempts at exorcism have failed."
Satan owns this ground now.
"I have never seen
a demon this powerful before."
(GROANING)
(SPEAKING IN ITALIAN)
Gabriele.
(SIRENS WAILING)
(OMINOUS MUSIC PLAYING)
It worked.
Ah.
Thank you, my friend.
(HAUNTING MUSIC PLAYING)
- (THUMPING)
- (GIRL SCREAMING, THEN LAUGHING)
Amy?
(ESQUIBEL COUGHS)
The gases and the sulfur,
it's getting stronger.
We are getting closer to hell.
Cardinal Sullivan, is he all right?
He collapsed.
LUMUMBA: Holy Father.
(EKG BEEPING)
(IN ITALIAN) You are just agitated.
(IN ENGLISH) Tell him.
(IN ENGLISH) Tell who?
Gabriele.
Gabriele?
- (SPEAKS IN ITALIAN)
- Amorth?
- (EKG BEEPING RAPIDLY)
- (SPEAKS IN ITALIAN)
Amorth?
What trouble has he got us into this time?
AMORTH: The Friar De Ojada.
One of the greatest exorcists of all time.
ESQUIBEL:
The seal of the Spanish Inquisition.
His journal.
"Today...
I was summoned to the town of Segovia."
A possessed monk.
"In the year of our Lord 1475."
While questioning the demon
possessing the monk,
he answered me from the mouth of another.
"And then a third."
Multiple possessions.
It's a powerful demon.
(SPEAKS IN ITALIAN)
JULIA: Amy?
(HAUNTING MUSIC PLAYING)
(DEMONIC GROWLING)
(AMY LAUGHS)
"The exorcist becomes possessed himself."
Friar De Ojada?
You know he is the man
who convinced Queen Isabella
of the need for an Inquisition?
So that means
from the time he is possessed in 1475,
everything that happens after this...
is the work of the devil.
Centuries of persecution and torture,
the worst abuses of the Inquisition,
all started by the friar
and done in the name of God
by the devil.
The Vatican must have known this.
The Church covered it up.
And they buried the truth here.
"Your sins will seek you out."
The construction work
must have freed the demon.
JULIA: Amy?
(AMY LAUGHING)
Amy?
Henry.
- It's okay, Mommy.
- Henry's okay.
Oh, that's great.
Listen, Amy,
why don't you come downstairs with me?
- I'm sorry, Mom.
- I don't know what got into me.
Well, that's okay.
That's okay.
I just need your sister for a minute. Amy?
- Can you forgive me, Mom?
(OMINOUS MUSIC PLAYING)
"The great dragon was hurled down.
Hurled into the earth,
where he was bound."
"And his angels with him." Revelations.
Two hundred rogue angels
buried into the earth.
This abbey
is one of those godforsaken places.
This demon, he was trying to find them.
To raise an army and destroy the Church.
Amy, come here.
- What's in your hand, Mommy?
Amy, come here, right now.
- (GROWLS)
- (SCREAMS)
(INTENSE MUSIC PLAYING)
(GROWLS)
Look.
DEMON: Watch me, Mommy.
Watch me.
AMORTH: His name...
the king of hell...
Asmodeus.
(ROARS)
(EKG BEEPING RAPIDLY)
Quickly!
JULIA: Amy, use the sedative.
(GROWLS)
Tie his arms.
(THUNDER RUMBLES)
We have his name.
"Bring me the priest."
What did you say?
Those were the first words the demon said.
"Bring me the priest."
It didn't mean me.
It wants you.
This demon feeds on exorcists.
He had a plan once.
To lure the friar here,
hide amongst the righteous
and commit heinous acts
in the name of God.
He wants to do the same thing again.
Using me to infiltrate the Church.
What greater victory for the devil...
than to claim the soul
of the pope's exorcist?
Maybe. But we know his name now.
So we have what we need to beat it
and to save the child.
The only thing
that can defeat us is ourselves.
He will use your sins against you.
I need to make confession.
- To me?
- You are a priest, are you not?
Forgive me, Father, for I have sinned.
Trust in the Lord.
I want to talk to you...
about things I have confessed before...
but they still burden me.
In 1942...
during the war, I joined the Resistance.
I became a partisan
and I fought against the fascists.
(POIGNANT MUSIC PLAYING)
So many of my friends
would die to German bullets.
Why them...
and not me?
Their dead bodies
would talk to me in my dreams.
To die in a war is heroic.
To survive a war...
complex.
And then I begin to see...
that my life had been spared.
It was my responsibility
to give it purpose.
And in my case, that meant to serve God.
In all of my years, I have tried
to embrace what is said in Matthew.
"What you do for the least among you,
you do for me."
But when it mattered...
I failed.
I did not help her,
I did not believe her.
I did not listen.
- Rosaria?
- (SPEAKS IN ITALIAN)
Rosaria.
At night, the devil fucks me.
(IN ENGLISH)
What does this devil look like?
You.
She was not possessed.
She was mentally disturbed.
So I let someone else handle her case.
Again...
my pride.
I was an exorcist.
The mentally disturbed, it's not my job.
Do you believe me now?
But that all changed because of her.
(DRAMATIC MUSIC PLAYING)
To hear
after her death
the rumors of the sexual abuse,
the coverup
within the walls of the Vatican City.
That innocent girl.
I did not help her when she needed me.
Her soul
is my burden.
And this demon, he knows that.
I know you...
as a humble man of God, Father Amorth.
It's time to lay down that burden.
Forgive me, Father.
I absolve you of your sins
in the name of the Father,
of the Son, and of the Holy Spirit.
Amen.
(THUNDER RUMBLING)
(CLOCK TICKING)
I give you the miraculous medal.
Holy fire insurance.
Very powerful.
To defeat the king of hell...
we require the armor of God.
(THUNDER RUMBLES)
(DEMON SHRIEKS)
Remember,
the demon will use your sins against you.
Do not believe everything you see or hear.
We have work to do.
We must save this child.
(OMINOUS MUSIC PLAYING)
(GROWLS)
All done confessing?
Father.
Did he bare his soul to you, Tomás?
Like your little whore bared her breasts?
(GROWLS)
Ignore it.
Pray for Henry.
No amount of prayers can save Henry.
Let me in, Gabriele.
You know what I want.
AMORTH: Our Father, who art in heaven...
- In heaven, hallowed be thy name.
- Hallowed be thy name.
Thy kingdom come, thy...
Was there really any point
confessing to your god, Gabe?
- Give us this day our...
- Shouldn't you be confessing to her?
You are not there.
You are only in my mind.
(GROWLS)
I burn in hell because of you!
You are not there.
You are only in my mind.
- Father.
- ASMODEUS: Join us in hell, Gabe.
Take me in.
ASMODEUS AS ADELLA:
Don't you want me, Tomás?
Tell me to get on my knees
and say my prayers.
Fuck me, Tomás.
- Deceiver.
- Fuck me, Tomás!
- Deceiver!
- Fuck me, priest.
- Oh, God.
- AMORTH: Tomás, focus on the prayer!
Asmodeus!
(GROWLS)
Asmodeus, king of Gehemma,
this is the cross of the Lord!
Release this child
and flee from the light of God!
See thee beneath God!
Never. Get out.
- Get out of my house.
- This is the house of God!
Not without my son!
ASMODEUS: Your son is gone.
His soul burns and rots in hell.
- Admit to thy name, Asmodeus.
- Never!
And bow to the power of God almighty.
- ASMODEUS: Take me in, Gabe.
- ALL: Oh, Mary...
(YELLS)
- Lord is with thee. Blessed art thou...
- And of the angels...
ASMODEUS: I am king.
You're under my dominion.
- We humbly beseech you...
- And here you will remain damned forever!
Now and at the hour of our death.
To crush Satan's skull.
I am Asmodeus, king of hell.
And I command you!
We beseech thee to send thy holy angels,
that under thy command and by thy power,
they may pursue the evil spirits,
encounter them on every side,
resist their bold attacks,
and drive them hence
into the abyss of woe!
(THUNDER RUMBLES)
(IN NORMAL VOICE) Mommy?
Mom, help me.
Speak to him, Julia. Speak to him.
A mother's love never fails.
JULIA: Henry. Henry, I love you.
- Call to him.
- Henry, come back to me.
Henry, please talk to me.
(SUSPENSEFUL MUSIC PLAYING)
Mommy, they're hurting me.
Oh, God.
Henry, we need your help.
You must resist.
I can't.
You must resist!
Mom?
Henry.
What's happening?
(JULIA GASPS)
Oh, my God.
Holy shit.
(IN ITALIAN) Almighty God.
It's in them both.
(GROWLS)
(INTENSE MUSIC PLAYING)
Amy.
- Give me what I want!
- No!
ASMODEUS: Surrender yourself to me.
(ROARS)
Julia!
(IN DEMONIC VOICE) I told you, bitch.
You're all gonna die!
- Amy, please.
- Amy's gone.
Julia, resist!
Don't lose faith!
Give me back my children!
Your children are gone!
Please.
Amy, please.
I love you.
(LAUGHS)
(ROARS)
AMORTH:
It's me you want. Let the children go.
They all suffer because of you.
Say the words, piggy.
Be the martyr you dreamed of being.
Be my piggy.
AMORTH: Take me.
(ROARS)
(INTENSE MUSIC PLAYING)
Mom?
No, Gabriele!
(HAUNTING MUSIC PLAYING)
ESQUIBEL: Father.
(THUNDER RUMBLES)
(IN NORMAL VOICE) Mommy?
What have you done?
- Take the cross from my hand.
- Okay.
- Take it.
Oh, my God. Oh, my God.
Oh, my God. Henry, you came back to me.
- You're safe now.
- Take it!
Get them out of here. Go!
ESQUIBEL: Hey. Hey.
Julia, we have to go!
- Put your arms around me.
- Let's go.
Come on, run. Amy, come on.
ASMODEUS: Your soul is mine.
Sullivan.
Sullivan!
(SULLIVAN WHIMPERS)
(YELLS)
(SCREAMING)
(GROANING)
I knew you would sacrifice yourself
to save those children,
and now you are mine.
(INTENSE MUSIC PLAYING)
Come on. Hurry.
The boy, he's safe now.
Just get away from here.
- Go.
- Thank you, Father.
ASMODEUS: I need my pig, Gabe.
(YELLS)
You will not take me.
You will not take me!
(ASMODEUS LAUGHS) You prideful fool.
The friar said the exact same thing.
AMORTH: Forgive me, Lord.
(ASMODEUS LAUGHING)
Not yet!
I need my pig
to get me inside the Vatican, Gabe.
(GROWLING)
(GROANING)
(DRAMATIC MUSIC PLAYING)
(SNARLS)
Gabriele!
Damn us both...
to hell.
(DRAMATIC MUSIC PLAYING)
(HAUNTING MUSIC PLAYING)
Gabriele!
(THUNDER RUMBLING)
(IN DEMONIC VOICE) You're too late, Tomás.
He's gone, your friend. Gone.
So...
run along.
(LAUGHS) It would be my great pleasure
to excoriate your soul
and eviscerate your memory.
Gabriele, listen to me. Fight it.
It is just in your head.
We can only be defeated by ourselves.
He is not here!
The little piggy is slopping
at hell's trough, where he belongs.
I know you're here, Gabriele.
Pray with me.
God is not here!
God is always in our hearts.
Focus on the prayer.
"Where two of you gather...
in my name, there am I."
Lord, have mercy.
Say it! Lord, have mercy!
God is with you, Gabriele. Find him!
AMORTH: Finish it, Tomás.
Finish it!
(IN LATIN) God, by your name, save me.
(AMORTH IN LATIN)
Judge me in thy strength.
O God, hear my prayer.
Listen to the words of my mouth.
Behold, God is my helper.
ASMODEUS: Give up. He is mine.
(IN ENGLISH) I adjure you
in the name of the spotless lamb.
The word made flesh commands you.
Asmodeus!
Jesus of Nazareth commands you!
And now, I adjure you in his name!
(ROARS)
Lord, heed my prayer!
- Say it!
- No!
- Gabriele.
- We're not done yet.
You're coming to hell, priests.
I will take you both.
(DRAMATIC MUSIC PLAYING)
Adella.
(IN DEMONIC VOICE) Your sins will seek...
Seek you out!
AMORTH: Tomás, use the medal!
Lord, grant me the power!
- (MUSIC INTENSIFIES)
- (YELLING)
Gabriele!
Asmodeus. In the name of the Holy Mother.
See thee beneath God.
See thee beneath God!
Tomás! Pray the final rites.
In the name of the Father,
and of the Son, and of the Holy Spirit...
see thee beneath God!
(ROARS)
(COUGHS, THEN GROANS)
Gabriele, are you okay?
Not so bad.
(COUGHING)
- Tomás.
- What?
You look like shit.
(AMORTH CHUCKLES)
Bless you, Tomás.
You learned the Latin.
(LAUGHS)
Yes, it's similar to the Spanish.
(LAUGHS) Very similar to the Spanish.
Look.
You know, the God,
he works in very mysterious ways.
For you.
(HOPEFUL MUSIC PLAYING)
Yes, he does.
(HOPEFUL MUSIC CONTINUES)
Cuckoo.
Is that you, Gabriele?
(AMORTH IN ITALIAN) Yes, Your Holiness.
(IN ENGLISH) And I have brought
Padre Esquibel to meet you.
You look well, Your Holiness.
Thanks to you both. I'm glad to see you.
You had me worried this time.
Sounded dangerous.
(IN ITALIAN) Yeah, not too bad.
Sometimes you fly
a little too close to the sun.
(IN ENGLISH) It has not killed me yet.
The Church will not forget
what you have done.
You struck a mighty blow for our side.
Saint Michael would be proud.
And this is why God
put you here, Gabriele.
(IN ITALIAN)
Thank you very much, Your Holiness.
And God has made a good choice
in you too, Father Esquibel.
Thank you, Holy Father.
The congregation
has requested a full report on Spain.
(IN ENGLISH) A full report.
So Cardinal Sullivan can tell me again
that evil only exists in my imagination?
You haven't heard?
Cardinal Sullivan has taken a sabbatical
in the Isle of Guam.
I shall pray for Guam.
And who has, uh, filled his shoes?
I have found someone far more trustworthy.
I will leave you in his good hands.
See thee beneath God.
- See thee beneath God.
(CHURCH BELLS RINGING)
LUMUMBA: Welcome to the holiest of holies.
Twelve centuries of treasures.
Letters from saints and apostles.
Books of wisdom and piety.
Revelations of the spirit.
The entire canon of Christian thought.
The Vatican has purchased the abbey
from the Vasquez family
and reconsecrated the soil.
The family has safely relocated
back to the U.S.,
where the boy made a full recovery.
The friar's diary is proving very useful,
despite his abhorrence.
As mode us has been defeated,
but there are many more to be found.
Soon we will know
all of the other 199 sites on earth
where God is not welcome.
Gabriele, will you take on this task?
(PENSIVE MUSIC PLAYING)
This would be more
than a lifetime's work for one priest.
But two priests...
What do you think, Tomás?
Can you see this now as a calling?
And that we must serve God
the way he wants us to serve him?
Let's go to work.
Let's go to hell.
(MUSIC TURNS DRAMATIC)
(HAUNTING MUSIC PLAYING)
(MUSIC INTENSIFIES)
(DRAMATIC MUSIC PLAYING)