Let me tell you about
who first seduced us to do evil.
Lucifer,
to set himself in glory,
raised war in heaven against
the throne and monarchy of God.
Defeated by
the archangel Michael,
this fallen angel was cast
headlong into the lower realm.
Flaming as he fell through
the ethereal sky.
Down to bottomless damnation.
There to dwell
in unbreakable chains.
And punishing fire.
Shit.
Lucifer!
Is this really necessary?
Unchain me!
Michael!
Return as my ally and devoted
angel of the kingdom.
Better to reign in hell
than serve in heaven.
Michael!
I will one day shake free
and rise from these ashes.
I will return to you
but not as your ally,
nor your brother.
I shall return to you
as your master,
your creator,
your God!
Over time,
legions of demons
joined Lucifer in hell
as he plots his revenge.
On Earth, his disciples
erect a stronghold
to guard where Lucifer fell,
believing one day
he will rise through
this gateway to hell.
And rule our world.
Professor Russo!
Yes, Laura?
Please reconsider
approving my thesis.
The last thing
the Turin University
wants to hear is
a young American lecturing us
on what our great
Italian artists believed
or didn't believe.
I'm simply saying
that the artists
who filled your cathedrals
with angels and devils
knew they weren't real,
you know.
Like no actual good spirits
from above
or evil spirits from below.
There is no dark side.
- No dark side?
- Yeah.
Your thesis makes
for a boring movie
and an arrogant dissertation.
The answer is no.
Please, Dr. Russo,
can't we discuss this?
Why don't we discuss it later
at my apartment?
I prefer crowded large
open spaces.
Is that why you wear
a wedding band?
To keep us Italian men at bay?
It's obviously not working.
The DNA of Jesus of Nazareth
will be on display this week
in Turin, Italy.
Hundreds of thousands
will flock to witness
this historic event
as the Shroud of Turin,
the burial cloth of Jesus,
is unveiled.
Accompanying the Shroud
will be renowned
art work and sculptures
provided by the
Vatican Historical Society.
Thanks again.
Thank you for coming to church.
- Thank you.
- Ciao.
- Yes, thank you.
- Ciao, thank you.
Thank you.
- Laura.
- Hey.
- How's my art historian?
- Good.
Wonderful.
You won't be disappointed.
Here, you'll need this today.
Added security
for the exhibition.
Oh, nice.
Everyone is very excited.
There's only been
five showings of the Shroud
in the last 100 years.
Yeah, good crowd.
Ooh, sorry.
- Thank you.
Welcome to the exhibition
of the Shroud of Christ.
The world's most famous object
and most sacred.
Can you come here, please?
Before we go in
to see the Shroud,
I want to show you all
the images up close,
so that you get
a better idea of
what they look like.
So here we have
Christ's blood
from His crucifixion.
His image
from the resurrection.
We believe that Jesus died,
was buried,
and descended to the dead.
On the third day, he rose.
Intense bright light
emitted from his body
imprinted His image
on the Shroud.
The Shroud is a photograph
of the resurrection.
Hmm.
Didn't you say
you wanted to show me something?
I do.
Something very special.
Just this way.
See, I believe that
art tells
the story of our past
and hints at our future.
It's on loan for the exhibit.
He's here to protect the Shroud.
Saint Michael defeating
the devil.
The war of angels
was the first war
and the first evil.
Thankfully,
Michael defeated Lucifer
and bound him in hell.
But the struggle
of good versus evil
continues on
within each of us.
Exactly.
Evil is not some external,
mystical force.
It's personal.
I disagree.
It's much more than that.
This artist insisted that
the devil himself
sat for his portrait.
I think he may be right.
I know of many good people
who have endured
horrendous evil.
Other-worldly evil.
Yeah, so do I.
But when something happens
to someone we deeply love,
blaming it on the devil
doesn't fix anything.
It certainly doesn't
reduce the pain.
It's the only way
I can make sense of it.
The war in heaven
has come to Earth.
The devil never rests.
Lucifer would have
consumed us all
if Michael hadn't stopped him.
Many prophecies
of the devil returning to Earth
as a false god.
I pray he never
finds his way out.
But I must
find my way out.
May I leave you three alone
to get acquainted?
Sure.
Thank you, Father.
Enjoy.
Laura.
Father?
Just in time.
Several fires
have nearly consumed
the Shroud.
The last all but destroyed
this Cathedral.
God saved it.
Follow me, please.
We will go upstairs.
GUARD 2 [ON WALKIE-TALKIE]:
Goodbye. Thank you.
- Ciao.
Go!
Shoo!
- Go!
Go!
Oh my God.
Uh, no, no.
Ah, badge, yes.
GUARD 2 [ON WALKIE-TALKIE]:
Stop.
Stop this at once.
Stop this desecration.
Holy Michael.
Be our defense
against the devil.
Rebuke him!
No!
No.
Keep Satan in hell
and all his evil spirits
who desire the ruin of souls.
Join us here on Earth, Lucifer!
Saint Michael,
return to us I pray.
Take it.
Stop.
Don't kill her.
He might choose her.
No.
No, don't touch me.
Where are you taking me?
No, please.
Saint Michael...
...take my body.
Use it to defeat
this beast of Satan.
Help me!
Keep her quiet.
Help!
Who are you people?
No.
Michael.
Kill him.
Faster!
Thank you all for coming.
My name is Dr. Laurent.
To resurrect brilliance,
my colleagues visited
Santa Croce,
final resting place for
Machiavelli, Galileo, Michelangelo.
This Fort Knox of genetic
genius stores treasure
much more valuable than gold.
Brilliant DNA,
which until now
was a puzzle that
could not be solved.
Today, I alone can bring
these dry old bones to life.
The result?
Children you can
honestly be proud of.
The past will become our future.
Once I resurrect history's
most influential people
from the dead,
I just need you to pay for it.
Ladies and gentlemen,
the risen Antonio Vivaldi.
And his proud parents.
Congratulations.
Thank you. Thank you so much.
Next up for bid.
One of the greatest poets
and architects.
Considered to be
the greatest sculptor
and draftsman,
living or dead.
The creator of
the Sistine Chapel,
the David,
Saint Peter's Basilica
and the Pieta.
Tonight, prize possession,
Michelangelo Buonarroti.
So we start the bidding tonight
at e10 million.
And there we have it,
just like that, 15 million.
20 million.
30 million.
Any advance on 30?
e40 million.
70.
e70 million.
Any advance on
e70 million?
80 million.
80 million,
and 80 million going once.
Going twice.
90 million.
Is the Shroud ready yet?
- Yes.
- Good.
Everything I have worked for
has been for this moment.
Prepare the surrogates.
He's waited long enough.
Lucifer will finally have
a worthy home.
Please make her stop.
Please, now.
Make her stop.
Hey, shhh. Hey.
Hey, Sophia. Shut up.
They're watching us.
Where am I?
Hell.
What?
Hey, where did they
get you from?
Um, the Cathedral?
Cathedral?
You're a nun?
Shut up.
Shut up! Shut up!
Can you make her stop, please?
Hey, be quiet, be quiet.
Listen, listen,
what's your name?
Sophia. Sophia.
She speaks English.
Okay, okay. Okay.
Sophia, Sophia.
Hi, I'm Laura.
Okay, Sophia, look at me.
Look at me.
You want to get out of here?
- Yeah?
- Yes. Yes.
Yeah, so do I.
Okay.
Okay, so what we're gonna do?
What's your name?
It's Brenda.
- Brenda?
- Yeah.
What's your name?
- Alina.
We're gonna have to stay calm
and we're gonna
have to work together.
All of us.
Yes.
No, no, no,
don't you come near me.
Don't touch me!
No!
Get away.
Off me.
No, no.
Bishop Bustamante is safe.
They're on their way.
Father Marconi.
How could you?
- My God.
- Oh.
How could you
let them take it?
Father Marconi.
It's a miracle.
Oh, you're bleeding.
I'm calling an ambulance.
Don't bother.
Where were the protectors
of the Shroud?
Sorry? Protectors of--
Where were the protectors
of the Shroud?
Ah, my head.
Cardinal Vincini was
charged with its protection.
But he became
to be unstable.
Unstable?
Prophecies of demonic beasts
and secret cults.
What?
Wild visions of the devil
coming to Earth
and obvious dementia.
Have you read the Bible?
Pardon me? Yes.
He's taking security footage.
Where can I find
Cardinal Vincini?
Father Marconi.
As your superior,
I insist that you--
My superior?
Where is Vincini?
Where?
He is a hermit now.
He's living alone
in Saint Michael's Asylum.
Who is this girl?
She-- she's a friend of--
friend of yours.
Laura is an arts student
from America.
Well, listen to me.
This is very important.
Do not tell a soul
that I have been here.
- Yes.
- No.
Yes, of course not.
By the way, who are you?
Exactly.
Now, there's something else.
I need a car.
You have a car.
I have a car.
Wait.
What about the police?
They would want
the missing footage.
Tell them a priest stole it
after a demonic woman killed him
and he came back to life.
Or make something up.
You don't want to get
sent to Saint Michael's Asylum
for telling the truth now,
do you?
Do you mind?
No, please.
Priests.
♪ Here come the world,
with the look in its eye ♪
♪ Future uncertain,
but certainly slight ♪
♪ Look at the faces,
listen to the bells ♪
♪ It's hard to believe
we need a place called hell ♪
♪ Place called hell ♪
♪ Here comes the woman
with the look in her eye ♪
♪ She's raised on a leather,
with flesh on her mind ♪
♪ Words are weapons,
sharper than knives ♪
♪ Makes you wonder
how the other half die ♪
♪ Devil inside,
the devil inside ♪
♪ Send me an angel ♪
♪ Right now ♪
♪ Send me an angel,
send me an angel ♪
♪ Right now,
right now ♪
♪ Right now ♪
Who the hell are you?
Easy, old man.
I come in peace.
You from Turin?
Did Bustamante send you?
Come to make your confession?
Excuse me?
For the sin of
not protecting the innocent.
For your indifference
to the sufferings of
the children of God.
I warned you fools for years.
But you all thought
I'd lost my mind.
You still think this collar
gives you protection?
You're no priest.
Who are you?
The hound of heaven.
Michael.
Why are you here?
They stole the Shroud.
I have the surveillance footage
from the Cathedral.
Was it a woman?
An old woman?
Yes, it was.
Where is she?
This asylum was built
as a lookout.
Over here. Look.
Come here.
See.
You remember where Lucifer fell?
Look. See.
Those who guard it
work for Lucifer's release.
Don't call that devil
by his angelic name.
He can't escape.
I chained him there.
Come with me.
Scripture tells us the devil
will be shaken loose
from his chains.
The gate to hell
will be opened.
And he and his demons
will come to Earth.
Now is that time.
Two ancient beasts
who are of both worlds
have been charged
with his release.
The woman, whom you've met.
And the beast of the ground.
The only beast that
Satan allowed to come to Earth
before him.
There is nothing he wants more
than to fight his way
out of hell.
I know that.
I put him there.
And only I can free him.
You mean God?
These scrolls are from
the occult that guards the gate.
They believe their Lord,
like Jesus,
would be born from innocence.
For centuries, they offered him
children for him to possess.
No! No!
Their young bodies
were not strong enough
to contain him.
Their suffering
was unspeakable.
And we did nothing.
The devil can't control
his pride or his rage.
Therefore, he cannot possess
a mortal body.
He'd destroy it.
Not any.
There is one body
that has held an eternal.
And now science
has given the devil
his way out of hell.
Not even my brother will dare
to inhabit such a body.
Don't you see?
It's why they stole the Shroud.
They needed DNA.
God would never allow it.
Isn't that why He sent you?
God didn't send me.
Now get me to that stronghold.
Keep watch.
I'll see to his destruction.
Sharpen it more.
Find anything?
I don't need anything.
Why do you think they need us?
Sex.
It's always sex.
And then they'll kill us.
No, fear gets us killed.
I know, okay?
I've had to fight before
to stay alive.
So find a weapon.
Are you married?
My husband and child
were murdered.
I'm sorry.
It's okay.
We're gonna be fine, right?
Yup.
No.
At the current exhibition
of the Shroud of Turin,
already attracting
over 2 million visitors,
was abruptly closed today.
The spokesperson
for the Archdiocese of Turin
provided no official comment.
Sources within the Vatican,
however, did indicate
the shocking possibility
that the Shroud itself
has gone missing.
Oh, yes. Right.
DNA's complete.
The girl from the Cathedral.
Yes.
Blood type matches.
Healthy.
Even her natural cycle
is fortuitous.
Prepare her as well.
Hurry.
I can sense the hound sniffing.
Ready?
Hey.
No!
No! No!
Get your fucking hands off me!
No.
Calm yourself down.
Who the hell are you?
I'm the angel of the Lord.
Call me, "Liz".
What are you doing to me?
We're implanting
a fertilized egg
into your uterus.
You sick fucking bitch!
It's a very important baby.
Please, please stop now.
Please.
When I first saw you
in the Cathedral,
your sketch of my Lucifer
was so inspired.
I have never seen him
captured like that.
And it's why I believe
you might be the one.
Is this where we part?
It is.
Following us since we left.
To light the darkness,
some flares.
You have the torch.
Be watchful.
The beast of the ground
dwells below.
We have lost many
to his claws.
This won't kill him.
But it will slow him down.
May God be with you.
Is God with you?
This is my responsibility.
I'll ask for permission later.
No.
Help. No, please. Please.
Help us!
Please.
Help me!
What is it?
Oh God. Oh God, oh.
Brenda. Stop it!
Stop!
No!
Help me!
May the holy mother be found.
No! I said, no!
Open the door!
Open it!
Someone help me!
No! No!
Oh my God.
What the fuck are you doing?
What is it?
No! No!
No, let us out!
Please, please, stop!
- Stop!
No!
Let us out!
- Stop!
No!
What is this?
Did you hear that?
What is it?
What's that noise?
What's there?
What the fuck is that?
Do you-- do you see anything?
No! No!
We're gonna die here.
Ah, no!
No!
Brenda!
Help me.
Brenda.
No. No!
The chosen one!
You've found favor
and will bring forth a son.
What's in me?
A new Jesus.
What?
A better Jesus.
Put it down.
Put it down! Put it down.
Excuse me.
What are you doing here?
Nobody's allowed in--
No, what have you done?
What have you done?
Why did you take the Shroud?
Who are you?
Why?
A new beginning.
No. Don't take--
No.
That's him! There!
You guys smell that?
It smells like smoke
or something.
Is that a fire?
Oh, don't just stand there,
we need to get out of here.
Father Marconi?
Oh my God!
I thought you died.
- Are you okay?
- Yeah.
We need to get you out of here.
Michael.
Yes. Yes, come on, let's go.
Come on.
What's the matter?
- Brother.
- What?
Come on,
let's get out of here.
Something's not right.
I can sense him.
Father Marconi.
I'm not Father Marconi.
No, you're not.
You're one of them.
Laura.
Laura! Laura!
Get away from me!
I'm not one of them.
Who the hell are you then?
Father Marconi is dead.
I'm just borrowing him
for a bit.
What?
What did they do to you?
I don't know how
you live in these things.
What did they do?
They did experiments on us.
What type of experiments?
They raped me.
They uh-- they implanted me
with something.
It was horrible.
Are you pregnant?
No! No!
I don't know.
It changes everything.
Please, can we just
get out of here?
Turn the damn alarm off.
The Shroud is gone.
Go and find it.
Follow me.
I know Michael is here.
This way.
Through here.
No!
Damn fool, you.
Not a finger on her!
What's wrong?
My stomach.
What is that?
Shit.
Let's go!
Through here.
Slip through here.
Come on!
Come on.
Get down!
Come on!
This way.
It's just through here.
Come on. It's okay.
Ah!
Are you okay?
Yes, just stay there.
What are you doing?
Hurry.
It's coming back.
Come on.
Stay down, stay down.
Where'd he go?
Watch out!
Ah!
No.
No!
Stupid little girl.
Get her back safely.
If you hurt him,
I'll kill the baby.
You wouldn't dare.
I'll have my chance.
Ow!
Accept what is
happening to you, Laura.
It would be much easier
this way.
I killed your priest...
...and I'm going to
kill the angel within it.
Go, find the Shroud.
Without it,
we only have her.
Oh, you caused
quite a stir tonight.
This can be your second chance
to live the life you lost.
You sick bitch.
You've no idea who I am!
Calm down!
This pregnancy
will be like no other.
Prepare yourself.
He can't wait to meet you.
No visual of the Shroud. Over.
DR. LAURENT
Keep searching.
I'm coming to find you, brother.
The fetus is healthy.
No, no.
Why?
Where is my sword?
Now it's your turn
to rot in hell.
Mammon?
Michael.
You look pale
without your sword.
Where is he?
Up with the mortals.
We'll join him soon.
Then we'll close the gateway
between the two worlds.
And you,
you'll be imprisoned here.
And we'll rule the Earth.
I chained him!
God would never set him free.
Foolish.
To take a mortal body
down here.
Now you're trapped in it.
Chain him
with Lucifer's sword.
Look at him.
He's given you
what you have lost.
This child will never replace
what I lost.
He'll give you even more.
Look.
Mommy.
Did he speak to you?
What?
In your dream.
Did he say anything?
Laura.
I want to tell you a story.
About a brave warrior
who stood up to
a gloating tyrant.
How long have I been asleep?
The warrior and the tyrant
were equal.
But the tyrant demanded
that the warrior bend his knee
and be his slave.
What's happening to me?
Our warrior,
the brightest of all, refused.
He fought to free us.
He would be soon free
and fight for us again.
I don't give a shit about
your story about
this goddamn demon seed, okay?
I--
He suffered for you!
And the least you can do is--
Laura.
He's perfecting your body,
so you carry
and protect the child.
I want him out of me.
I know, Laura. I know.
This is difficult.
Yeah, you kidnapped me,
put this thing inside me
and now hold me prisoner.
Yeah, it's a bit difficult.
Once the child is born,
you'll be free.
I promise.
But for now, I control you.
And I demand respect.
Doll!
Say quick, angel or demon?
Stay away from him, Doll.
Who are you?
How did you get here?
We're the Stolen.
They stole us for Lucifer.
We just want to go home.
We don't belong here.
Do you want to join us?
Take the pledge.
If one gets free--
- All go home.
You're a fool to trust
any angel.
Say it.
If one gets free, all go home.
What's your name, angel?
Michael.
The archangel.
Show us. Soar to the heavens.
Bring me my sword and I will.
Sword?
It's about this big,
silver, gold, sharp.
Yeah, we know
what a sword looks like.
If there was a sword, we'd know.
We're scroungers,
that's how we survive.
There is no sword to save you.
Just use your power.
You're the archangel,
aren't you?
They're here!
Run!
Doll, they got Zar!
Get off me!
Leave them be!
No!
I will give your painful life meaning.
Did you kill my husband?
My child?
No.
I've given you a child to love.
I hate what that murderer
did to you.
He took everything from you.
I fear some of the nurses here
might do the same.
You should do something
about it.
I hate her.
Liz envies you.
If you like,
I'll let you kill her.
If that pleases you, Laura.
Very much.
I cannot come to Earth
without you.
Give yourself to me.
As I have given myself to you.
The child is a drain
on her health.
We have to do something.
Laura is not getting weaker.
She is bonding with the child.
I can feel
she's getting stronger.
Hello.
What are you doing to me?
Oh my God.
I have to kill you.
Mother, no.
Laura, stop this now.
No!
LUCIFER'S VOICE:
Where is she?
Open the door!
Laura!
All gone.
How dare you, bitch!
Go, go, get Laurent.
You have no idea
what suffering means,
until you live
our eternal misery,
living in the dark
and in the dirt.
And you,
you want to kill our Christ!
You are the monster.
You will be gone soon.
Lucifer will consume you.
But don't fear.
Full possession is a comfort.
Like death.
All your silly independence
will end.
LUCIFER'S VOICE:
How do you like it?
No more mistakes.
Lucifer, forgive me.
LUCIFER'S VOICE:
I'm weary of Laura's womb.
Being stuck up inside
her stinking mess.
I wish it could be
you inside of me.
LUCIFER'S VOICE:
Ah, baby.
You have always been beside me.
We've always been
one and the same.
LUCIFER'S VOICE:
The same?
Ah!
After the birth,
no one can live
who knows what happened here.
Of course.
And we will close the hell hole
with explosives
after your army ascends.
LUCIFER'S VOICE:
Good.
Hell shall come to Earth.
Yes.
LUCIFER'S VOICE:
There is something else.
I thought Laura
would come to love me.
How I loathe that fucking whore.
Even worse,
the child has come to love her.
He is willful
and wants his mommy.
I didn't expect this.
Oh well,
once I'm born,
kill her.
That will be my pleasure.
LUCIFER'S VOICE:
And you, do something to
stop this bitch from killing me.
This could be me.
Should have been me.
Saint Michael,
protect us against
the snares and wickedness
of the devil.
I pray God sends you help
and reveals to you
how to defeat this evil.
Oh, you are miserable, brother.
Why did God set you free?
He fears me.
He does not fear you.
Which is why
you must lead my army
against Him.
Then, we will be free.
No.
The last thing you want
is for others to be free.
You're a tyrant.
You fool!
My angels are coming
to end you.
You are powerless
without your sword
of the spirit.
Thank you, Michael.
For what?
For failing.
For this revenge.
But most of all,...
...for my new home.
I will now control
the Earthly body of
God's precious son.
The ultimate "fuck you, Daddy".
Of course.
I've been blind, foolish.
Forget him, Doll!
He's our last hope.
I forgot that there are those
more powerful than me.
And every scheme of the devil
will be turned against him.
He's just bait
for us to get caught.
Come help us, Grunt!
I need to get to Laura.
Come on, quickly.
They'll be coming for you.
Bring me my sword.
Quickly!
Listen to me!
I need my sword.
And Grunt, I can set you free.
No, come on Doll. Come on!
Don't--
Listen to me.
Bring me my sword!
Is there any other way?
No!
Come on!
Grunt, come on.
Come on.
They're coming, they're coming!
Michael, get out!
Help!
Help him!
Help me, Doll!
Hurry!
Help me!
I need my sword.
Stop!
Give me the sword
and I'll spare you.
Can you get us home?
Of course, I can.
- What are you doing?
- Grunt.
Bring it to me.
And I will free you.
Don't listen to him.
He's a liar.
Grunt, you have to trust me!
No, no!
Bring it to me!
We don't know him, Doll.
But this is different.
We've been burned before.
Please.
I promise I'll return.
If one gets free--
All go home.
Oh, what have they done to you?
Laura.
You've got to trust me,
this child is not evil.
Laura.
LUCIFER'S VOICE:
Laura isn't here right now.
No!
Laura, I know
you're still in there.
I'm gonna get you out of here.
Stop!
Stay with me.
Laura, listen to me.
This child is
not what you think.
He will defeat the devil.
LUCIFER'S VOICE:
Brother...
I have wonderful news.
My water's broken.
LUCIFER'S VOICE:
Worship me or I'll end you.
Never!
LUCIFER'S VOICE:
Loving me will be a moment
of clarity for you.
Even those against me
will question their judgment.
We can rule Earth and heaven.
We just have to kill Dad.
He just gave me a message
for you.
LUCIFER'S VOICE:
Whisper it in my ear.
You won't possess the baby.
He will possess you.
LUCIFER'S VOICE:
He will possess me?
No!
The child will not be
my undoing.
Can't you sense it even now?
This child is born
of eternal blood.
LUCIFER'S VOICE:
Shut up!
He is more powerful than you.
Because good is more powerful
than evil!
LUCIFER'S VOICE:
Motherfucker!
Try to stop your contraction.
You can't stop this baby
from being born.
He wants to be born.
To bind you like I bound you.
You are not God's equal!
You rule over the rebellion.
That is all.
And in every age,
you are defeated.
Laura! Open the door!
No!
LUCIFER'S VOICE:
Kill it!
I will not!
LUCIFER'S VOICE:
Listen to me!
No more tricks, Laura.
Get her to the altar.
LUCIFER'S VOICE:
No.
It's God who tricked us.
No, no!
Push. Keep pushing.
Good.
Yes, it's--
Where are you taking my baby?
No, no.
No!
No, no!
Welcome our beautiful,
exalted prince.
We're no longer
under the tyranny of God.
Our lost eternal.
Worship him.
Lord Lucifer,...
...I baptize you
not with water...
...but with blood.
Take them all!
He found you
in your youth.
I want to be a part of it.
I know you do.
But I have something
much more precious.
You'll have a moment with him.
Check inside.
No one can live
to tell the story.
Laura. Laura!
Laura.
- Laura!
- Michael!
Come, come on!
Come on, that's it.
That's it.
Where's my baby?
Give me my baby.
No!
No, no!
Michael, don't harm my Lucifer.
The child is not Lucifer.
He has his own destiny.
Lucifer's lust for revenge
blinds him.
He chose the only DNA
that can imprison him.
Lucifer didn't choose Laura.
God did.
Come on!
Find Cardinal Vincini.
Where are you going?
Home.
But first I have
a promise to keep.
You're too late!
Hell is coming to Earth.
Go now!
Thank you, Marconi.
But I miss my old self.
The hound of heaven indeed.
Maybe some of you may say,
that Father,
how old fashioned you are
to speak about the devil
in the 21st century.
But look out.
The devil's present.
The devil's here.
Even in the 21st century.
God have mercy.
♪ Have you ever heard
the song of angel ♪
What child is this?
♪ Have you seen
their kingdom come?
♪ Sacred bodies held,
God eternal ♪
♪ Two souls bound by
sword and shield ♪
Let's go home.
♪ Have you seen ♪
♪ Have you
seen the eyes of demons? ♪
Michael, come on.
Home time.
♪ One brother fell down
from the sky ♪
♪ Then he turned to
shadows and dust ♪
Lord, protect this child
from evil.
May the devil fear him.
Lucifer.
And not he the devil.
♪ Have mercy ♪
♪ Father,
won't you bend your knee ♪
♪ Oh, oh ♪
♪ Rising from the ashes ♪
♪ Father,
won't you bend your knee ♪
♪ Oh, oh ♪
♪ Take my hand ♪
♪ Don't let go ♪
♪ Keep my chin on ♪
♪ Till the sun ♪
♪ Will rise again
for you ♪